<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
 
 <title>Gorilla-Studios</title>
 <link href="http://www.gorilla-studios.com/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
 <link href="http://www.gorilla-studios.com"/>
 <updated>2013-05-28T11:26:18-05:00</updated>
 <id>http://www.gorilla-studios.com</id>
 <author>
   <name></name>
   <email></email>
 </author>

 
 <entry>
   <title>130 Years Of The Brooklyn Bridge</title>
   <link href="http://www.gorilla-studios.com/2013/05/26/brooklyn-bridge"/>
   <updated>2013-05-26T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
   <id>http://www.gorilla-studios.com/2013/05/26/brooklyn-bridge</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;img src='/images/brooklyn-bridge.jpg' /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://ny.curbed.com/archives/2013/05/22/130_years_of_brooklyn_bridge_photos_decade_by_decade.php&quot;&gt;Curbed.com posted a gallery&lt;/a&gt; of one of my favorite architectural icons, The Brooklyn Bridge. Opened in 1883, the gallery has some fantastic photos decade by decade up to the 2000's. Side note, if you are looking for a good book, check out &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.amazon.com/The-Great-Bridge-Building-Brooklyn/dp/1451683235/ref=sr_1_1?ie=UTF8&amp;qid=1369620166&amp;sr=8-1&amp;keywords=the+great+bridge&quot;The Great Bridge&quot;&gt;The Great Bridge&lt;/a&gt; by David McCullough, which coincidentally I just finished - it's a great read.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Tower Bridge</title>
   <link href="http://www.gorilla-studios.com/2013/05/11/tower-bridge"/>
   <updated>2013-05-11T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
   <id>http://www.gorilla-studios.com/2013/05/11/tower-bridge</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;img src='/images/tower-bridge.jpg' /&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Gorilla Studios Heads To London</title>
   <link href="http://www.gorilla-studios.com/2013/05/10/london"/>
   <updated>2013-05-10T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
   <id>http://www.gorilla-studios.com/2013/05/10/london</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;In just a few hours I'll be hopping a plane and headed to London for the &lt;a href='http://futureofwebdesign.com/london-2013/'&gt;Future of Web Design Conference&lt;/a&gt;. I will be in England for a week, coming back next Thursday, so there won't be many updates on the site, but keep an eye on my &lt;a href='http://twitter.com/gorilla_studios/'&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href='http://gorilla-studios.tumblr.com'&gt;Tumblr&lt;/a&gt; feeds for quick updates and photos if I have time. I plan on taking most of of my free time and shooting as much as I can, sleep be damned. See you next week!&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Concert Photography Basics</title>
   <link href="http://www.gorilla-studios.com/2013/05/07/concert-photography"/>
   <updated>2013-05-07T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
   <id>http://www.gorilla-studios.com/2013/05/07/concert-photography</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I love when I get the chance to photograph bands in action, so here's a few things I have learned to keep in mind if you want to be successful in music photography.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;1. Know your gear&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This may seem obvious, but know your gear. &lt;i&gt;Really know your gear&lt;/i&gt;. If you are fiddling with AF settings or looking at an exposure I guarantee you are going to miss shots. The faster you are at switching settings on the fly the more shots you are going to make. Good bands are high energy and you have to keep up - it's your job to make them look awesome and you can't do that if your stuck messing with your camera. Take time to really learn your Auto-Focus system. Can you change AF points quickly without taking the camera away from your face? Have you played around with your cameras AF shortcuts? These are things you need to know if you want to keep up with an energetic front-man who is diving all over the stage.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Get your exposure dialed in with a few shots then focus on the show. I check exposure every now and then if I feel the lighting may have changed enough to impact exposure, but on the whole I am not checking my shots throughout a set. This comes from years of learning my camera and being able to change most functions blind-folded.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/images/cadillac-bass.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;The Cadillac Casanovas rocking the Arcada in St. Charles&quot;/&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;2. Don't Machine Gun It&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Keep calm, don't run and gun it. I like to really listen to the music - when you start feeling the beat you can start to predict what some of the band members are going to do. Is the drummer building up tension? Is the bassist going to do some acrobatic trick at the crescendo? Feeling the music, staying cool, and taking your time will lead to some great photographs. If you have the chance talk to the band beforehand, get a feel for what kind of show they like to put on. Good bands love to show off for us photographers, a lot of times you'll get guys hamming it up for the camera, be ready for it, they don't wait for you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;3. Keep Track Of Your Shots&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Be sure to get every band member if possible, don't spend time on the lead singer or one person in particular. Finishing a set with 1000 photos of the lead singer and 5 of the drummer is not going to look good when you are trying to show your results to them, or other bands. Variety is key.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;4. Composition&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is another skill that is honed over time. Watch your composition like a hawk. Don't clip the guitarists headstock. Make sure the mic isn't covering too much of a singers face. Keep an eye on the background lights. Know your surroundings. It's little details that can make or break a photo.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src='/images/everly-hillbillies.jpg' alt='The Everly Hillbillies at the Arcada Theatre in St. Charles' /&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;5. Prepare&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Get to know the band your shooting, if at all possible. I like talking to them before a show to get to know their personalities. Get their set list and keep it in the back of your head so you know when their time is almost up. A lot of bands will kick it up a notch on the last song, so be ready.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Save yourself the headache and avoid any future hearing loss problems by getting a nice set of earplugs. If you love shooting shows you are hopefully going to do it a lot, and keep doing it. Protect your hearing and wear earplugs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Also Be sure to stretch before the show and if you can drink plenty of water during. Shooting concerts can be very physically demanding, so make sure you take care of yourself first. When I shoot shows I am stretching, bending, reaching, and crouching to get shots, and if I don't take time before the show to get limber then I pay for it the next day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Last but not least, be ready and able to switch out gear on the fly. Its going to be dark, its going to be loud, and its going to be hectic. This is one reason I HATE SD Cards with a passion, they are very easy to drop or mishandle.  Practice changing lenses and memory cards quickly and cleanly. Know where your gear is and have it ready.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Above all else, have fun!&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Photo Of The Month</title>
   <link href="http://www.gorilla-studios.com/2013/05/05/photo-of-the-month"/>
   <updated>2013-05-05T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
   <id>http://www.gorilla-studios.com/2013/05/05/photo-of-the-month</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;img src=&quot;/images/pod/118_full.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Flooding at Island Park in Geneva, IL&quot;/&gt;
&lt;p&gt;April's photo of the month was taken in the flood waters at Island Park in Geneva, IL. After the storms rolled through in the middle of the month most of the major rivers and creeks flooded severely. Since travel was hazardous I waited for the initial surge to subside before exploring - even a week later a lot of areas were still underwater. Island Park is located on the Fox River in downtown Geneva, and most of the inside of the park was still under a foot or two of water as I sloshed my way through. Very carefully I made my way into the park and setup my tripod almost dead center looking north back towards downtown which you can see in the top left. Since it was close to noon with a bright blue sky the park was very well lit. I stacked three ND filters and closed the aperture down to f/22. That combination allowed me to open the shutter for around 4 seconds, smoothing out the water. I found that unless I used my hands as a hood the first ND filter would reflect the branding from the front of the lens back into the exposure.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;Water and camera gear don't mix, so needless to say when you are shooting in or around water be extremely careful. I didn't have any issues with gear, the heart-attack of the day came from nature itself. It appeared some large fish were trapped inside of the park as the waters had receded enough to cut off access to the river, but was still deep enough for them to swim and every so often flopping out of the water. While taking photos I was in the middle of one shot when a large fish brushed my leg, jumped up out of the water, and then swam off very quickly. To be honest I let out a choice word or two and tried to get pulse back down to double digits. Be careful out there!&lt;/p&gt;</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Quick Tip</title>
   <link href="http://www.gorilla-studios.com/2013/04/20/cable-organization"/>
   <updated>2013-04-20T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
   <id>http://www.gorilla-studios.com/2013/04/20/cable-organization</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Here's a quick and free tip for cable organization - take those toilet paper tubes that you usually throw away and use them to keep your camera bag cables from tangling up. I always carry a USB sync cable and a wired shutter release remote in my bag and they used to get tangled up with each other or I would have to fidget with twist ties. Now I simply wind the cable on itself and slip it into the tube, and toss it into the bag.  Once the tubes get a little folded and worn they actually flatten a bit and hug the cables even more. Simple.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/images/toilet-paper-tubes.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Using toilet paper tubes as cable organizers&quot;/&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Chicago Lakefront</title>
   <link href="http://www.gorilla-studios.com/2013/04/12/chicago-lakefront"/>
   <updated>2013-04-12T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
   <id>http://www.gorilla-studios.com/2013/04/12/chicago-lakefront</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;img src=&quot;/images/chicago-lakefront.jpg&quot; /&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Geneva Sundown</title>
   <link href="http://www.gorilla-studios.com/2013/04/09/geneva-sundown"/>
   <updated>2013-04-09T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
   <id>http://www.gorilla-studios.com/2013/04/09/geneva-sundown</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;img src=&quot;/images/geneva-sundown.jpg&quot; /&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Photo Of The Month</title>
   <link href="http://www.gorilla-studios.com/2013/04/01/photo-of-the-month"/>
   <updated>2013-04-01T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
   <id>http://www.gorilla-studios.com/2013/04/01/photo-of-the-month</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;My favorite photo for March has to be a very quick shot from Union Station in Chicago. I was a little early for my train so I decided to go up to one of the balconies overlooking the main hall. I had intended to slow my shutter down enough to capture some of the motion from everyone hurrying in and out of the hall but I did not have my tripod. Attempts to use the railing while shooting around 1/10th or 1/8th were unsuccessful, but this shot at f/4.5, ISO 100 for 1/20th was sharp and had no camera shake. Overall I love the photo - in particular the one woman in the foreground seems to stand out to me. I was interrupted when a bride and her photographers came up to the balcony for some shots, however I was more than happy to get out of their way.  I will eventually go back with my tripod and get some long exposures but for now I am happy with this one.&lt;/p&gt;  
&lt;img src=&quot;/images/pod/81_full.jpg&quot; /&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Coming Soon</title>
   <link href="http://www.gorilla-studios.com/2013/03/11/coming-soon"/>
   <updated>2013-03-11T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
   <id>http://www.gorilla-studios.com/2013/03/11/coming-soon</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;img src=&quot;/images/framed.jpg&quot; /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have been working since the beginning of the year to find the best way to sell my work both locally and online. I have been hesitant up to this point because I have not found any solutions that ensure you get a high quality print, framed or matted, affordably and reliably. I can't wait to start selling my artwork, and am looking forward to making it available. More updates soon!&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Photo Of The Month</title>
   <link href="http://www.gorilla-studios.com/2013/03/02/photo-of-the-month"/>
   <updated>2013-03-02T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
   <id>http://www.gorilla-studios.com/2013/03/02/photo-of-the-month</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Two months down, still going strong. This month I spent a lot of time out hiking through various forest preserves in the area so my favorite photo this month came from Waterfall Glen Forest Preserve in Darien, IL. I found these waterfalls along a small creek that winds its way through the southern section of the park. A graduated ND filter kept a balanced exposure between the sky and foreground, and a circular polarizer filter cut back reflections from the water to reveal all the rocks and little details underneath. Using both of these also allowed me to extend my exposures up to 2 seconds. I plan on going back in the summer to get one from in the water, but for now its just a bit too cold.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/images/pom_february.jpg&quot; /&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Photo 365 FAQ</title>
   <link href="http://www.gorilla-studios.com/2013/02/22/photo-365-faq"/>
   <updated>2013-02-22T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
   <id>http://www.gorilla-studios.com/2013/02/22/photo-365-faq</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I am 52 days into my Photo365 challenge and have already gotten a few people asking me almost the same questions about the project, so I thought I would explain a little bit more about why I am doing this exercise and what my guidelines are.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Why?&lt;/strong&gt; - A number of reasons, some of which are: Staying sharp by taking at least one photo every day, keeping my camera on me at almost all times (I &lt;i&gt;hate&lt;/i&gt; that feeling when I wish I had it), to push myself to try different styles I normally wouldn't shoot, and also it acts as a photo diary for the year.  Im looking forward to having all 365 in a gallery, I have kicked around ideas about what to do with the final set, but more on that later in the year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Do you really take and post one photo a day?&lt;/strong&gt; - I try to take at the very least one photo per day, but also limit myself to no more than 36 if its not a photo walk or specific shoot. The main point of the limit is so I don't keep second guessing or trying the same shot over again. I want to see the bad shots as well as the good.  I try to post the photo on the same day, but if I have to wait until morning I am okay with that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How much time per day?&lt;/strong&gt; - Like I said I usually limit myself to a handful of shots, the average seems to be about 5-10 per day. I also limit myself to three minutes of photoshop touchup for any given photo.  I have a timer set and when beeps, thats it. I try to get the best photo I can straight from the camera - however I have been playing around with some alternate edits I usually don't try like half-saturation and stylized filters.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What have you learned so far?&lt;/strong&gt; - I have noticed that I am looking around for photo opportunities a lot more than I used to. It was difficult getting into the habit of bringing my SLR everywhere, but my Black Rapid strap really helps with that - I just sling it over my shoulder and head out. I like to see the progress I have made, and I also like seeing the good shots contrasted with some of the bad. I can see days where I just wasn't feeling very creative, and then others where I wish I could have posted a lot more.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/images/pod/53_full.jpg&quot; /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here is the photo from today, February 22nd.  I simply walked a few blocks out of my way after work and took a handful of shots as I went. I was quite surprised at how this one came out. Allowing myself three minutes for editing I spent most of the time adjusting the highlights &amp;amp; color temp, and staying true to the limit I didn't get a chance to straighten the composition.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Remember to keep shooting and have fun.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>From The Archives</title>
   <link href="http://www.gorilla-studios.com/2013/02/05/from-the-archives"/>
   <updated>2013-02-05T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
   <id>http://www.gorilla-studios.com/2013/02/05/from-the-archives</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I spent the weekend going over my backups and consolidating over ten years worth of photos into one complete archive. I made the decision when I got my first camera to keep everything so when I am back at home after a shoot I can go over what worked and what didn't, just like film. This strategy is starting to pay dividends in full, because now I have a ten year archive to sort through and see how far I have come in my craft. I wanted to share one of a handful of shots I took with my original Canon Powershot S200 that re-ignited my passion for photography.&lt;/p&gt;  
&lt;img src=&quot;/images/archer.jpg&quot; /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Taken on August 3rd, 2003 in downtown Chicago on one of my first photo walks. I vaguely recall trying very hard to capture some long night-time exposures with a point and shoot, and looking back on the roll I didn't do too bad considering the limitations of the camera. This was from the tail end of the walk - &lt;i&gt;The Spearman&lt;/i&gt; is a large bronze statue from 1928, one of two guardians (the other being &lt;i&gt;The Bowman&lt;/i&gt;) standing watch at Congress &amp;amp; Michigan Ave in the loop.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Photo Of The Month</title>
   <link href="http://www.gorilla-studios.com/2013/02/01/photo-of-the-month"/>
   <updated>2013-02-01T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
   <id>http://www.gorilla-studios.com/2013/02/01/photo-of-the-month</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;One month into the Photo365 challenge and I feel it has been going very well so far. The goal when I started wasn't to produce portfolio-worthy images every day - it was mainly to keep practicing my craft while pushing myself to step outside my comfort zone and shoot things I normally wouldn't. Some days were harder than others, but overall it has been thoroughly enjoyable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A few shots stand out more than others, but the one that caught the most attention was actually completely random.  On January 24th I had to walk from one client to another in the middle of a rather blustery Chicago snowstorm.  I had a vague idea of how to get from A to B, but didn't have a specific route in mind. I just started walking and snapping pictures as I went. A few turns in the general direction I found myself in front of a row of very interesting looking townhomes in the River North neighborhood. Thankfully nobody was parked in front so I took a quick photo and kept walking. &lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;img src=&quot;/images/pom_january.jpg&quot; /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The image was captured at f9.5 at 1/90, ISO 100. I intentionally kept my shutter speed down to catch the snow swirling in front of the lens. I was not sure of exactly how it would show up after processing, but I love how it turned out. I'm undecided if this one will make it to print or portfolio, but it looks beautiful as a desktop image on my Cinema Display. One month down, eleven to go!&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Flight</title>
   <link href="http://www.gorilla-studios.com/2013/01/20/flight"/>
   <updated>2013-01-20T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
   <id>http://www.gorilla-studios.com/2013/01/20/flight</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;img src=&quot;/images/flight.jpg&quot; /&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Experiment</title>
   <link href="http://www.gorilla-studios.com/2013/01/14/experiment"/>
   <updated>2013-01-14T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
   <id>http://www.gorilla-studios.com/2013/01/14/experiment</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I hear a lot of less-experienced photographers bemoaning the fact that they don't have a particular lens, or their camera 'isn't good enough', and it always frustrates me. You don't need the latest 20+ Megapixel camera to produce great images. Keep practicing with the gear you have, and more importantly push yourself and try something you've never done before. For my Photo 365 project I decided to try to catch a droplet splashing out of water but I don't have a ring flash or enclosed soft-box - heck my tripod was in the trunk of my car with my wife at work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Necessity is the mother of invention so I grabbed some things in the kitchen and setup a mini-studio. I used a glass of water, an eye dropper, a lamp as a secondary light, my flash &amp;amp; sync cable, and ...a chopstick?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/images/experiment.jpg&quot; /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I set the camera up on a plastic tupperware container as a makeshift tripod and switched over to manual focus mode since nothing would be moving. Looking through the camera I couldn't tell if I was in focus on the center of the water's surface, so I dipped the chopstick in dead center and focus locked on that.  I grabbed my cable release in one hand and the eye dropper in the other and tried to sync the drop to the shutter.  At first I tried the built-in timer but couldn't get the droplet to hit at the right time, so I resorted to dropping multiple drops not too far apart and releasing the shutter during.  It only took me a few shots to get the timing down. About 10 minutes of setup and a few minutes of shooting and I captured this one:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/images/droplet.jpg&quot; /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Its not going to appear in any magazines thats for sure, but then again it was about 15 minutes with no additional equipment. No high-speed camera, no special lighting, just what I had in my camera bag and kitchen. &lt;i&gt;f&lt;/i&gt;/19, 1/200th, ISO 100. This was just an experiment, I like to tinker around. Next time I will probably distill the water first so its free of impurities, and I may try a larger container so I can get more of a horizontal shot. I only spent a few minutes tinkering around in the kitchen, but I already have a better understanding of macro-photography setups, and how I can improve next time.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Photo 365</title>
   <link href="http://www.gorilla-studios.com/2013/01/13/photo-365"/>
   <updated>2013-01-13T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
   <id>http://www.gorilla-studios.com/2013/01/13/photo-365</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;As previously mentioned, I have decided to participate in a Photo 365 Challenge.  I will be taking one photo a day for the entire 2013 calendar year, and posting them &lt;a href=&quot;/photo365.html&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; as well as my &lt;a href=&quot;http://gorilla-studios.tumblr.com&quot;&gt;Tumblr feed&lt;/a&gt;. I wanted to take this challenge so I would have my camera on me at all times, push myself as a photographer, and try some things I haven't done before. So far I am only 13 days in and already I am finding myself seeing things differently, looking for photos everywhere I go.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To make things a bit more challenging, I will limit myself to only a handfull of shots per day.  I have also turned off the automatic preview after each shot as a throwback to the old film days where you don't know your results until your in the dark-room. I'll make monthly posts about my progress, positive notes, frustrations,  etc..&lt;/p&gt; 
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Happy New Year</title>
   <link href="http://www.gorilla-studios.com/2013/01/01/happy-new-year"/>
   <updated>2013-01-01T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
   <id>http://www.gorilla-studios.com/2013/01/01/happy-new-year</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Happy New Year from Gorilla-Studios!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Since its January 1st and everyone under the sun is making resolutions, I've decided to jump on the bandwagon. This year I am going to try to complete a Photo 365 Challenge (tip o' the hat to &lt;a href='http://www.kandirich.com'&gt;Kandi Rich&lt;/a&gt; for the inspiration).  If you want a project to push you all year be sure to checkout &lt;a href='http://content.photojojo.com/tips/7-new-year-projects/#more-32021'&gt;Photojojo's 7 New Year Projects&lt;/a&gt; for some great inspiration if you're not quite up to a 365 day photo challenge. My other resolution is to post more often and keep working on the site. Last year was spent focusing on getting married and my new full-time job, so this year I am going to set aside time to grow my site and skills the best I can.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Heres to 2013!&lt;/p&gt;</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Practice Swapping Lenses</title>
   <link href="http://www.gorilla-studios.com/2012/12/30/practice-swapping-lenses"/>
   <updated>2012-12-30T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
   <id>http://www.gorilla-studios.com/2012/12/30/practice-swapping-lenses</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Any craftsman will practice his skills, working on them over and over. Any photographer worth their salt will practice not only taking photos, but working with their equipment as well. I have seen on many blogs posts talking about swapping lenses quickly, but they always say practice in favorable conditions in good light. Lets take practicing lens swapping a bit further.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I was out yesterday walking through the snow,  getting used to my new Black Rapid Double Strap, keeping sharp with handling gear in windy cold conditions, and just enjoying the scenery when I decided to swap from my wide angle to a telephoto. Problem was I couldnt set my bag down because I was in the middle of a field in deep snow. &lt;i&gt;Here's the challenge:&lt;/i&gt; swap out your lens with out setting down any gear, then try to do it with gloves on. Try it in the dark with minmal light. Could you do it by feel alone? Whats it like handling your lenses and caps with your gloves on? Practice working in adverse conditions before you find yourself in them not knowing what to do.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Remember to keep practicing not only taking and composing photos, but working with your gear. The better you know it the faster you will be in the field when it counts.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Celestron Dry Run</title>
   <link href="http://www.gorilla-studios.com/2012/12/22/celestron-dry-run"/>
   <updated>2012-12-22T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
   <id>http://www.gorilla-studios.com/2012/12/22/celestron-dry-run</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I finally took my recently acquired Celestron Ultima 11 Schmidt-Cass telescope out for a test run to get a feel for using it in the field. Everything setup easily and I got the moon in sight quickly, but I had some initial focusing problems. About a half hour of tinkering around and I finally got it in focus and was thoroughly impressed with the clarity. The Celestron has an 11&quot; mirror with a rough focal length of 2800mm. Using a 26mm Plossl eyepiece puts us at roughly 108x magnification (2800mm / 26mm). I couldn't help just gazing through the eyepiece for some time, getting used to tracking the moon manually (I still need to learn how to properly polar align the scope and use the auto tracking). Finally I pulled out my trusty EOS 10D and mounted it to the scope. I refocused and started shooting, right around 1/90th at ISO 200. I locked the mirror up and used a remote as to avoid shake, but the first round of photos were all soft. Im not sure if it was a mirror shake problem or the images were just plain out of focus. I had a hard time getting locked in with the telescopes focus knob, clearly its going to take some practice. Heres the 'best' of the out of focus images from tonight:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img src='/images/celestron_test.png' /&gt;&lt;p&gt;That was shot at ISO 200 for 1/90th of a second with the mirror lock enabled. If I understand correctly it has a focal length of f/16. This image was also completely un-cropped - the telescope has so much power I cannot fit the moon into the frame all at once. To get full lunar images I either need to stitch multiple images together or purchase a telecompressor. It was a relatively clear night, but I did shoot with a lot of ambient light from the subdivision. I may take it out tomorrow for another shoot, stay tuned!&lt;/p&gt;</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Gorilla-Studios Looks To The Skies</title>
   <link href="http://www.gorilla-studios.com/2012/12/02/gorilla-studios-looks-to-the-skies"/>
   <updated>2012-12-02T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
   <id>http://www.gorilla-studios.com/2012/12/02/gorilla-studios-looks-to-the-skies</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;img src='/images/celestron.png' /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Today I liberated my fathers Celestron Ultima 11&quot; Schmidt-Cass telescope which had been collecting dust for some time. I picked up an adapter for my Canon, so over the next few months I will be seriously exploring astrophotography.  I have previously used a low-grade Quantaray 600-1000mm scope for lunar photography, needless to say this is quite an upgrade - the Celestron has a focal distance of 2800mm (if I understand the specs correctly). I will keep posting my experiences and results soon.  Stay tuned.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Insure Your Gear</title>
   <link href="http://www.gorilla-studios.com/2012/11/27/insure-your-gear"/>
   <updated>2012-11-27T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
   <id>http://www.gorilla-studios.com/2012/11/27/insure-your-gear</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Here's a great reason why to insure your gear before something bad happens. Ed Hetherington shared a story via &lt;a href='http://www.facebook.com/media/set/?set=a.10152269804305542.929748.117291240541'&gt;his facebook page&lt;/a&gt; about how a lioness decided to get up close and personal with his EOS 5D MkII. While the camera did not survive, thankfully it looks like the lioness didn't suffer any injuries from her curiosity.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>5D MkII Price Drop</title>
   <link href="http://www.gorilla-studios.com/2012/09/30/5D-MkII-Price-Drop"/>
   <updated>2012-09-30T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
   <id>http://www.gorilla-studios.com/2012/09/30/5D-MkII-Price-Drop</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='http://www.canonrumors.com/2012/09/big-canon-eos-5d-mark-ii-price-drop-coming/'&gt;Canon Rumors&lt;/a&gt; reports that there is a big price drop coming on the Canon EOS 5D MkII. This is a great deal for someone looking into upgrade to a more capable body but cannot justify spending $3500 on the MkIII.  Just remember - the MkII is still a great camera, and a terrific bargain now.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt; UPDATE &lt;/strong&gt; - &lt;a href='http://www.bhphotovideo.com/c/product/583953-REG/Canon_2764B003_EOS_5D_Mark_II.html'&gt;B&amp;amp;H Photo&lt;/a&gt; has the body only on sale for $1799. This really makes me think long and hard about my next major purchase.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Great Blue Heron</title>
   <link href="http://www.gorilla-studios.com/2012/08/26/great-blue-heron"/>
   <updated>2012-08-26T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
   <id>http://www.gorilla-studios.com/2012/08/26/great-blue-heron</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;img alt='Great Blue Heron spearing a fish, Canon EOS 10D 200mm f/5.6 1/125th' class='img_center' src='/images/heron_fish_spear.jpg' /&gt;</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Quick Tip - Shooting The Moon</title>
   <link href="http://www.gorilla-studios.com/2012/07/27/quick-tip-shooting-the-moon"/>
   <updated>2012-07-27T21:41:26-05:00</updated>
   <id>http://www.gorilla-studios.com/2012/07/27/quick-tip-shooting-the-moon</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;img alt='Half Moon shot on July 27th, 2012 with a Canon EOS 10D + Quantaray 600-1000mm' class='img_center' src='/images/half_moon.jpg' /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Here are two things you can do to give your astro and night photography a little boost.  First is to pair your cable release with the camera's 'Mirror Lock' function. Simply go into your DSLR's custom functions and select Mirror Lock. By enabling this, when you press the shutter release the mirror swings up and out of the way locking into position and holding in place. You then have to press the button again to open the shutter and make the exposure. After the photo is taken the mirror swings back into place as normal. What this does is eliminate any shaking or movement involved when the mirror flips up.  Normally during the day time and during normal photos this movement does not matter, but when you are trying to keep the camera as steady as possible during a long exposure at night it makes a large difference.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Second is to use a UV/Haze filter. These filters cut down on UV light and haze that can impact image quality. Sometimes the difference isn't that great, but when I shot a before and after tonight I was impressed with what a cheap $20 UV filter did.  The moon was low in the sky when the shot was taken, increasing the amount of atmospheric haze to shoot through.  Both images were taken within a minute of each other, on my Canon 10D paired with a Quantaray 600-1000mm super telephoto, extended to 1000mm, &lt;i&gt;f&lt;/i&gt;/16 at 1/30th of a second, ISO 100. On the left the mirror was not locked and the filter was not on the lens. On the right the mirror-lock function is enabled and the filter is on. Without the mirror-lock the first image was shaken enough to impact the sharpness, and you can also see the clarity difference as well.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt='Unfiltered with no mirror lock vs. UV/Haze filter with Mirror Lock' src='/images/moon_example.jpg' /&gt;</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>A Photographers best tool - improvisation</title>
   <link href="http://www.gorilla-studios.com/2012/07/24/a-photographers-best-tool-improvisation"/>
   <updated>2012-07-24T19:23:21-05:00</updated>
   <id>http://www.gorilla-studios.com/2012/07/24/a-photographers-best-tool-improvisation</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;One lesson I have learned in my years of shooting is that you should always be ready to improvise. It's a good idea to plan your shoots to get a good idea of what you want to accomplish but you always have to be ready to throw it out the window and get what you can.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I went out after work last Friday and decided to go down to Navy Pier and take some dusk shots of the Ferris Wheel and spinning swings. I wanted to catch them as the sun was going down and use a slower shutter speed to capture some motion. After taking a few test shots I was approached by a security guard and he told me firmly that they did not allow tripods during high traffic periods 'due to safety concerns'. I was frustrated and voiced my displeasure since I was actually using it as a monopod, but rather than having a chat with the Chicago Police I decided to move along. Needless to say I was in a bad mood, but instead of just packing up and heading home I started walking up the lakefront. I knew there was a great park just north of Navy Pier with a beautiful view of the skyline and lots of boat activity, so I decided to try to see what I could get up there. Again I setup and started composing my shots, taking some test exposures and watching the sun sink farther and farther. Just as I started to feel good about everything a Chicago Police officer reported that the park was closing and ran everyone out. This was yet another opportunity to throw my hands up and pack it in. Thankfully I stayed cool and left the park and went down to the beach around the corner. After double-checking with the officer I found that it was open until 10 so I wouldn't have any problems. As the golden hour set in I started getting some great shots and all my frustrations just drifted away.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt='Chicago skyline at dusk' src='/images/chicago_skyline.jpg' /&gt;&lt;p&gt;This was the last shot before the sun finally went down, taken at 19mm &lt;i&gt;f&lt;/i&gt;/8 for 30 seconds. I would have missed this opportunity had I gotten angry and just headed home.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt='' src='/images/flower_bug.jpg' /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Here is another great example. This photo was taken when I went out last summer looking for more Great Blue Herons that were nested near my house. I was walking along the Fox River looking at the tree line when the color of these flowers really caught my eye. I switched over to my 50mm macro lens and started photographing these bold flowers. I was just about to pack up when I noticed this bug on one flower, climbing the stamen. I would have totally missed this had I not had my eyes open.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Always be sure to have an idea of what you want to get before you even leave the house but keep your eyes and mind open to something completely different. Looking through my portfolio there are quite a few shots that were a complete surprise to me at the time. Whether its a scenery or lighting change, location change, equipment malfunction or whatever, one of the best tools you can have is being able to stay calm and get the shot that presents itself to you.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Wolf Camera Blowout Sale</title>
   <link href="http://www.gorilla-studios.com/2012/07/18/wolf-camera-blowout-sale"/>
   <updated>2012-07-18T19:23:21-05:00</updated>
   <id>http://www.gorilla-studios.com/2012/07/18/wolf-camera-blowout-sale</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;It looks like Wolf Camera is filing for bankruptcy - again.  I stopped by my local store and found out they are closing 'probably half' of their stores.  While they were never able to compete against online retailers in terms of cost, the customer service was always top notch.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I'm not sure exactly which and how many stores are closing, but the one in Batavia, IL is shutting down 'within the month' and is currently having a huge blowout sale.  I picked up about $200 worth of filters for about $40 bucks today.  Most of their inventory is picked clean already, but if you know what you're looking for be sure to stop by.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Don't Worry</title>
   <link href="http://www.gorilla-studios.com/2012/06/15/dont-worry"/>
   <updated>2012-06-15T09:34:58-05:00</updated>
   <id>http://www.gorilla-studios.com/2012/06/15/dont-worry</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I have had lots of conversations over the years with friends and younger photographers about upgrading gear, and they always ask about what camera is 'better' or which does X better. As a beginner or amateur photographer guess what? The specs don't really matter. If you listen closely you'll hear the sound of thousands of Internet Trolls crying out &lt;em&gt;'Blasphemy!'&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The other day a friend and I were discussing about what she should get as her first serious DSLR. She told me that the guy at Wolf Camera was going on about how Nikon has better low-light performance, but the Canon optics are better, blah blah blah. She got worried and wanted to know the real-world differences between a few entry to mid-level cameras. These clerks never seem to realize that they are splitting hairs and to a beginner it doesn't matter (and most of the time they don't understand). Do you really think to a beginner (or anyone really) it matters that camera X shoots .5fps faster than camera Y, or its sensor is 3MP more? No. Nobody can tell the difference between a 16MP photo and a 18.5MP photo when they are all uploaded onto Flickr.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I always laugh when car guys are comparing a BMW that can do 180MPh and a Mercedes that can do 182MPh. Yes that Merc is technically faster, but they are both high-performance machines that are really never going to be pushed to their limits. It's the same with cameras - the difference between a Canon EOS 60D and a Nikon D90 is going to be marginal to most beginner and amateur photographers. This Nikon may have 1MP more, or that Canon may be a hair better in low-light sensitivity, but guess what? They are both fantastic cameras that produce great images.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Yes it is an investment and you want to purchase the right camera to fit your needs since you will have it for years (I am *still* shooting with my 10D I purchased in 2003), but don't go overboard wringing your hands about the spec differences between a Rebel T2i and a D5000. Figure out what you want to use the camera for, buy it, and start having fun. Remember: its not the sensor, the lens, or the ultra-high ISO, or some whiz-bang feature that make the photograph - it's your eye, your gut, and your heart.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Stop worrying about all the new cameras coming out and forget about how this camera magazine said brand X was so much better. Instead of sitting in front of a computer reading spec sheets, review after review, and endless forum posts, take that time and go outside with &lt;em&gt;your camera&lt;/em&gt;. Take some awesome shots with what you have - share it, talk about your art, and most of all, have fun with it.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Summer Is Almost Here</title>
   <link href="http://www.gorilla-studios.com/2012/05/18/summer-is-almost-here"/>
   <updated>2012-05-18T14:29:05-05:00</updated>
   <id>http://www.gorilla-studios.com/2012/05/18/summer-is-almost-here</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;img alt='Bug on a flower Strobist Macro Photography' src='/images/portfolio/flower_bug.jpg' /&gt;</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>The Coolest/Dumbest Photographer In The World</title>
   <link href="http://www.gorilla-studios.com/2012/04/20/the-coolestdumbest-photographer-in-the-world"/>
   <updated>2012-04-20T15:12:18-05:00</updated>
   <id>http://www.gorilla-studios.com/2012/04/20/the-coolestdumbest-photographer-in-the-world</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;img alt='Don&amp;apos;t Panic' src='/images/stay-cool.gif' /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Found this on &lt;a href='http://memebase.com/2012/04/20/internet-memes-just-escaped-death-still-taking-pictures/'&gt;Memebase&lt;/a&gt;.  This guy is both 1) Incredibly calm given the circumstances, and 2) Incredibly stupid for being that close to the action.  I think 99% of the time that would have ended the other way. Had a car almost clipped me I don't think I would calmly take pictures as it went by, id be changing my pants.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Don't try this at home kids.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Hands On The EOS 5D MkIII</title>
   <link href="http://www.gorilla-studios.com/2012/04/14/hands-on-the-eos-5d-mkiii"/>
   <updated>2012-04-14T22:53:17-05:00</updated>
   <id>http://www.gorilla-studios.com/2012/04/14/hands-on-the-eos-5d-mkiii</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;A friend of mine recently purchased the new Canon EOS 5D MkIII and gave me a chance to check it out after dinner tonight. While this is not a full review, I wanted to share my initial thoughts. The camera feels absolutely solid, great to hold and the shutter release is extremely snappy. The large LCD panel on the rear of the camera is crisp and bright, photos looked amazing. What really blew me away was its low-light capabilities - I took a quick set of photos and was amazed at the clarity. Shots from ISO 12,000 up to the 25,600 max were clear, and certainly useable.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I really hope to get my hands on one for an extended period so I can do a full review, but for now I wanted to say that I am really impressed.  Soon I'll have a complete review with image and HD video samples, so stay tuned!&lt;/p&gt;</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Infographic Of The Week - The Space Shuttle</title>
   <link href="http://www.gorilla-studios.com/2012/04/13/info-graphic-of-the-week-the-space-shuttle"/>
   <updated>2012-04-13T10:05:17-05:00</updated>
   <id>http://www.gorilla-studios.com/2012/04/13/info-graphic-of-the-week-the-space-shuttle</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Since I am a total space geek I wanted to share an awesome, well-designed &lt;a href='http://www.npr.org/2011/07/21/138560459/sizing-up-space-a-visual-history'&gt;Space Shuttle info-graphic&lt;/a&gt; that NPR put together. If you love that be sure to check out &lt;a href='http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=W2VygftZSCs'&gt;Ascent&lt;/a&gt; - a long slow motion HD breakdown of a shuttle launch from just about every angle possible with explanations of what your seeing. &lt;/p&gt;</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Web Design Blog</title>
   <link href="http://www.gorilla-studios.com/2012/04/04/web-design-blog"/>
   <updated>2012-04-04T16:18:12-05:00</updated>
   <id>http://www.gorilla-studios.com/2012/04/04/web-design-blog</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;In February I accepted a design residency at &lt;a href='http://www.8thlight.com'&gt;8th Light&lt;/a&gt; in Chicago, so needless to say that has been my primary focus lately.  One of my residency requirements is to write weekly blog posts about my experience and what I am learning. I wrote an entirely new &lt;a href='https://github.com/mojombo/jekyll'&gt;Jekyll&lt;/a&gt; powered blog hosted on github to share my experiences. You can check it out at &lt;a href='http://cpeak.github.com'&gt;cpeak.github.com&lt;/a&gt;. It also has a lot of design &amp;amp; development resources. Enjoy!&lt;/p&gt;</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Canon 50mm f/1.8</title>
   <link href="http://www.gorilla-studios.com/2012/03/31/canon-50mm-f1-8"/>
   <updated>2012-03-31T09:32:00-05:00</updated>
   <id>http://www.gorilla-studios.com/2012/03/31/canon-50mm-f1-8</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I got a chance earlier this week to test out my Canon 50mm f/1.8 in the field for a quick headshot session downtown with our friend Allie. Overall it's a great lens at an absolute bargain that should be in any photographers bag. Amazon has the lens on sale for $117 as of right now.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt='Canon 50mm f/1.8 Prime Lens' src='/images/50mm.gif' /&gt;&lt;p&gt;We had planned to meet up and shoot around 5:30, about an hour before sunset. However Allie got delayed at work which put us back a bit so we were fighting the sun going down. Despite losing daylight rapidly the little 50mm performed very well - I even grabbed some frames at 1/20th all the way open at f/1.8 handheld. Since it is not packing a USM (Ultra Sonic Motor) low-light focusing did become an issue, however it wasn't a deal-breaker though I felt it could perform better. I only mis-focused one or two shots due to the low-light (and that was shooting 1.8 with a very limited depth of field). The lens is super light and some reviews complain that it is built cheaply but I couldn't find any issues with the quality.  The manual focus ring is smaller than most lenses so I can see that being a complaint to someone who likes to use manual control often, but I don't mind it that much.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt='Canon 50mm f/1.8 at 1/20th' src='/images/allie.jpg' /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Here is an un-edited shot taken on my 10D with the 50mm, f/1.8 at 1/20th, hand-held.  As you can see even with an extremely shallow depth-of-field it is very sharp where it needs to be. The bokeh is very smooth so shooting in downtown Chicago at dusk made for some beautiful backgrounds.  We did a basic one-light strobist shoot. I set my Speedlite paired with a wireless trigger on a lightstand with an umbrella which my wife kept from blowing away. Walking around Millennium Park we found some overhead lights in the amphitheater that acted as beauty lights really highlighting her hair, so technically its a two-light setup in this shot.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Hands down this is almost a must buy for anyone who shoots portraits or wants more performance in low-light situations.  It's a well built lens thats &lt;em&gt;very&lt;/em&gt; fast, a great bang for the buck. &lt;/p&gt;</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Don't Rush Out And Buy The Latest And Greatest</title>
   <link href="http://www.gorilla-studios.com/2012/03/23/dont-rush-out-and-buy-latest-and-greatest"/>
   <updated>2012-03-23T10:52:21-05:00</updated>
   <id>http://www.gorilla-studios.com/2012/03/23/dont-rush-out-and-buy-latest-and-greatest</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;A lot of younger and more inexperienced photographers I've met over the years have a bad case of gadget envy.  I always hear them saying '...if I only had this lens' or 'if I had this new DSLR body then I would really be so much better'.  Repeat with me: &lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Buying new gear does not make you a better photographer&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;. Trust me, I've been there - I still get the bug every now and then, but thankfully my experience wins out in the end. I started writing this post because the new Canon EOS 5D MkIII was just announced and is poised to hit the market very soon (update: &lt;em&gt;today&lt;/em&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Just because the 5D MkIII is now on the market that does not make your DSLR any less of a camera. If you have a Rebel T2i or an EOS 60D, the jump to the 5D MkIII is not going to instantly make your photos better. The difference between an 18.1MP photograph from an entry level T2i and a 22.3MP photograph from the new MkIII are going to be negligible at best. Unless you are doing glamour shots for Vogue or full spreads for National Geographic your current camera is up to the task. The new Digic 5+ processor is not going to compose better photographs for you and having a 63-Zone Dual Layer Metering system is not going to magically fix that lighting problem you've been having in the photos you've taken so far.  Practice and experience make the photographer, not the camera.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;But, but, but I want that shiny new camera that was just released, its soooo much better!&lt;/em&gt; Guess what - I still shoot to this day with an 6.1MP EOS 10D, which is now almost 10 years old. Technology wise most people categorize this as a 'dinosaur', heck, most cell phones have higher megapixel counts. Every photo in &lt;a href='/?page_id=133'&gt;my gallery&lt;/a&gt; was shot with the 10D. When I first got it I experienced a lot of growing pains - I was exploring night photography, taking long exposures of the city and I found myself constantly looking at the pro level EOS SLRs thinking they would take me to the next level. I was frustrated about the quality of photographs I was taking. Would a pro level camera back then make my photos any better? Nope. I would have made the same mistakes in composition and lighting and been just as frustrated and my wallet would have been a lot lighter. I took my time to learn my craft, discussing my work with other photographers, learning as much as I could.  Now shooting with that same camera I am getting photos that I am truly proud of, and the only thing I upgraded was my experience.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>37signals - Give It 5 Minutes</title>
   <link href="http://www.gorilla-studios.com/2012/03/01/37-signals-give-it-5-minutes"/>
   <updated>2012-03-01T13:19:52-06:00</updated>
   <id>http://www.gorilla-studios.com/2012/03/01/37-signals-give-it-5-minutes</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='http://37signals.com/svn/posts/3124-give-it-five-minutes'&gt;My favorite blog post&lt;/a&gt; from them in a long time, which is saying something because SVN is one of my favorite feeds.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;So next time you hear something, or someone, talk about an idea, pitch an idea, or suggest an idea, give it five minutes. Think about it a little bit before pushing back, before saying its too hard or its too much work. Those things may be true, but there may be another truth in there too: It may be worth it.&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I am the exact opposite of how Jason was - I take a lot of time when people pitch ideas and express opinions.  I deliberately wait and think about it, working out my thoughts clearly first.  I let the first round of counter-arguments and crap fly before I open my mouth, that way I can tell who is worth discussing the issue with.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>DSLR Shutter Release In Super Slow-Motion</title>
   <link href="http://www.gorilla-studios.com/2012/02/11/dslr-shutter-release-in-super-slow-motion"/>
   <updated>2012-02-11T19:15:13-06:00</updated>
   <id>http://www.gorilla-studios.com/2012/02/11/dslr-shutter-release-in-super-slow-motion</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='http://www.petapixel.com/2012/01/24/a-dslr-camera-shutter-in-slow-motion/'&gt;Via PetaPixel&lt;/a&gt; - watch straight down the inside of a Canon 60D as the shutter button is pressed. For beginners this is a great way to understand the whole process of how your DSLR actually takes a photo. When you press the shutter release the mirror flips up and the shutter blades then open to expose the sensor to the light coming in from the lens.  After a set time - &lt;em&gt;your shutter speed&lt;/em&gt; - the blades snap back into place and the mirror drops down again.  What is really amazing is how fast this process happens - a typical exposure during the day may be around 1/250th to 1/500th of a second.  My old camera can go all the way up to 1/4000th!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;This is also a great example why why for long exposures I like to use my &lt;strong&gt;Mirror Lockup&lt;/strong&gt; function built into my camera.  As you can see there is an awful lot of vibration as the mirror slams up into place before the shutter opens.  To avoid any of this shake you can 'lock the mirror' in place before the actual exposure. Using my cable release I press the button once to lock the mirror up into place, then press it again to take the actual exposure and release the mirror, avoiding any vibrations that may compromise my photograph. More on that later.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Productivity Quick-Tip - SynergyKM For Mac</title>
   <link href="http://www.gorilla-studios.com/2012/02/04/productivity-quick-tip-synergykm-for-mac"/>
   <updated>2012-02-04T10:04:49-06:00</updated>
   <id>http://www.gorilla-studios.com/2012/02/04/productivity-quick-tip-synergykm-for-mac</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;One tool I use quite a bit but never think about is &lt;a href='http://sourceforge.net/projects/synergykm/'&gt;SynergyKM&lt;/a&gt;, an open-source app that lets you control multiple computers with one keyboard and mouse without a physical KVM switch.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;My primary setup is a PowerMac G5 workstation which I do all my photography editing on, but for coding and work I have a PowerBook that travels with me.  When I am home I enjoy being able to use both but I don't want the hassle of switching back and forth between the two. Synergy solves the problem very simply.  The application installs as a preference pane on both machines and setup is easy.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt='SynergyKM for Mac' src='/images/synergykm.jpg' /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Here I have my PowerMac G5 'Ogden' setup as the server, and my PowerBook 'Asana-2' (why did I name it -2?) setup to the left of my displays.  On the PowerBook I just tell it to look for Ogden and since they are on the same network they connect to each other.  Now I can just swing my mouse over to the left and just like with multiple displays it transfers mouse and keyboard control over to the PowerBook.  When you leave the current computer it takes the mouse cursor and just drops it dead center on the primary screen indicating that its in a kind of 'idle' state.  Mac's and PC's work seamlessly, and you can setup multiple locations as well - I have profiles setup for home and work so when I'm at the office I just switch profiles and it connects to my work PC.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Its open-source so its free, and it removes the clutter of a second keyboard and mouse from the desk which is huge for me since I enjoy a clean work area.  The biggest benefit is that it removes the confusion or mental jump between machines - when you're in a workflow you don't even think about it, it's seamless. Be sure to head over to the &lt;a href='http://sourceforge.net/projects/synergykm/'&gt;Source-Forge project page&lt;/a&gt; and check it out.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>First Of The Month - What's Your Backup Situation?</title>
   <link href="http://www.gorilla-studios.com/2012/02/01/first-of-the-month-whats-your-backup-situation"/>
   <updated>2012-02-01T21:42:04-06:00</updated>
   <id>http://www.gorilla-studios.com/2012/02/01/first-of-the-month-whats-your-backup-situation</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;It's the first of the month - a great time to double check how your backups are doing.  My full time job is doing IT support so I see first-hand the dangers of either not backing up data or not checking your backups. Remember: just backing up your data is not good enough! &lt;strong&gt;CHECK IT&lt;/strong&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;How do you know your backup set is good? Most people don't check until they are already in hot water. Don't gamble with your data - run a 'fire-drill' every few months.  Pretend your main computer just crashed - shut it down and walk through what it's going to take to get you back on your feet.  Do you have a spare machine incase your motherboard fails? Do you have a spare hard drive to swap in if its a drive crash? Do you have your software installers and more importantly the license keys?  What applications do you need to get your workflow going? Planning this out before something crashes, that way when it does you know what to do.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Remember&lt;/em&gt; - backup drives are just as fallible as internal drives.  Don't put all your eggs in one basket by storing all your documents in one external 'backup drive'.  You are not protected until your data is on two separate devices. In my experience you can usually expect hard drives to last between 3 and 5 years, however if it is a mission critical drive I would replace them every 1 or 2 years.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Backup solutions are very affordable these days so there is no excuse for not having at least something in place.  Check your backups on the first of the month and run your fire drill once every few months, that way if something ever happens you'll be in great shape.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Back!</title>
   <link href="http://www.gorilla-studios.com/2012/01/23/back"/>
   <updated>2012-01-23T19:06:03-06:00</updated>
   <id>http://www.gorilla-studios.com/2012/01/23/back</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;img alt='Beachfront in the Bahamas' src='/images/beach.jpg' /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Back from my honeymoon with my amazing wife, refreshed and ready to take on the new year.  Looking forward to a great year for myself and the website, lots of new things are cooking so be sure to come back often!&lt;/p&gt;</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>28 Resolutions From 28 Seasoned Photographers</title>
   <link href="http://www.gorilla-studios.com/2012/01/10/28-resolutions-from-28-seasoned-photographers"/>
   <updated>2012-01-10T19:23:06-06:00</updated>
   <id>http://www.gorilla-studios.com/2012/01/10/28-resolutions-from-28-seasoned-photographers</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I set myself a number of goals for the upcoming year that I am committed to fulfilling, so I was happy to find a great list of 2012 resolutions from professional photographers (a few of which I really look up to and love their work).  &lt;a href='http://blog.photoshelter.com/2012/01/28-resolutions-from-28-seasoned-photographers/'&gt;Read the full article over at Photoshelter&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Jam Session</title>
   <link href="http://www.gorilla-studios.com/2012/01/09/jam-session"/>
   <updated>2012-01-09T19:28:13-06:00</updated>
   <id>http://www.gorilla-studios.com/2012/01/09/jam-session</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;img src='/images/CRW_3885.jpg' /&gt;</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Sunset - January 6th, 2012</title>
   <link href="http://www.gorilla-studios.com/2012/01/06/sunset-january-6th-2012"/>
   <updated>2012-01-06T18:55:37-06:00</updated>
   <id>http://www.gorilla-studios.com/2012/01/06/sunset-january-6th-2012</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;img alt='Sunset' src='/images/CRW_3718.jpg' /&gt;&lt;p&gt;I was stuck at work but managed to sneak out back and take a quick snap.  Remember, the best camera is the one you have on you!&lt;/p&gt;</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Gorilla-Studios Now On 500px</title>
   <link href="http://www.gorilla-studios.com/2012/01/02/gorilla-studios-now-on-500px"/>
   <updated>2012-01-02T23:59:21-06:00</updated>
   <id>http://www.gorilla-studios.com/2012/01/02/gorilla-studios-now-on-500px</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='http://500px.com/gorilla-studios'&gt;Gorilla-Studios is now on 500px.com&lt;/a&gt;, a new photographic community for discovering and sharing great photographs.  I'm still setting up my profile and getting my work uploaded, but if you want to share your work be sure to join soon.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>New Years Resolution - Investing In Myself</title>
   <link href="http://www.gorilla-studios.com/2012/01/01/new-years-resolution-investing-in-myself"/>
   <updated>2012-01-01T17:33:31-06:00</updated>
   <id>http://www.gorilla-studios.com/2012/01/01/new-years-resolution-investing-in-myself</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Happy New Year everyone!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Here's to making 2012 a great year. I usually don't make resolutions but this year I will be investing in my photography - dedicating more time and hopefully upgrading equipment as the year goes on. In 2011 I was focused on getting married and working my full time job, so now this year I am going to spend more time learning, shooting and expanding my portfolio. My immediate goal is to at least go out shooting once a week and try to get a portfolio image every month. I want to learn more and hone my skills, I will be really pushing myself and sharing my knowledge and experience here. I have quite a bit planned for the site this year, more post ideas, reviews, critiques and more!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;So happy shooting and happy 2012 everyone!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Chris&lt;/p&gt;</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>From The Archives</title>
   <link href="http://www.gorilla-studios.com/2011/12/31/from-the-archives-2"/>
   <updated>2011-12-31T11:33:44-06:00</updated>
   <id>http://www.gorilla-studios.com/2011/12/31/from-the-archives-2</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;img alt='Lighthouse and Sailboat on Lake Michigan, Chicago, Illinois' src='/images/IMG_1811.jpg' /&gt;</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Whats In The Bag? Black Rapid RS 7</title>
   <link href="http://www.gorilla-studios.com/2011/12/30/whats-in-the-bag-black-rapid-rs-7"/>
   <updated>2011-12-30T07:18:30-06:00</updated>
   <id>http://www.gorilla-studios.com/2011/12/30/whats-in-the-bag-black-rapid-rs-7</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;The newest addition to my setup is a brand new Black Rapid RS-7 sling camera strap.  Prior to finding this one under the Christmas tree this year I was using a homemade setup that consisted of a guitar strap secured to a post from an extra tripod mount - not the most professional setup in the world.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Black Rapid RS-7 is simply the best camera strap I have come across in years.  It allows me to go hands free when setting up a shoot, moving lighting around or directing my subjects while keeping my camera at my side right where I need it ready to go. It comes with the main strap and a fastener that attaches to your SLR body tripod mount (or long lens if need be).  The strap clips into the fastener with a locking carabiner that sits well on the underside of your camera. I have a battery grip with vertical controls and the while the RS-7 attached I don't find it uncomfortable shooting vertically.  The fastener sits right in the center of my palm without any discomfort.  The carabiner swings out of the way and freely spins on the strap without un-screwing the fastener from the SLR body.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt='Black Rapid RS-7 Fastener on Canon EOS DSLR Camera' src='/images/fastener.jpg' /&gt;&lt;p&gt;The whole setup feels great to use - I am usually paranoid about straps and hanging on to my camera, but I have no doubts when using it.  As with any strap I always have a hand on the lens while walking in crowds or around anything that I can bang into, but I have no worries about it unclipping or detaching and dropping. Sliding the strap up to shooting position is very quick with little resistance, same with sliding it back in place at your side.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt='Black Rapid RS-7 Caribeaner clip for digital SLR camera' src='/images/carabiner.jpg' /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Another great feature is the locking 'bumpers' on the strap that keep the shoulder padding in the right place.  There is a back bumper that you lock in right where you want the camera to hang - this way if the padded portion of the strap moves when you pull your camera up to shoot, as you slide your camera back down it catches the bumper and moves the strap back into the proper location.  There is another front bumper that you can move down to lock the camera down by your hip which really reduces how much it swings around when you are hands free.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The RS-7 is also compatible with Black Rapid's Mods - like the BRAD strap or storage for memory cards or a cell phone.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Overall the Black Rapid RS-7 is a beautifully made camera strap that any photographer worth their salt should have in their bag. I only had the chance to shoot with it a few times, but I am in love with it and highly recommend it. Check out the &lt;a href='http://www.blackrapid.com/product/camera-strap/rs-7/'&gt;RS-7 at Black Rapid's website&lt;/a&gt;.  Don't believe me? Check out &lt;a href='http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=hWJKrqP40Nw'&gt;Jared Polin's (aka FroKnowsFoto......DOT COM) video review.&lt;/a&gt;  All images courtesy of Black Rapid.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Quote - Ira Glass</title>
   <link href="http://www.gorilla-studios.com/2011/12/27/quote-ira-glass"/>
   <updated>2011-12-27T22:26:40-06:00</updated>
   <id>http://www.gorilla-studios.com/2011/12/27/quote-ira-glass</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I am reading &lt;a href='http://www.amazon.com/The-Passionate-Photographer-Toward-Becoming/dp/0321719891/ref=sr_1_1'&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Passionate Photographer: Ten Steps Toward Becoming Great&lt;/em&gt; by Steve Simon&lt;/a&gt; and came across a quote from Ira Glass about honing your skills that I had heard a few years ago which hit me like a truck...&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='quote'&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You've got to get rid of a lot of crap before you're going to get anything that's special.  You don't want to be making mediocre stuff.  There's a gap for the first couple years that you're making stuff. What you're making isn't so good. But your taste, the thing that got you into the game, is good enough that you can tell what you're making is kind of a disappointment to you. A lot of people at that point, they quit. The thing I would say to you with all my heart is that most everybody I know who does interesting, creative work, went through a phase of years where they had really good taste, they could tell what they were making wasn't as good as they wanted it to be. They knew it fell short. Everybody goes through that. If you're going through it right now, or if you're just starting off and you're entering into that phase, you've got to know its totally normal and the most important thing you could do is a lot of work. Do a huge volume of work because it's only by actually going through a volume of work that you're actually going to catch up and close that gap.&lt;br /&gt;
- Ira Glass&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Such an amazing quote.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Watching The Storm Roll Through</title>
   <link href="http://www.gorilla-studios.com/2011/12/16/watching-the-storm-roll-through"/>
   <updated>2011-12-16T10:45:10-06:00</updated>
   <id>http://www.gorilla-studios.com/2011/12/16/watching-the-storm-roll-through</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;a href='/images/CRW_1453.jpg' rel='lightbox[unique]'&gt;&lt;img src='/images/CRW_1453s.jpg' /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Photoshop Quick Tip - Lens Correction</title>
   <link href="http://www.gorilla-studios.com/2011/12/14/photoshop-quick-tip-lens-correction"/>
   <updated>2011-12-14T09:36:53-06:00</updated>
   <id>http://www.gorilla-studios.com/2011/12/14/photoshop-quick-tip-lens-correction</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I love shooting in downtown Chicago, but one of the hazards you run into is something called the Keystone Effect - a distortion of taller buildings and structures.  A few days after our wedding, the wife and I took a day trip into the city with our cameras in tow. After a fun afternoon at the Shedd Aquarium we walked back up along the lake and I took a quick shot of the skyline. Here you can see the shot before editing.  I added quick lines to show how the buildings are leaning in towards the center of frame and you will notice this effect getting worse the farther from center they are.  This is a great example of the Keystone Effect.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt='Distorted image correction' src='/images/before_wlines.jpg' /&gt;&lt;p&gt;To take care of this we are going to use a Photoshop filter called &lt;strong&gt;Filter &gt; Distort &gt; Lens Correction&lt;/strong&gt;.   Here is the control panel for this particular filter.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt='Photoshop Lens Correction Filter' src='/images/lens-correction.jpg' /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Leave the grid on and take a look over at the Transform section towards the bottom right.  There you will find a slider for 'Vertical Perspective'.  Here you can adjust your photo and make sure everything lines up the way it should, taking care of that Keystone Effect.  For this particular example I adjusted it to -15, this got most of the buildings in the shot back to vertical, especially Aon Center and Trump Tower.  Once you make your adjustment you will notice that the bottom of your photo has been compressed in a bit leaving some bare canvas on either bottom corner. This is due to the fact Photoshop has basically tilted the entire plane of the photo towards you, hinging on the center line - therefore the bottom of the image is smaller and the top is larger.  Just crop the photo to ensure you don't have any blank areas on either corner. Here we can see the before and after:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt='Keystone effect before after' src='/images/before_after.jpg' /&gt;&lt;p&gt;It is details like this that can sometimes make or break a photograph so keep an eye out for this effect when shooting large buildings or have a lot of vertical lines in your photo.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Have fun and keep shooting!&lt;/p&gt;</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Happy 8th Birthday Gorilla-Studios</title>
   <link href="http://www.gorilla-studios.com/2011/12/12/happy-8th-birthday-gorilla-studios"/>
   <updated>2011-12-12T11:46:19-06:00</updated>
   <id>http://www.gorilla-studios.com/2011/12/12/happy-8th-birthday-gorilla-studios</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;It's been 8 years since the first version of Gorilla-Studios went live! A few tear-downs and re-designs later, many trivial &amp;amp; random posts later and here we are! I meant this post to be a bit more grand but I am laid up this week one appendix lighter so the celebration will have to wait a little bit. I'll be back later with some more, but for now, its time for another nap...&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Chris&lt;/p&gt;</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Whats In The Bag?</title>
   <link href="http://www.gorilla-studios.com/2011/12/03/whats-in-the-bag"/>
   <updated>2011-12-03T14:35:05-06:00</updated>
   <id>http://www.gorilla-studios.com/2011/12/03/whats-in-the-bag</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I get a lot of questions about what camera and lenses I shoot with and what gear I like to carry, so I am going to write a few posts covering what's in my bag and what I lug around on a typical shoot.  Here's my usual gear bag for general shoots:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt='Lowepro Camera Bag' src='/images/bag.jpg' /&gt;&lt;p&gt;And my primary DSLR....&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt='Canon EOS 10D DSLR' src='/images/10D.jpg' /&gt;&lt;p&gt;I shoot everything with my trusty EOS 10D.  Its pretty antiquated these days, but I still get great results.  It has a 6.1MP CMOS which still holds it's own in most situations but is severely lacking in low-light situations. It has an ISO range from 100 to 1600, however I rarely get shots above ISO 800 that I really like. All the photos in the gallery were shot with the 10D paired with various lenses (which I will go over individually later).  Originally purchased in 2003, the camera is still solid as a rock after taking (and this is an estimate) somewhere in the neighborhood of at least 50,000 photos.  The primary shutter button is just starting to flake out, it takes a firm press and there is a bit of a delay but thankfully I have it paired to a dual-battery grip with vertical controls.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Once my checkbook has recovered from the wedding I am planning on investing in a 5D MkII.  Remember the phrase &lt;em&gt;'Buy once, buy right'&lt;/em&gt;.  Don't buy something thats good enough for now that you may outgrow later just because you can afford it. Save up and invest in good equipment - it will last and you'll be much happier.  I made the mistake as a young photographer by purchasing a number of really slow lenses not knowing exactly what I should have gotten.  I saw the Canon 70-200mm f2.8 but didn't understand why that was so much more than an off brand f4 telephoto.  There is a huge difference in quality and without experience I couldn't see that.  Remember, you don't need a bunch of fancy lenses and the latest greatest equipment to be a great photographer.  Invest in a solid DSLR, and one or two fast lenses, and shoot, shoot, SHOOT.  Practice and experience make the photographer, not the gear.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I'll be writing some more posts about the rest of the gear in my bag, so check back later or subscribe to my RSS Feed.  Feel free to contact me with any gear questions, and have fun shooting!&lt;br /&gt;

- Chris&lt;/p&gt;</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>From The Archives</title>
   <link href="http://www.gorilla-studios.com/2011/12/03/from-the-archives"/>
   <updated>2011-12-03T13:11:22-06:00</updated>
   <id>http://www.gorilla-studios.com/2011/12/03/from-the-archives</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;img src='/images/CRW_2392_med_thumb.jpg' /&gt;</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Congrats John &amp; Helen</title>
   <link href="http://www.gorilla-studios.com/2011/11/22/congrats-john-helen"/>
   <updated>2011-11-22T17:25:59-06:00</updated>
   <id>http://www.gorilla-studios.com/2011/11/22/congrats-john-helen</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I got the chance over the weekend to take John &amp;amp; Helen over to the park for a quick engagement photo shoot. We had a lot of fun and they were fantastic to work with, requiring very little direction to get great portraits from. This was my first attempt at using an off-camera flash out in the field. More on that soon!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt='Off camera flash portrait' src='/images/CRW_3241.jpg' /&gt;</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Mini-Review - Opteka MP100 67" Monopod</title>
   <link href="http://www.gorilla-studios.com/2011/10/25/mini-review-opteka-mp100-67-monopod"/>
   <updated>2011-10-25T12:03:11-05:00</updated>
   <id>http://www.gorilla-studios.com/2011/10/25/mini-review-opteka-mp100-67-monopod</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;In preparation for an upcoming photo trip to see migrating Sandhill Cranes I wanted to get a monopod so I didn't have to lug my full tripod out into the field.  After some browsing online, I decided to go with the Opteka MP100 67&quot; Monopod.  I couldn't bring myself to spending over a hundred dollars on some high-end brand name kit.  For &lt;a href='http://www.amazon.com/Opteka-MP100-Professional-Heavy-Monopod/dp/B0002RBQO0/'&gt;13.50 from Amazon&lt;/a&gt; I figured why not try it and see if its a good deal.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt='Opteka M100 Monopod and carrying case' src='/images/opteka_m100.jpg' /&gt;&lt;p&gt;The monopod itself is rather sturdy, not completely solid, but well built.  It compacts down very well, with 3 quick release levers for fairly easy adjustments.  I paired it up with an Opteka Ball Head and got amazing results.  I assumed for 13$ it was going to be flimsy and not well constructed, but I was surprised. It held my EOS with battery grip, the ball head, and a large lens very well.  The main advantage of this monopod is that it extends out to 67&quot; which is a must for me considering I stand at 6'6&quot;.  With the ballhead I found myself actually lowering the top section a bit to get the camera eye level, which is astounding.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Overall its a well built monopod for an absolute steal.  Its not the most solid constructed unit I have ever seen, but it is a fantastic bargain.  We will see how it holds up to day to day usage in the field.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Ever have one of those days?</title>
   <link href="http://www.gorilla-studios.com/2011/10/07/ever-have-one-of-those-days"/>
   <updated>2011-10-07T15:17:55-05:00</updated>
   <id>http://www.gorilla-studios.com/2011/10/07/ever-have-one-of-those-days</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;where everything was perfect and way beyond expectation? I did, and it happened to be my wedding day...&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt='Chris and wife' src='/images/c_n_k.jpg' /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Huge thanks to &lt;a href='http://riversidereceptions.com/'&gt;Riverside Receptions&lt;/a&gt; in Geneva, IL for taking care of everything, having everything setup, ready to go and handling anything that came up.  The service was fantastic, the food was wonderful and the whole day was amazing thanks to them.  Many thanks to &lt;a href='http://aclassactdjservice.com/aclassactdjservice.com/Welcome.html'&gt;Andy Fuzak with A Class Act DJ Service&lt;/a&gt; for DJ'ing the night and making sure everything flowed well and everyone kept dancing all night!  Also many thanks to &lt;a href='http://www.bellapictures.com/'&gt;Bella Pictures&lt;/a&gt; and their photographer who captured the special day for us.  I am extremely picky when it comes to photography and they paired us with a true professional - I cannot wait to see the results.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Thank you to all my family and friends who supported us throughout the years and came out to celebrate with us.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;And above all, thanks to my blushing bride, I love you so much.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Thank You Steve</title>
   <link href="http://www.gorilla-studios.com/2011/10/06/thank-you-steve"/>
   <updated>2011-10-06T08:57:37-05:00</updated>
   <id>http://www.gorilla-studios.com/2011/10/06/thank-you-steve</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Thank you for years of dedication and passion. When I was tall enough to reach the keyboard I started playing around with my Dad&amp;#8217;s Apple II, getting lost in the adventure of Oddessy, trekking the Oregon Trail, and discovering a passion that lives on to this day. My jaw hit the floor when we got our Apple IIGS, color graphics! A mouse! Dad and I started learning basic programming together, exploring what we could get that amazing machine to do.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was the happiest kid in the world when I got my very own Centris 650, all 30Mhz of its power, all mine! I was an expert by the time I got a PowerMac 7200. An iMac, PowerMac G4, and an iBook all followed. My trusty PowerBook and PowerMac are still my reliable workhorses I use every day. My wife got me an iPad for my birthday and I was as giddy as I was when I was a kid playing with our Apple II.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As my passion for photography grew and grew, so did my love of Apple. Their products allowed me to focus on my work and express my creativity, as Steve said, a true &amp;#8216;bicycle for the mind&amp;#8217;. I would not be able to do what I do if not for Steve Jobs. I am in awe of all the tributes popping up all over the web today, it truly shows us the world lost a visionary.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He did make a dent in the universe.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is with great sadness in my heart that I say &amp;#8216;Thanks Steve&amp;#8217;&lt;/p&gt;</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Great Egret</title>
   <link href="http://www.gorilla-studios.com/2011/08/27/great-egret"/>
   <updated>2011-08-27T13:34:48-05:00</updated>
   <id>http://www.gorilla-studios.com/2011/08/27/great-egret</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;img alt='Great Egret on the Fox River' src='/images/CRW_9646.jpg' /&gt;</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Stop to smell the roses</title>
   <link href="http://www.gorilla-studios.com/2011/08/10/stop-to-smell-the-roses"/>
   <updated>2011-08-10T10:52:27-05:00</updated>
   <id>http://www.gorilla-studios.com/2011/08/10/stop-to-smell-the-roses</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;You'll never know what you might find.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt='Bug in Flower' src='/images/flower_bug.jpg' /&gt;</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Good Morning</title>
   <link href="http://www.gorilla-studios.com/2011/07/30/good-morning"/>
   <updated>2011-07-30T10:58:42-05:00</updated>
   <id>http://www.gorilla-studios.com/2011/07/30/good-morning</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;img alt='Butterfly Mt St Mary Park' src='/images/CRW_8206.jpg' /&gt;</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>New band logo - Just Enuff</title>
   <link href="http://www.gorilla-studios.com/2011/07/12/new-band-logo-just-enuff"/>
   <updated>2011-07-12T21:05:12-05:00</updated>
   <id>http://www.gorilla-studios.com/2011/07/12/new-band-logo-just-enuff</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;img alt='Just Enuff' src='/images/just_enuff.jpg' /&gt;</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Photojojo - Gifts &amp; Gear For The Photographer</title>
   <link href="http://www.gorilla-studios.com/2011/07/07/photojojo-gifts-gear-for-photographers"/>
   <updated>2011-07-07T13:28:03-05:00</updated>
   <id>http://www.gorilla-studios.com/2011/07/07/photojojo-gifts-gear-for-photographers</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Stumbled across this today - &lt;a href='http://photojojo.com/store/'&gt;gifts and gear for photographers from Photojojo&lt;/a&gt;.  Fun looking site with lots of fun stuff that I would love to order (or &lt;a href='http://photojojo.com/store/awesomeness/camera-lens-mug/'&gt;hope to find&lt;/a&gt; under the Christmas tree *cough cough*).    Full disclosure - I have no affiliation with Photojojo, but would easily be bought with freebies.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Cuddle Up With Your Favorite Lens</title>
   <link href="http://www.gorilla-studios.com/2011/07/07/cuddle-up-with-your-favorite-lens"/>
   <updated>2011-07-07T09:05:13-05:00</updated>
   <id>http://www.gorilla-studios.com/2011/07/07/cuddle-up-with-your-favorite-lens</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='http://www.plushtography.com/shop.html'&gt;Plushtography.com&lt;/a&gt; hand makes lens pillows that are absolutely awesome.  Two of the three they have are now sold-out and I would assume the last one is going to sell out fast too.  Tip of the hat to &lt;a href='http://www.engadget.com/2011/07/07/plush-camera-lens-pillows-get-you-through-the-night-koala-hug-a/'&gt;Engadget&lt;/a&gt; for the find.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Congrats D&amp;H</title>
   <link href="http://www.gorilla-studios.com/2011/06/29/congratulations-dh"/>
   <updated>2011-06-29T06:35:40-05:00</updated>
   <id>http://www.gorilla-studios.com/2011/06/29/congratulations-dh</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;img alt='The Happy Couple' src='/images/d&amp;amp;h.jpg' /&gt;</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Start Basic</title>
   <link href="http://www.gorilla-studios.com/2011/06/25/start-basic"/>
   <updated>2011-06-25T17:10:03-05:00</updated>
   <id>http://www.gorilla-studios.com/2011/06/25/start-basic</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;img alt='Start Basic band logo' src='/images/start_basic_logo.jpg' /&gt;&lt;img alt='Start Basic band' src='/images/start-basic1.jpg' /&gt;&lt;p&gt;I got the chance to shoot some promo shots over the weekend for Start Basic - a great local band from Batavia.  They are prepping their first album so we are working on rolling out their new logo, identity, t-shirt and poster designs - the works. I'll be posting about my experience with shooting a band, working with your subjects and getting the results you want.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Cranes And Herons</title>
   <link href="http://www.gorilla-studios.com/2011/06/18/cranes"/>
   <updated>2011-06-18T13:47:15-05:00</updated>
   <id>http://www.gorilla-studios.com/2011/06/18/cranes</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;img alt='Great Blue Heron in the reeds' src='/images/CRW_3909.jpg' /&gt;&lt;img alt='Great Egret eating fish' src='/images/CRW_4045.jpg' /&gt;</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Absolutely Breathtaking</title>
   <link href="http://www.gorilla-studios.com/2011/06/15/absolutely-breathtaking"/>
   <updated>2011-06-15T20:22:50-05:00</updated>
   <id>http://www.gorilla-studios.com/2011/06/15/absolutely-breathtaking</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Via Gizmodo - Randy Halverson shot these &lt;a href='http://gizmodo.com/5812198/watch-the-milky-way-wheel-overhead-in-all-its-glory'&gt;absolutely breathtaking time-lapse shots&lt;/a&gt; of the Milky Way passing over the South Dakota landscape. Simply amazing.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>This Is How My Childhood Was Made</title>
   <link href="http://www.gorilla-studios.com/2011/06/15/this-is-how-my-childhood-was-made"/>
   <updated>2011-06-15T11:42:59-05:00</updated>
   <id>http://www.gorilla-studios.com/2011/06/15/this-is-how-my-childhood-was-made</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;CNet posted a &lt;a href='http://news.cnet.com/2300-11386_3-10008183.html?tag=mncol'&gt;photo tour&lt;/a&gt; of LEGO's headquarters in Denmark, I can't tell you what I would do for a trip there in person.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Rock n' Roll</title>
   <link href="http://www.gorilla-studios.com/2011/06/03/rocknroll"/>
   <updated>2011-06-03T14:51:20-05:00</updated>
   <id>http://www.gorilla-studios.com/2011/06/03/rocknroll</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;img alt='Formerly We Survived Y2K' src='/images/CRW_3618.jpg' /&gt;</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>The Oatmeal v. FunnyJunk - Copyright &amp; Creativity</title>
   <link href="http://www.gorilla-studios.com/2011/06/02/the-oatmeal-vs-funnyjunk-copyright-creativity"/>
   <updated>2011-06-02T09:12:43-05:00</updated>
   <id>http://www.gorilla-studios.com/2011/06/02/the-oatmeal-vs-funnyjunk-copyright-creativity</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='http://www.theoatmeal.com'&gt;The Oatmeal&lt;/a&gt; is possibly one of the most creative laugh-out-loud funny (and &lt;a href='http://theoatmeal.com/comics/semicolon'&gt;educational&lt;/a&gt;) web-comics I have come across in recent years and it breaks my heart to see Matthew Inman getting ripped off by FunnyJunk.  Arstechnica has &lt;a href='http://arstechnica.com/tech-policy/news/2011/06/funnyjunk-vs-the-oatmeal.ars'&gt;a great article&lt;/a&gt; about FunnyJunk lifting Inman's work with little to no attribution.  Be sure to read Matthew's thoughtful and insightful &lt;a href='http://theoatmeal.com/blog/funnyjunk2'&gt;response&lt;/a&gt; to the whole ordeal.  As a footnote - if you want to see the downfall of human culture in action just look at any internet forum or youtube comment thread.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;As an artist I am extremely nervous about my own work being ripped off, but thankfully (or not) I am not well-known enough to have that happen.  I have struggled with how to handle copyrighting and watermarking my images to protect my work, however I don't want to treat my tens of readers/viewers like criminals.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Broken Lens Horror Stories</title>
   <link href="http://www.gorilla-studios.com/2011/06/01/broken-lens-horror-stories"/>
   <updated>2011-06-01T11:51:43-05:00</updated>
   <id>http://www.gorilla-studios.com/2011/06/01/broken-lens-horror-stories</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Fun little article over on Gizmodo listing some &lt;a href='http://gizmodo.com/5804720/broken-lens-horror-stories'&gt;horrifying stories&lt;/a&gt; about equipment damage.  It brought to my attention &lt;a href='http://www.borrowlenses.com/'&gt;www.borrow-lenses.com&lt;/a&gt;, which I have every intention of using sometime in near future.  Remember - always take care of your camera equipment!&lt;/p&gt;</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>We Survived Y2K</title>
   <link href="http://www.gorilla-studios.com/2011/05/24/we-survived-y2k"/>
   <updated>2011-05-24T20:02:02-05:00</updated>
   <id>http://www.gorilla-studios.com/2011/05/24/we-survived-y2k</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;img alt='We Survived Y2K' src='/images/y2k.jpg' /&gt;&lt;p&gt;A great local band asked me to design a new logo for them, but of course when I presented it to them they told me they are changing their name.  I'll help them out when they finally settle on an identity, stay tuned...&lt;/p&gt;</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>When was...</title>
   <link href="http://www.gorilla-studios.com/2011/03/26/when-was"/>
   <updated>2011-03-26T14:37:29-05:00</updated>
   <id>http://www.gorilla-studios.com/2011/03/26/when-was</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;img alt='When was the last time conventional wisdom changed the world' src='/images/change.jpg' /&gt;&lt;p&gt;I woke up with that in my head a few months ago and finally decided to put it to use.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Fly Me To The Moon</title>
   <link href="http://www.gorilla-studios.com/2011/03/18/fly-me-to-the-moon"/>
   <updated>2011-03-18T22:41:27-05:00</updated>
   <id>http://www.gorilla-studios.com/2011/03/18/fly-me-to-the-moon</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;img alt='Super Moon shot' src='/images/fly_me_to_the_moon.jpg' /&gt;</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Against Chrome - A Manifesto</title>
   <link href="http://www.gorilla-studios.com/2011/02/07/against-chrome-a-manifesto"/>
   <updated>2011-02-07T12:02:35-06:00</updated>
   <id>http://www.gorilla-studios.com/2011/02/07/against-chrome-a-manifesto</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='http://www.3quarksdaily.com/3quarksdaily/2011/02/against-chrome-a-manifesto.html'&gt;Great blog post by Steven Poole&lt;/a&gt; lashing out against virtual visual clutter in modern UI.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I disagree on his critisim of the iPad's iBooks reader though, while it is always in a perpetual middle of the book state, it fades to the background rather quickly when you get absorbed into the actual book itself.  Additionally, if you find yourself nit-picking the tiniest details of the software your using then the designers got all the huge important stuff right.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;A bit extreme, but I enjoyed the post thoroughly.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>100 Days In Glacier National Park</title>
   <link href="http://www.gorilla-studios.com/2009/12/02/100-days-in-glacier-national-park"/>
   <updated>2009-12-02T14:25:25-06:00</updated>
   <id>http://www.gorilla-studios.com/2009/12/02/100-days-in-glacier-national-park</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='http://www.glacierparkmagazine.com/100_days_in_Glacier_National_Park/100daysinGlacierNationalPark.html'&gt;A beautiful photo set from a photographer who spent 100 days in Glacier National Park.&lt;/a&gt;  This is definitely is kindling my long lost love of photography.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Pixar's Brad Bird On Fostering Innovation</title>
   <link href="http://www.gorilla-studios.com/2009/09/29/pixars-brad-bird-on-fostering-innovation"/>
   <updated>2009-09-29T12:49:26-05:00</updated>
   <id>http://www.gorilla-studios.com/2009/09/29/pixars-brad-bird-on-fostering-innovation</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='http://gigaom.com/2008/04/17/pixars-brad-bird-on-fostering-innovation/'&gt;An article from 2008 with Brad Bird&lt;/a&gt;, director of &lt;em&gt;The Incredibles&lt;/em&gt; on fostering innovation and Pixar's company culture.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I have read and re-read this article many many times and I hope I am privileged enough to work with people like him.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Mac Portable Teardown</title>
   <link href="http://www.gorilla-studios.com/2009/09/23/mac-portable-teardown"/>
   <updated>2009-09-23T17:07:49-05:00</updated>
   <id>http://www.gorilla-studios.com/2009/09/23/mac-portable-teardown</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Technologizer has a &lt;a href='http://technologizer.com/2009/09/20/inside-the-macintosh-portable/'&gt;fantastic tear-down of the original Macintosh Portable&lt;/a&gt;.  Its amazing how far we have come in the last 20 years.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Designs just dessert</title>
   <link href="http://www.gorilla-studios.com/2009/09/08/designs-just-dessert"/>
   <updated>2009-09-08T15:23:59-05:00</updated>
   <id>http://www.gorilla-studios.com/2009/09/08/designs-just-dessert</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;It's safe to say that I am obsessed with design.  I mentally critique just about everything I see on a daily basis on how it's put together, how usable or readable it is.  I'm constantly nitpicking tiny details in web design and technology.  My girlfriend gets annoyed when I complain about my cellphone menu being laid out the way it is, or a web page design choice.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I came across a &lt;a href='http://www.aiga.org/content.cfm/designs-just-dessert'&gt;wonderful article on AIGA by Kenneth FitzGerald&lt;/a&gt;
 comparing a Mac to a box of cake mix and design to dessert.  Its a thought-provoking read, definitely worth looking at.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class='quote'&gt;&amp;ldquo;I urge students to aspire to pastry chef status as graphic designers. They should select choice ingredients, carefully consider the utensils they employ and eschew default choices. This isnt to run down cake mix product, which I often enjoy. Its a satisfactory and convenient option when you want a treat. With a little embellishment, it can be especially tasty.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Enjoy&lt;/p&gt;</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>New Identity - Ms Domestic Darling</title>
   <link href="http://www.gorilla-studios.com/2009/08/31/ms-domestic-darling-new-identity"/>
   <updated>2009-08-31T09:57:39-05:00</updated>
   <id>http://www.gorilla-studios.com/2009/08/31/ms-domestic-darling-new-identity</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;img alt='' src='/images/domesticdarling.png' /&gt;&lt;p&gt;A close friend of mine recently asked me for some design help with her new blog and after a lot of humming and hawing with a few false starts, we got on the right track and came up with a new identity &amp;amp; logo for Ms. Domestic Darling. The logo was created by scanning a few sketches into the computer and using Adobe Illustrator to create a sharp, colorful, vector-based logo.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Check out her blog at &lt;a href='http://msdomesticdarling.com'&gt;MsDomesticDarling.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Enjoy&lt;/p&gt;</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Adam Savage On The Value Of Failing</title>
   <link href="http://www.gorilla-studios.com/2009/07/06/adam-savage-on-the-value-of-failing"/>
   <updated>2009-07-06T20:27:22-05:00</updated>
   <id>http://www.gorilla-studios.com/2009/07/06/adam-savage-on-the-value-of-failing</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;a href='http://fora.tv/2009/05/30/MythBuster_Adam_Savages_Colossal_Failures'&gt;GREAT talk at this years Makers Faire&lt;/a&gt;</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Visual Decision Making</title>
   <link href="http://www.gorilla-studios.com/2009/07/05/visual-decision-making"/>
   <updated>2009-07-05T13:22:34-05:00</updated>
   <id>http://www.gorilla-studios.com/2009/07/05/visual-decision-making</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;a href='http://www.alistapart.com/articles/visual-decision-making/'&gt;A great article from A List Apart about visual aesthetics in web design.&lt;/a&gt;</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Testing Word Press</title>
   <link href="http://www.gorilla-studios.com/2009/06/30/testing-word-press"/>
   <updated>2009-06-30T11:13:03-05:00</updated>
   <id>http://www.gorilla-studios.com/2009/06/30/testing-word-press</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;For a while now Gorilla-Studios has lead a secret double life - one standard PHP/HTML site along with a WP Powered site hidden behind the scenes.  Over the next few days I will be migrating the site over to a WP powered version.  I've decided to go with WordPress to save me some headaches with tracking posts, RSS Feeds, etc.  There are some downsides though, WP is built for beginners with little web experience, and since I make a living from web-development there are some WP functionalities &amp;amp; practices that drive me up a wall.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;However, the site should be gaining more and more functionality in the coming weeks, hope you enjoy.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;- Chris&lt;/p&gt;</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>My desktop, Friday at 5pm</title>
   <link href="http://www.gorilla-studios.com/2009/04/24/my-desktop-friday-at-5pm"/>
   <updated>2009-04-24T13:03:54-05:00</updated>
   <id>http://www.gorilla-studios.com/2009/04/24/my-desktop-friday-at-5pm</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;img src='/images/geek_desktop.jpg' title='My Desktop' /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Closing up work for the day, I just had a geek moment I thought I would share. Im starting to make a living doing what I *love*. How great is that? That is a screen FILLED with code.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Go Cubs Go</title>
   <link href="http://www.gorilla-studios.com/2009/04/06/go-cubs-go"/>
   <updated>2009-04-06T13:25:14-05:00</updated>
   <id>http://www.gorilla-studios.com/2009/04/06/go-cubs-go</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;img alt='Wrigley Field' src='/images/wrigley-field.jpg' /&gt;</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Preaching To The Choir With A Loudspeaker</title>
   <link href="http://www.gorilla-studios.com/2008/09/08/preaching-to-the-choir-with-a-loudspeaker"/>
   <updated>2008-09-08T13:29:30-05:00</updated>
   <id>http://www.gorilla-studios.com/2008/09/08/preaching-to-the-choir-with-a-loudspeaker</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;img alt='' src='/images/football.jpg' /&gt;&lt;p&gt;There is a fine line between advertisements and bombarding the viewer with annoying junk, and ESPN has gone the distance with the latter. I went to check on some football news on SportsIllustrated.com when I was greeted with a lovely growing astroturf ad for Monday Night Football that covered the WHOLE SCREEN. After grumbling and letting it load all the way so I could close it, I was delighted to see that there were also 3 ads for it again on the main page. Seriously ESPN? I'm pretty sure most football fans that go to SI.com to check football scores may have a vague clue that there are games on Monday night now, just a guess. Excuse me while I go put a pop up ad on the front page here to advertise for my site.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>No, I will not fix your computer</title>
   <link href="http://www.gorilla-studios.com/2008/08/28/no-i-will-not-fix-your-computer"/>
   <updated>2008-08-28T14:29:46-05:00</updated>
   <id>http://www.gorilla-studios.com/2008/08/28/no-i-will-not-fix-your-computer</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;img alt='' src='/images/designer.gif' /&gt;</content>
 </entry>
 
 
</feed>