<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Gorilla-Studios Photography</title>
    <description>Focusing on stunning landscape and high-energy music photography, Gorilla-Studios has been the online home of my portfolio since 2003. I specialize in landscapes, cityscapes and architecture, nature, candid portraiture, headshots, band promos and concert photography.
</description>
    <link>http://gorilla-studios.com</link>
    <atom:link href="http://gorilla-studios.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>My top 10 images of 2016</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I am continuing my tradition of taking the end of the year to review my photographs over the last 365 days and create a selection of 10 images that represent my best work over that time period. This year was mostly focused on family and work so I didn&#39;t get the chance to shoot as much as possible, but I was able to get some time in Chicago, Portland, and London which I am very grateful for.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To find my best work I have a smart gallery in Lightroom set to this calendar year + anything thats rated 3 stars or above. At the end of the year I start weeding out weaker shots, taking a few passes to get the collection down to the top 15 or so. This year I started with a set of 56 images, which seems about average for me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/posts/2016-finalists.jpg&quot;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Photos in 2016 rated 3+&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After a few passes I narrowed it down to my 10 strongest. Lets take a look at what I chose, presented chronologically.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since I work about two blocks from the Sears Tower and its between my office and the train station, I find myself constantly snapping photos and getting different looks at the building. In March when it started warming up a bit I wanted to see what kind of details I could get in the glass bottom viewing platforms using my 70-200 f/2.8. You can&#39;t get directly underneath and shoot upwards since there is a large atrium on the west side of the building, so I tried an angle I hadn&#39;t seen before. I walked over to the corner of Adams &amp;amp; Wacker Drive, almost completely around the to the side of the building, where I could barely see the west face of the building. From that angle the boxes were very pronounced outwards, combined with the &#39;shoulders&#39; of the building making some interesting lines. A deep blue cloudless sky turned into a wonderful dark spotlight when converted to black and white.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/catalog/0K6A0939.jpg&quot;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the end of March I found myself out in London on business, and while I didn&#39;t have much time I was able to sneak out for a late night shoot along the Thames where I took this photo of Millennium Bridge and St. Paul&#39;s cathedral. I love the mixture of colors reflecting in the river in contrast to the almost purple night sky.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/catalog/0K6A1416.jpg&quot;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In May I headed out west to Portland Oregon, and while I was there I ventured out to Cannon Beach. An iconic beach instantly recognizable to anyone who has seen &lt;i&gt;The Goonies&lt;/i&gt;, Haystack Rock is a beautiful rock formation over 200 feet tall jutting out of the Pacific coast. I spent two nights shooting sunsets from various spots around the beach, both in and out of the water. My favorite shot was taken at sunset as the tide was creeping in and I could barely feel my toes. The waves breaking over the large rock in the center of the frame combined with how the rip tide washed out the foreground make this one of the best landscapes I have taken in some time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/catalog/0K6A3261.jpg&quot;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another location in Portland I visited was Multnomah Falls just outside Portland. After a serious rain shower cleaned out the tourists I had a few minutes before it filled back up again. Making sure I had my rain gear covering my camera, I got my 16-35 f/4 setup on the tripod and started exposing frames around 1 to 2 seconds, trying to smooth the rushing water as much as possible without over-exposing the highlights. The dull gray sky wasn&#39;t adding anything so I cropped in-camera to just below the horizon above, and just below the base of the falls. This was the first time shooting at 16mm that I wish I had a bit more range on the low end, as I couldn&#39;t get as much of the lake below as I would like.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure class=&quot;vertical&quot;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/catalog/0K6A3635.jpg&quot;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Back in Chicago, again shooting the Sears Tower, this time it was more of a learning exercise. I picked up some stackable ND filters so I wanted some practice making exposures with an ND16 (or more) sitting in front of the lens. I was able to open the shutter for 30 seconds at f/16, which on a windy day created the wonderful cloud movement that I was hoping for. After importing these into Lightroom I sat on them for a few months not paying them another thought. It wasn&#39;t until I started diving deeper into Lightroom&#39;s black and white conversion tools that I went back and took a closer look, which I am very glad I did.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure class=&quot;vertical&quot;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/catalog/0K6A8841.jpg&quot;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Combining my ND filters with a straight up composition I used for some commission work earlier in the year I took some more black and white photos of various skyscrapers in the Loop. This next frame was taken on Wacker Drive and Monroe of the Deloitte building, a newer building in the skyline. Some minor sharpening with a little burning of some shadows, but otherwise this was almost straight out of the camera. I was surprised how much contrast I had gotten from the pylon at the bottom of the frame with the ceiling of the ground floor. Another piece for my architectural portfolio.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/catalog/0K6A8852.jpg&quot;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During a brief trip to Los Angeles I was able to get out for one evening and was extremely lucky to make this photograph. I had digitally scouted quite a few areas around the city having only been there once before, finally deciding to shoot the Walt Disney Concert Hall after shooting the sunset from another location. I walked around a bit finally deciding to shoot from this angle. I fired off a test exposure, and made a few adjustments. In the middle of this exposure a police officer rode up telling me that there were no tripods allowed and I had to either shoot handheld or leave the premises. I heard the shutter click while I was talking to him so I quietly hit the remote one last time before he rode off, but I had to pack up my gear and leave which I was rather cross about. I could (well should have) taken some exposures from across the street but I was tired and hungry so I packed it in and headed back to the hotel. Looking back at the three shots I got I was delighted that the older couple taking a cell phone shot of the building stayed still for just the right amount of time. You can tell that they are all dressed up, the gentleman was wearing a very nice hat and suit, the woman in a wonderful dress. Contrasted against the angular and sharp building it made for a very nice overall composition. I am irritated that I couldn&#39;t spend more time on the property, but I do like what I was able to get.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/catalog/0K6A9996.jpg&quot;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My final three exposures were all taken in one day, almost on a whim. It had been a few years since I have shot in blizzard conditions and it&#39;s not something I particularly enjoy, but I can&#39;t argue with the results as some of my favorite landscapes are in the snow. Chicago was forecasted to get about a foot of snow over two days, so I thought I might be able to get something, but didn&#39;t have anything particular in mind. My wife sent me out to run some errands right as the storm hit which as it turns out was perfect. I grabbed my camera bag &lt;i&gt;just in case&lt;/i&gt;, but as I got about 2 blocks from home I realized that conditions were absolutely magical for some landscape work. Knowing I didn&#39;t have much time I headed over to Leroy Oakes Forest Preserve which is only a few minutes from my house. Typically it is over-run with portrait photographers doing family shoots, but when the weather gets foul they all disappear. Pulling in my first thought was to shoot a scene I had taken back in 2013, a row of trees leading off into the distance. It wasn&#39;t snowing as heavily back then so I was hoping for something softer and more washed out, which is exactly what I got. Struggling to keep the rain cover on while still accessing the camera I reviewed my first few shots - I knew I was on to something. A slight color temperature adjustment and some sharpening was all that was needed. The rest was mother nature.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/catalog/0K6A1968.jpg&quot;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Turning around and trudging through calf deep snow drifts I looked up to see what, in the summertime is a rather ugly clump of trees, but was now turned into a magnificent scene just fading off into the snowstorm. Every distraction was already taken out of the frame by the blanket of snow on the ground and even more coming down.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/catalog/0K6A1975.jpg&quot;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I kept trying different angles as I made my way closer and closer to the &#39;front&#39; of the outcropping, finally getting what has to be one of my all time favorite shots. The snow was coming down so heavy that everything beyond about 20 or 30 feet was completely washed out. Grabbing a few more frames I headed back to the car, resolving to come back the next time we got socked with snow, which of course we haven&#39;t had a single flurry since.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/catalog/0K6A1986.jpg&quot;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Looking at the timestamps from my last shoot I spent exactly 13 minutes from first frame to last. It was unexpected, rushed, improvised, and wonderfully magical. It was a great way to re-energize me heading into the new year. For most of my landscape work I like to sit on it for a week or so, then if it still catches my eye I make the best frame my desktop to see how it holds up after repeated viewings. If it can survive that I know I am on to something, and the last two shots I keep flip flopping on which I like more. They are holding up a month later, and I think are really going to stand out as some of my best work. Not bad for 13 minutes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Ready for 2017&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I like doing this exercise to keep me excited and get me going more during the colder months. I definitely don&#39;t get out as much when it&#39;s cold and miserable outside, but a little end of the year retrospective always helps the winter blues. Here&#39;s to 2017!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 31 Dec 2016 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
      <link>http://gorilla-studios.com//post/2016/12/31/best-of-2016.html</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">http://gorilla-studios.com//post/2016/12/31/best-of-2016.html</guid>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My Lightroom workflow</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I finally made the jump this fall and switched my photography workflow to Lightroom 5 full-time. Since at least 2003 I was using Bridge + Photoshop which I knew was not the most efficient way to do it, but it was comfortable and I was fast with it. When I first checked out Lightroom a few years ago I couldn&#39;t quite figure out the way to edit my most recent photos on the go while keeping the bulk of my library at home on my archive drives. After some more thinking, and some inspiration from Martin Bailey, I resolved all my issues and took the plunge.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/posts/lightroom-flow.jpg&quot;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Adobe Lightroom 5&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My photo catalog is quickly racing towards 2TB and while it&#39;s certainly not as large as some professionals, it&#39;s still big enough to cause headaches. I can&#39;t fit my catalog on my laptop, and smart previews just weren&#39;t going to cut it. After a little reading and testing I setup a workflow where I could have my cake and eat it too. There is a folder on my laptop called &#39;To Vault&#39; (The Vault is the name of my archive drive). I import all new photos into that folder, using a simple &lt;code&gt;YYYY-MM-DD - Subject&lt;/code&gt; folder structure, then open Lightroom and synchronize the folder which imports them into the catalog. Once I am finished editing the photos locally, I then use the Lightroom interface to physically move the source files to The Vault, which is duplicated to another off-site hard drive monthly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I decided to use Lightroom because I was sick of dealing with maintaining both the source catalog alongside a &#39;final edits&#39; collection which took up even more space. Lightroom is non-destructive meaning it saves all your &#39;edits&#39; in simple xml data files which it then applies to the RAW files when you open them in develop mode, that way the source RAW file isn&#39;t touched and the edits are only a few kb of data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Organization&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My rating system, while completely arbitrary, has served me well. Three stars is my baseline for anything that has the potential to be added to my portfolio, four stars for gallery images, and five stars are for my master portfolio - a set of 18-20 photos that showcase my best work. One and two stars are for family photos and client shoots which stay private excepting for their respective subjects. Using this structure allows me to setup smart galleries where I can quickly find my best work from a given time frame, or other constraint.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have a number of smart collections to keep things organized. A catch folder of anything rated higher than 1 in the last 30 days lets me review and edit my &#39;approved&#39; shots over the last month, meaning my last few photo shoots. I also have smart collections for anything rated 3+ for each calendar year which allows me to review and curate a set of best photos from each year. Additionally I like to go back and see if I missed anything, so I use a &#39;Review&#39; collection - setting it as the target collection I can go back and look over photos, tapping &#39;B&#39; to add them quickly so I can take a closer look later.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/posts/2016-3plus.jpg&quot;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;All photos from 2016 rated 3+&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Editing&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Editing photos is much faster than using Photoshop. All the adjustments needed are right at your fingertips and are  specifically designed for photo editing. For most photos all I usually do is set a lens correction, and make some minor tweaks such as exposure adjustments or spot removal. If I have to do any deep cloning or healing I will sometimes export to Photoshop, but that is only because I am still learning how cloning and healing work in Lightroom. A wonderful feature that I use every time is Before &amp;amp; After review pane. You can view both the original and edited views a few different ways to see how much you have changed - definitely not possible in Photoshop.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/posts/lightroom-comparison.jpg&quot;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Developing and comparing to the original&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once I am done editing a photo I can simply go back to grid view. I don&#39;t worry about exporting or saving an edited version unless I need to post on social media or deliver to a client. This keeps me from filling up drive after drive with the original RAW files AND edited versions of each. On export I can embed copyright information and watermarks, as well as constrain the image size by the long edge (very handy).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Overall impressions&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am sincerely impressed with Lightroom and wish I had made the jump sooner. I know I could upgrade to Creative Cloud for a monthly fee, but I don&#39;t like the idea of not being able to use it once I stop paying. Lightroom 5 has all the features I need for my workflow, and while there are a few neat tools in Creative Cloud, there is nothing that makes me want to upgrade any time soon. If you have any questions about how I import, organize, edit, or export my work feel free to &lt;a href=&quot;/about&quot;&gt;contact me&lt;/a&gt;, I&#39;d love to chat.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Dec 2016 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
      <link>http://gorilla-studios.com//post/2016/12/10/lightroom.html</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">http://gorilla-studios.com//post/2016/12/10/lightroom.html</guid>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Leroy Oakes Forest Preserve</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Northern Illinois got it&#39;s first snow of the season when a few inches came down just before lunch yesterday. I hadn&#39;t taken the camera out for a while so I decided to head over to Leroy Oakes Forest Preserve here in St. Charles to see if I could capture some of the magic. It&#39;s a wonderful park just west of the city and while it&#39;s a hot spot for portrait photographers, I discovered years ago that when it&#39;s blanketed in snow there are some perfect spots for minimalist landscapes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I pulled in and sure enough there were a few families brave enough to be doing portrait sessions in the blustery snow. Just past the two barns where most of the portraits are taken is a small one room schoolhouse, Sholes School. Local grade-schoolers get to spend the day there in period costume learning about what it was like living here in Illinois back in the 1800&#39;s - which I myself was lucky enough to do back in second grade.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Paired with my 16-35mm f/4, I stuffed my camera into a rain cover and jumped out of the car to see what I could get as the snow started coming down even harder. No one else was brave enough to face the deepening snow here, so the immediate area was untouched. I captured this frame from underneath a large tree on the walkway leading up to the school building itself.&lt;p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/posts/0K6A1952.jpg&quot;&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is a white fence around the schoolhouse could use some repairs, but I think it adds to the overall charm of the property. In the next shot I was at 16mm so I stood only a few inches from the post in the foreground, the lens distortion made for an interesting composition. I had tried this exact shot years ago at 19mm and just wasn&#39;t happy, but this time around I am really pleased with the results that the extra 3mm gives me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/posts/0K6A1960.jpg&quot;&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another shot I had taken years ago that I was hoping to re-visit was one of a row of trees near the entrance of the park. An access road since removed caused this set of trees to line up straight as an arrow, disappearing into the snowy horizon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/posts/0K6A1968.jpg&quot;&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Just on the other side of the main road stand another two trees leaning towards each other almost as if they are about to hug. I made this photo as the snow continued to pick up its pace, making it very difficult to see what I was doing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/posts/0K6A2009.jpg&quot;&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Visibility was dropping so I decided to turn around and trudge back to the car to see what I had gotten. Fortunately as I turned I realized that the very large bank of trees that normally I would completely ignore were naturally just fading away into the horizon, disappearing into the swirling snow. Captured almost entirely in camera this next photo was only sharpened a touch, thats all. I love how everything just fades out of frame without any after effects.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/catalog/0K6A1995.jpg&quot;&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I kept getting even closer as I tried a few different perspectives, finally taking what is my favorite shot from the day. This was from the very end of the row, while making sure the surrounding trees still faded into the snow.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/catalog/0K6A1986.jpg&quot;&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I love taking minimalist landscapes and while snowstorms are difficult to shoot in, they create some wonderful results. Normally I don&#39;t wish for a lot of snow during the winter, but after yesterday&#39;s outing I am going to be keeping my eye on the weather reports hoping for some big storms.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Dec 2016 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
      <link>http://gorilla-studios.com//post/2016/12/05/leroy-oakes.html</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">http://gorilla-studios.com//post/2016/12/05/leroy-oakes.html</guid>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Star Trails - A Success</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Last month I went out and performed a test run for shooting star trails. It was a wonderful learning experience and despite the full moon along with the clouds rolling in halfway through I felt the end result was a great start.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/posts/star-trails-1.jpg&quot;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Star trails test run&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Taking a few reminder notes I checked the calendar for the next new moon and then kept a close eye on the weather report. When it finally cleared up I grabbed my gear and headed out to a small spot near Kaneville, IL where it looked to be fairly dark with minimal light pollution. Again I knew I wanted Polaris to be close to center of the frame so the stars would spiral around it. It&#39;s been a while since I&#39;ve spotted constellations manually so I decided to use &lt;a href=&quot;https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/skyview-free-explore-universe/id413936865?mt=8&quot; target=&quot;blank&quot;&gt;Skyview Free&lt;/a&gt; to verify I was on target. I decided to try a vertical shot this time, looking over a small lake in the foreground with a tree breaking up the horizon to add some interest. I set my intervalometer for continuous 30 second exposures, grabbed my chair and settled in for an hour and a half of waiting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure class=&quot;vertical&quot;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/catalog/star-trails-2s.jpg&quot;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Star trails second run&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I loved how the sky turned out, Polaris was exactly where I wanted, but I wasn&#39;t in love with the composition. I didn&#39;t get enough reflection in the water as I wanted, and the horizon line was just too cluttered with the tree not standing out how I had imagined it. I chalked it up to another learning experience and started looking at the weather report again.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A week later things were looking good. I had again scoured Google Maps looking for remote locations in the area with a large tree next to a field I could face north while shooting. I had found what looked to be exactly what I wanted out near Maple Park, IL.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/posts/star-trails-location.jpg&quot;&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The next clear night I drove out to my spot and instantly knew I was going to get something special. I couldn&#39;t seem to get a good focus dialed in so I wound up backing my car up and turning on the headlights while pointing at the tree which did the trick. After verifying everything was set I sat down for another hour and a half session, shooting 120 frames for the final stack.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/posts/lightroom-trails.jpg&quot;&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Using Lightroom I adjusted my exposure settings and applied them to all 120 frames and exported them to JPGs. The next step was to remove all the planes streaking by since I didn&#39;t want them in the final print. Thankfully being pretty far out in the suburbs there wasn&#39;t too many frames I had to fix. I had to stack them a few times to catch all the planes, but when I was finished I was extremely pleased I went through the trouble.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/catalog/star-trails-3.jpg&quot;&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The final result was almost exactly what I had in my mind before I even made my first exposure, which is always extremely satisfying as a photographer. An hour and a half made some nice long trails farther outside Polaris, but next time I think I would like to try two or three hours to see how far I can push it. I am definitely in love with this type of astrophotography, and am looking for more opportunities to shoot star trails in different locations as well as during some upcoming meteor showers.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Sep 2016 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <link>http://gorilla-studios.com//post/2016/09/23/star-trails-2.html</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">http://gorilla-studios.com//post/2016/09/23/star-trails-2.html</guid>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Star Trails Test Run</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Last week a number of people started messaging me on the 11th asking if I was going to go out that night and shoot the Perseid Meteor Shower which was forecasted to have the most activity in recent history. I hadn&#39;t planned on it but after humming and hawing for a minute I decided to get my gear together and head out - only to find a large storm front rolling in and the sky completely covered by clouds. Extremely disappointed I decided to try shooting a star trail as soon as it cleared up again. Despite it being a full moon a week later, I went back out. Let&#39;s take a look at my first attempt.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most star trail photos aren&#39;t actually one photograph - they are a series of exposures stacked on top of each other and blended together. Before learning more about it I thought you would need specialized software or a lot of technical know-how to accomplish it, but as it turns out the process is dead simple and only requires Photoshop (there are specialty programs available as well). The benefit of it being a series of continuous exposures is that you are also treated with a nice time-lapse if you shoot for long enough.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My goal was to wind up with both a good still photograph and a short time-lapse video. Shooting with my Canon 5DMkIII + 16-35mm f/4 IS II, each exposure would be 30 seconds at f/4, ISO500 - anything longer and the stars start to blur in each frame (typically its about 20-25s, but at 16mm you have a little flexibility). Shooting for 90 minutes I would get about 7.5 seconds of video (180 exposures / 24fps = 7.5s). That would be enough for a test run to work out any bugs or something I overlooked. Ideally I was hoping to have the north star Polaris in frame so all of the stars would circle around it. In order to track it I downloaded a free iOS app called &lt;a href=&quot;https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/skyview-free-explore-universe/id413936865?mt=8&quot; target=&quot;blank&quot;&gt;Skyview Free&lt;/a&gt; which I cannot recommend enough.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Looking at the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.lightpollutionmap.info&quot; target=&quot;blank&quot;&gt;Light Pollution Map&lt;/a&gt; I could see that I was going to have to head out into the farmlands to get dark enough skies to overcome the full moon. I chose a remote one-lane gravel road between two farms with zero traffic to set up camp. Since the corn was about 7ft high I popped the tripod on the top of my car and dialed in the exposure settings. Once everything was setup I took one exposure with the lens cap on so in post I could identify any hot pixels on the sensor, then grabbed a book and let the camera do its work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A half hour later clouds started rolling in which meant my still frame was going to be much less dramatic than I had hoped for, but with some thunder claps in the other direction I was hoping to get something in the time-lapse, so I let it go for the full 90 minutes. Afterwards I packed up my gear and headed home.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;shot-sheet&quot;&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
  &lt;span&gt;Exposure settings&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br&gt;
  &lt;span&gt;Canon EOS 5D MkIII&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br&gt;
  &lt;span&gt;Canon 16-35 f/4 IS II&lt;/span&gt; - IS Off, Manual Focus&lt;br&gt;
  &lt;span&gt;Shutter speed&lt;/span&gt; 30s - Anything longer and stars start streaking&lt;br&gt;
  &lt;span&gt;Aperture&lt;/span&gt; f/4&lt;br&gt;
  &lt;span&gt;ISO&lt;/span&gt; 500 - Due to the full moon this was low, typically its around 2000 or so&lt;br&gt;
  &lt;span&gt;White Balance&lt;/span&gt; 3000K - If you set it to auto it may shift, then you have to fix it in post.&lt;br&gt;
  &lt;span&gt;Long Exposure Noise Reduction&lt;/span&gt; Off&lt;br&gt;
  &lt;span&gt;Image Preview&lt;/span&gt; Off&lt;br&gt;
  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/posts/image-settings.jpg&quot;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Importing your images and matching the settings (Bridge or Lightroom work just fine)&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I opened up my first frame and made the final tweaks, then exported the settings to the entire batch* (more on this below). Once I had them all exported with the correct settings I opened up Photoshop and clicked &lt;strong&gt;File &amp;gt; Scripts &amp;gt; Load Files into Stack&lt;/strong&gt;. I found my source images, double checked that they were in the right order, and clicked OK.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It should be noted that for the stack I only selected the first 40 or so images to keep the clouds in the bottom left side of the frame before they overtook everything.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/posts/photoshop-stacks.jpg&quot;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Importing your images&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This opens every file as its own layer in a single Photoshop document. Once opened, I selected all the layers and changed the &lt;strong&gt;blend mode to Lighten&lt;/strong&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/posts/layers-to-lighten.jpg&quot;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Change the blend mode to lighten&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While I was delighted to see the stars streaking nicely, to my horror there was a very obvious checkerboard effect over the entirety of the image. It wasn&#39;t on any single image, but as soon as I had two layers visible it appeared.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/posts/checkerboard.jpg&quot;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Checkerboard bug&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;* After some investigation online the effect appears from me applying a crop and slight rotation to each layer during the export process. Each frames adjustment is not pixel perfect which is enough to cause this strange phenomenon. To avoid this do NOT crop or rotate any of the source images before stacking them. Once your image is set and merged down to one layer then you can rotate and crop as needed. Lesson learned.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As I mentioned previously my first and last exposures are with the lens cap on. This is to pickup any &#39;hot pixels&#39; on the sensor - sometimes individual pixels don&#39;t record light correctly and show up as colored spots on the exposure. These would be the same in each frame, so the lens cap shot is my baseline to remove any should they pop up. Thankfully I didn&#39;t have any issues, but it is good practice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Overall I like how the final image turned out. I wish I would have included Polaris in the frame, but that just wasn&#39;t possible from my vantage point. Like David duChemin has said, this was merely a &#39;sketch&#39; of a final image I want to produce at some point. I learned a lot and can&#39;t wait for the next new moon in a week or so.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/posts/star-trails-1.jpg&quot;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Star trails test&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once I wrapped up work on my still frame I grabbed the entire batch of images and went to turn them into a time-lapse video. Now I have done some in the past, and I swear you could do it right in Quicktime, but I wound up using a free Mac utility called &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.panolapse360.com&quot; target=&quot;blank&quot;&gt;Panolapse&lt;/a&gt; The interface is a bit utilitarian but it got the job done. Take a look at the final product.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/Uynzz4wZ1VE&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As you can see the clouds came and covered the entire sky, the flickering on the ground is from when they sporadically covered the moon. I learned a lot and will be much more confident when I go out during the next new moon to capture something really special. Stay tuned and happy star-gazing!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Aug 2016 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <link>http://gorilla-studios.com//post/2016/08/18/star-trails.html</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">http://gorilla-studios.com//post/2016/08/18/star-trails.html</guid>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Arca-Swiss Tripod Mount + L Bracket</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;During my recent trip to Portland the quick release plate on my Manfrotto ball head malfunctioned - the pin that holds the release lever open and ready for the camera to mount seized shut, meaning the latch doesn&#39;t stay open. Im pretty sure the combination of salty air and a small amount of sea water are the culprit. After a few days of hitting it with WD-40 then PB Blaster I had no luck getting the pin to move again.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure class=&quot;vertical&quot;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/posts/IMG_1366.jpg&quot;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Seized quick mount sitting in PB Blaster&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I figured I could use this as an excuse to finally get myself a new Arca-Swiss compatible head and L-bracket, but I wasn&#39;t too excited about replacing the head itself since it was still in excellent condition. After a little bit of searching I found I could simply replace the ball head plate with an adapter, so I settled on a &lt;a target=&quot;blank&quot; href=&quot;http://www.amazon.com/Haoge-CP-58-Arca-Swiss-Compatible-Manfrotto-Replacement/dp/B01CAO7PR4?ie=UTF8&amp;psc=1&amp;redirect=true&amp;ref_=ox_sc_act_title_1&amp;smid=AST9DIMYBFQ3A&quot;&gt;Haoge Combo Boss Adapter&lt;/a&gt;. While it doesn&#39;t have the quick release clamp like the Manfrotto, I find that during shooting I don&#39;t take the camera off tripod enough to make me miss that feature.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/posts/IMG_0012.jpg&quot;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Haoge Combo Boss Adapter&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The adapter itself is very well built, made from a machined aluminum alloy. The adapter simply bolts in place on the top of the ball head, takes about a minute if you take your time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The main reason I wanted to switch over to an Arca-Swiss mount was so I could also get a &lt;a target=&quot;blank&quot; href=&quot;http://www.amazon.com/Fotga-Release-Bracket-Battery-Compat/dp/B01DKEWW8K?ie=UTF8&amp;psc=1&amp;redirect=true&amp;ref_=ox_sc_act_title_2&amp;smid=A1POCZTLJ8H9VM&quot;&gt;Fotga L Plate Bracket&lt;/a&gt; to mount my camera both horizontally and vertically on the tripod. With the normal mount on the bottom of the camera, vertical shots require you to tilt the ball head 90&amp;deg; to the side, which means you lose a good 6&quot; of height. Since I am 6&#39;6&quot; even when the camera is in the normal position I have to crouch a little bit, meaning vertical shots are just flat out awkward for me. With an L bracket I can simply mount the camera on the left side of the body, keeping the eyepiece at a comfortable level.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure class=&quot;vertical&quot;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/posts/IMG_0022.jpg&quot;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Fotga L Plate Bracket&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Fotga bracket is also very well made, designed specifically for the Canon 5DMkIII. The curved aluminum frame feels unobtrusive while shooting hand held and more importantly the design allows access to all the ports as well as the battery tray without having to remove it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/posts/IMG_0020.jpg&quot;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Fotga L Plate Bracket on the horizontal mount&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If I am being honest the thumbscrew on the base plate makes everything feel a bit more secure and tight when the camera is mounted versus the old Manfrotto quick mount. I am still cautious whenever the camera is on the tripod, but I definitely feel a bit more at ease with this setup.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/posts/IMG_0035.jpg&quot;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Fotga L Plate Bracket on the vertical mount&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am very happy with both the Haoge adapter and the Fotga bracket, they fit together perfectly. A great addition to my setup, I am looking forward to being more comfortable shooting landscape panoramas and just having a bit more flexibility with my tripod now.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jun 2016 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <link>http://gorilla-studios.com//gear/2016/06/07/tripod-head.html</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">http://gorilla-studios.com//gear/2016/06/07/tripod-head.html</guid>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Oregon Travelogue</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Last week I flew out to Portland Oregon to attend the WebVisions design conference and while I was there I had some free time to explore. Scouring Google Maps and various online resources I put together a small list of places I wanted to see and things to shoot. On my list were Cannon Beach, Saddle Mountain, Pittock Mansion, and Multnomah Falls. I knew I couldn&#39;t hit them all with my limited time, so I figured I would play it by ear and wait to see what the weather was like when I arrived.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While flying in the captain came over the intercom to say that out the right side would be Mt Adams and Mt Saint Helens, so I was able to grab a quick shot of them before touching down at Portland Airport. Having grown up in the midwest, mountains and large elevation changes are still amazing to me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/posts/0K6A2899.jpg&quot;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Mt Adams and Mt Saint Helens&lt;span&gt;1/500th, f/5, ISO100&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After getting out of the airport and checked into the hotel the forecast looked perfect, so I headed up to Cannon Beach along the coast to see Haystack Rock. Fans of &lt;i&gt;The Goonies&lt;/i&gt; will recognize this as the iconic rock formation just outside Astoria where Mikey holds up the key to learn the location of the entrance to the cave where One Eyed Willie&#39;s ship was.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One amazing feature of Cannon Beach is the tide pools that host a wide variety of wildlife which you can explore at low-tide. I arrived an hour or so before sunset so I had time to soak in the scenery and setup my shot before golden hour began. While walking along the beach I found a huge boulder sticking out of the sand completely covered in mussels and barnacles.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/catalog/0K6A2935.jpg&quot;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Barnacles and mussels&lt;span&gt;1/200th, f/8, ISO200&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One particularly bold seagull was picking mussels off the outcropping while hopping around avoiding the larger waves. I snapped a few photos of him just as he was taking off.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/catalog/0K6A4009.jpg&quot;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Seagull&lt;span&gt;1/6000th, f/4.5, ISO500&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After taking off he headed over to a small set of rocks that were getting pummeled by the waves but he didn&#39;t seem to mind at all, jumping up and down as the water almost swept him away a few times.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/posts/0K6A3759.jpg&quot;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Seagull&lt;span&gt;1/6000th, f/4.5, ISO500&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Inspired by Doran Morgenstern&#39;s work I tried my hand at a few long-exposure pans of the waves to see if I could get some dreamy abstract photos of the early evening sunlight on the ocean water. It&#39;s a shame I don&#39;t live on the coast because I would love to try more work in this style. You can see Doran&#39;s amazing work &lt;a target=&quot;blank&quot; href=&quot;http://www.doranmorgenstern.com&quot;&gt;on his website here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/catalog/0K6A3135.jpg&quot;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Ocean waves&lt;span&gt;0.5s, f/22, ISO50&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/catalog/0K6A3161.jpg&quot;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Ocean waves&lt;span&gt;0.5s, f/22, ISO50&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There were a number of photographers on the beach setting up for different angles for sunset however I was the only one brave enough to get wet. I rolled my jeans up over my knees and firmly planted my tripod about two inches down into the sand. If you don&#39;t firmly seat your tripod the undercurrent will strip sand out from underneath the feet which will ruin your exposure. With my 16-35mm I was able to get in close - at 235 feet tall Haystack Rock took up the right side of the frame with the two large rocks called The Needles setup on the left third. In the foreground was the barnacle covered rock from earlier getting swallowed by the incoming tide. I didn&#39;t notice this particular shot until I saw it on the computer - having the shutter open for 2 seconds the water cascaded over the large rock in the foreground creating some really white streaks over the top and front.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/catalog/0K6A3261.jpg&quot;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Haystack Rock&lt;span&gt;2s, f/22, ISO50&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As the light really started dropping off and I started losing feelings in my toes I decided to get back to dry land. Knowing I already had a number of shots I really liked from in the water I decided to take a few more from a bit farther back until the light was gone. This is one of the last shots of the night, as the light is dying the waves broke over a medium sized group of rocks sending water high into the air as the tide came in.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/catalog/0K6A3334.jpg&quot;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Haystack Rock&lt;span&gt;2.5s, f/18, ISO50&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After being rained out the second evening, the weather cleared up the next afternoon so after the conference I headed east to Multnomah Falls just outside Portland. The photos I had seen made it look like a remote location, however when I got there it was swarming with tourists. As fought for a parking space the skies opened up and dumped a massive amount of rain down almost out of nowhere. I stayed in the car for about 10 minutes until it slowed down to a drizzle, then got out my rain gear and headed out. Thankfully the rain drove a lot of tourists away so when I walked up to the base of the falls there were only a few intrepid (and soaking wet) people left.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the base of a cliff, the Multnomah falls are split into two main sections, combined they reach over 600&#39; straight up, quite a wondrous sight. Shooting all the way open at 16mm I could have gone from the base to the top however the sky was an ugly gray, so I zoomed in a touch to just below the horizon. Adding a variable ND filter I was able to open the shutter up for about 1-2 seconds each time depending on if the sun was peeking through or not. This shot is from when the sun was completely covered, casting a soft light over the entire area.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure class=&quot;vertical&quot;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/catalog/0K6A3635.jpg&quot;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Multnomah Falls&lt;span&gt;1.6s, f/22, ISO50&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I shot for a while with the 16-35mm and was happy with what I was seeing, so I decided to try the 70-200mm and get in close to the water. At this point the wind was picking up so just about every shot was blurred from the camera buffeting in the wind. This was the only one that made it, just as the sun broke through the clouds casting a spotlight down on the top of the second portion of the falls.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/catalog/0K6A3623.jpg&quot;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Multnomah Falls&lt;span&gt;0.8s, f/25, ISO50&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The last day&#39;s forecast looked like I had a 50/50 chance of being rained out and since I had a limited amount of time left I decided I had to try, so I packed up and headed up to Saddle Mountain. The drive out was nice and clear, however when the road started getting higher in elevation the rain started in again. After reaching the base of the mountain it wasn&#39;t too bad so I decided to give it a try. I didn&#39;t get more than 1/4 mile in when it started getting too dangerous to try alone while carrying a bunch of camera gear. The trail was very narrow and slick so I figured instead of risking my safety I would come back some day when I could properly do the hike.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/posts/0K6A3408.jpg&quot;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Saddle Mountain&lt;span&gt;1/200th, f/4, ISO3000&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Saddle Mountain was not too far Cannon Beach so I decided to head down to the coast and see if conditions improved at all, if they hadn&#39;t I read of a few places that served some wonderful clam chowder so win/win either way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I had arrived it was a complete 180&amp;deg; from Saddle Mountain. On the coast it was in the upper 70s and not a cloud in the sky. People were everywhere so I took some candid photos of a woman&#39;s black lab as it sprinted in and out of the waves, having the time of its life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/catalog/0K6A3916.jpg&quot;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Playing in the surf&lt;span&gt;1/1600th, f/2.8, ISO200&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Having gotten some amazing shots of Haystack Rock a few nights before, I wanted some closer shots of the waves breaking over The Needles. With the variable ND filter on my 70-200mm I was able to slow my shutter down to about 1/4th of a second, capturing a bit of motion without over exposing the shot. I love the colors of the ocean here, lots of turquoise and blues, much different from my first visit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/catalog/0K6A3894.jpg&quot;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Haystack Rock&lt;span&gt;1/4th, f/32, ISO50&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The evenings sunset was a bit less dramatic than before, however it was serene and calming, so I took some long exposures looking Southward from the other side of Haystack. I had attempted to shoot some panoramas but with the waves in different positions between frames it&#39;s proving to be extra difficult stitching them together, lots of work to be done. Here&#39;s one of the final shots from my last night in Oregon, I hope to bring the family next time and see even more of the coast.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/catalog/0K6A4219.jpg&quot;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Haystack Rock&lt;span&gt;4s, f/22, ISO50&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 May 2016 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <link>http://gorilla-studios.com//blog/2016/05/28/portland.html</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">http://gorilla-studios.com//blog/2016/05/28/portland.html</guid>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>London Travelogue</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This past week I flew over to London for work and while I was there I had a few nights to go out and explore a bit. I fly out of O&#39;Hare airport and knowing this I have a good idea as to what the flight path will be. With this knowledge I try to get a window seat on the side of the plane that will present the best opportunities to me on both takeoff or landing. Monday this forethought paid off.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;O&#39;Hare is located just north west of Chicago proper so a lot of eastbound flights pass either right over the city or just to the north. The flight took off and just seconds after getting airborne I was treated with a wonderful view of the city being bathed in a warm afternoon light. Shooting out of airplane windows is usually a toss up, so getting anything is a miracle. I fired off a bunch of shots as we passed overhead, but I like this one the most.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/posts/0K6A1328.jpg&quot;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Chicago skyline&lt;span&gt;1/320th, f/8, ISO500&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While coming into London I was absentmindedly shooting some Hyperlapse videos as we were getting close to landing. The plane banked hard making the sun popped out over the wing, blinding me for a few seconds. When we leveled back out and I could see again I recognized that we were going to pass right over the heart of the city on approach. I scrambled and grabbed my camera out of my bag and started firing off more shots hoping to get something similar to when we took off. Unfortunately the window was polarizing pretty bad, so all the shots I took had a very significant color shift over the entire frame. Despite this I had fun with one I took looking straight down at the London Eye over the Thames river. The only way to make this even close to presentable was to convert it to black and white which I really didn&#39;t want to do, so I figured why not have some fun and make it a tilt-shift as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/posts/0K6A1377.jpg&quot;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;London tilt-shift&lt;span&gt;1/200th, f/4, ISO125&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After work I ran back to my hotel because it was raining very heavily and crashed after having some dinner. Unfortunately due to jetlag I woke up around 10:30, fully awake, so I decided to go for a brief walk since the storms had passed. Since it was around 11pm on a Tuesday night the city was virtually empty. Typically after magic-hour at sunset I pack it in and don&#39;t shoot when the sky is completely black, but I wanted to use the limited time I had so I went ahead and tried to get what I could. I took a few exposures but wasn&#39;t thrilled until a young couple came over the bridge headed towards me, suddenly pausing at the apex to share a long kiss. I made a 25 second exposure which was just enough to get them during their embrace with a little motion between the two.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/catalog/0K6A1402.jpg&quot;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;St. Pauls and Jubilee Bridge&lt;span&gt;f/8, 90s, ISO50&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A few exposures later I felt I wanted to try another angle, so I walked down to the south end of the bridge where the walkway switches back on itself presenting some interesting lines. From this angle we get multiple layers in the composition - the dark night sky and great dome, the top level of the bridge and railings, a brief glimpse at the river with the brilliant colors reflecting on the water, and finally the lower walkway. This is a definite example of stepping outside of my comfort zone as I usually prefer very simple compositions and a limited color palette.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/catalog/0K6A1411.jpg&quot;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;St. Pauls from Jubilee Bridge&lt;span&gt;f/8, 30s, ISO50&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Continuing down to the river walk this next frame is from just east of the bridge. Previously I had tried this angle that was zoomed in tight to the dome with a small piece of the bridge in the foreground but I wasn&#39;t thrilled with it. This night I wanted to capture a wider view since the colors reflecting off the river were very vibrant against the deep purple sky.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/catalog/0K6A1416.jpg&quot;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;St. Pauls and Jubilee Bridge&lt;span&gt;f/8, 90s, ISO50&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I followed the river walk down to More London Riverside, located right by Tower Bridge and city hall. My goal was to re-shoot a photo I had taken during the day last time that I knew I could improve upon. There is a small walkway leading towards city hall with a number of interesting buildings that a lot of people would pay no attention to. On my last trip I looked up and took a photo of one of them at 19mm, not thinking much of it until I saw it in post when I got home.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This time I could use my 16-35 f/4 wide open and get even more of the surrounding buildings, and shooting at night I wouldn&#39;t have a completely blown out sky. I collapsed my tripod all the way down and laid on the ground looking almost completely up - the security guard had a good chuckle but didn&#39;t bother me since I was the only one there. I love how this one turned out, especially after running it through Silver Efex Pro. Note - if you haven&#39;t heard, Google just released the entire NIK Collection for free, so go &lt;a href=&quot;#&quot;&gt;download them now&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/catalog/0K6A1420.jpg&quot;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;More London Riverside&lt;span&gt;f/8, 32s ISO50&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On my last trip while shooting this area I focused primarily on Tower Bridge, getting some amazing panoramas. Knowing I already had those in my portfolio I tried to take some more interesting and unique photos of City Hall and &#39;the scoop&#39;, an interesting public space that hosts art installations and various presentations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/catalog/0K6A1426.jpg&quot;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;City Hall&lt;span&gt;f/9, 30s ISO50&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After work the next day I headed down towards Jubilee Gardens at the foot of the London Eye. While waiting for the sun to set I took some different angles of the ferris wheel pods, did some people watching, and mainly just relaxed a little bit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/catalog/0K6A1442.jpg&quot;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;The London Eye&lt;span&gt;1/200th, f/6.3, ISO250&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I sat down on and set up my tripod to shoot wide open at 16mm an interesting angle that I hadn&#39;t seen before of the Eye and Elizabeth Tower in the background with these unique trees in the foreground. With a slow enough shutter speed I was hoping to get blurs of people walking around, so I attached a variable ND filter, slowing my exposures down to around 2-4 seconds each. Suddenly the sky over Elizabeth Tower lit up with vibrant pinks and purples, so I captured this photo before scrambling to get my 70-200mm out for some close ups.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/catalog/0K6A1542.jpg&quot;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;London Eye at sunset&lt;span&gt;4s, f/9, ISO50&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I hoped that the whole sky would light up, but it was limited to the cloud cover down river from me. So I swapped in my 70-200mm 2.8, took my camera off the tripod, and went in close on Elizabeth Tower. I knew I only had a minute or two of perfect lighting so I had to find the right composition and fast. I wanted to be in tight on the tower with the beautiful sunset behind, but I also wanted some interesting people in the foreground as well as a little bit of the London Eye on the left side of the frame.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure class=&quot;vertical&quot;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/catalog/0K6A1546.jpg&quot;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Elizabeth Tower at sunset&lt;span&gt;1/160th, f/2.8, ISO1000&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Just as I had expected the color show had faded within minutes, so I packed up and headed over to the Golden Jubilee footbridge for another viewpoint from over the river. It was difficult to get a sharp exposure from the bridge as trains were rumbling past every few minutes, but I was able to figure out the timing and continue working. As I was putting together a four shot panorama a party boat passed directly underneath me creating a wonderful light trail leading right back into the center of the frame. This shot is the four frames stitched together, each around 90 seconds long.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/catalog/london-eye-2016-pano.jpg&quot;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Downtown London from Golden Jubilee Bridge&lt;span&gt;90s, f/8, ISO50&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I only had two nights to go out, but I tried to get what I could. Next time I go back I want to shoot more street photography and non-touristy locations. Looking forward to my next trip whenever that may be.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Apr 2016 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <link>http://gorilla-studios.com//blog/2016/04/01/london.html</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">http://gorilla-studios.com//blog/2016/04/01/london.html</guid>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building a custom time-lapse slider</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I have been sketching out ideas for a custom built time-lapse slider for probably years now, so when I opened up an Arduino Uno on Christmas day I realized its time to get on with it and put something together. It should be a straight forward build, as it&#39;s only comprised of a few components: a set of rails for the camera to slide on, a stepper motor to move the dolly the camera will be on, a shutter release, and a controller to coordinate the shutter release and camera movement.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/posts/slider-notes.jpg&quot;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;My initial sketch and brain dump&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The goal of this build is to have something simple I can shoot basic time-lapses with, nothing more than that. It&#39;s a learning exercise. Could I go drop $2000 on a pro-grade rig and be out shooting this weekend? Sure, but where is the fun in that? No, it won&#39;t have a rotating ball head, or carbon fiber components, but it also doesn&#39;t have the massive price tag. I think I can complete this build with about $100 worth of parts. So lets get started.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With daytime time-lapses you don&#39;t need to worry about alternating movement and capture as the shutter speeds will be so fast it won&#39;t impact the exposure, however I want to shoot sunrises, sunsets, and at night which means exposures of 15-30 seconds each, so movement during exposure is a no-go. Thats where the Arduino comes in. The Arduino will alternate between opening the shutter for a set amount of time, then shifting the camera while the shutter is closed between shots.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first step is wiring up the shutter release to the Arduino board so in essence it can talk to the camera.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/posts/remote-prototype.jpg&quot;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Breadboarding the shutter controls&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I took my old Canon RS-80 shutter release cable and removed the plastic housing around the button to reveal it&#39;s simply 3 wires attached to metal reeds. When you depress the button two reeds come into contact activating the AF, and when all three touch it completes the circuit, activating the shutter. For time-lapses I always use manual focus, so I can ignore one wire right off the bat. That means all I have to do is plug the two wires into a breadboard and use the Arduino to complete the circuit. I plugged everything in and wrote a quick script to open the shutter for 1 second, close it, wait a second, and repeat.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/posts/uno-program-1.jpg&quot;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Arduino code - getting started&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I pushed the program over to the Uno and the camera started taking 1 second exposures every 2 seconds. It&#39;s not much, but it&#39;s a great start. Next up is wiring up the stepper motor and alternating between activating it and opening the shutter. The &lt;a target=&quot;blank&quot; href=&quot;https://brainy-bits.com/shop/new/nema-17-stepper-motor/&quot;&gt;stepper motor&lt;/a&gt; is on the way, so I&#39;ll be working on this in the next week or so. I&#39;ll be giving periodic updates as everything comes together, and when I am done I will provide a parts list and instructions. Here&#39;s a rough list of tasks to complete and using the Agile mindset from work these are my epics to hit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;input type=&quot;checkbox&quot; checked=&quot;checked&quot;&gt;Get Arduino to control shutter&lt;/input&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;input type=&quot;checkbox&quot;&gt;Get Arduino to control stepper motor&lt;/input&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;input type=&quot;checkbox&quot;&gt;Arduino shield to enable shutter speed variable definition in the field&lt;/input&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;input type=&quot;checkbox&quot;&gt;Build actual slider and camera mount&lt;/input&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;input type=&quot;checkbox&quot;&gt;Calculate stepper motor rotations for full range of movemnt&lt;/input&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;input type=&quot;checkbox&quot;&gt;Reed switches for either end to act as stoppers&lt;/input&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;input type=&quot;checkbox&quot;&gt;Program Arduino for variable shutter speed input, slider speed, and reed stops to limit movement&lt;/input&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;input type=&quot;checkbox&quot;&gt;Power source?&lt;/input&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;input type=&quot;checkbox&quot;&gt;Wire up PCB and build Arduino enclosure&lt;/input&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;input type=&quot;checkbox&quot;&gt;Test&lt;/input&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Stay tuned&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Jan 2016 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
      <link>http://gorilla-studios.com//blog/2016/01/20/slider-project-1.html</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">http://gorilla-studios.com//blog/2016/01/20/slider-project-1.html</guid>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My top 10 images of 2015</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;After dragging my feet for a long time I decided that 2016 would be the year I took the plunge and switched my workflow over to Adobe Lightroom. Inspired by Martin Bailey&#39;s Photography Blogcast, I kicked things off by following a yearly tradition where he goes through and shares his top 10 images from the last calendar year. This is an amazing exercise in how to trim down your body of work to showcase only your very best. I highly recommend listening to the &lt;a target=&quot;blank&quot; href=&quot;http://www.martinbaileyphotography.com/2016/01/04/my-personal-top-ten-photos-for-2015-podcast-504/&quot;&gt;episode where he explains this process in detail&lt;/a&gt;, it&#39;s a must for every photographer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lightroom allows you to set a &#39;target&#39; collection so when you are in grid view you can simply tap the B key and add the selected photo into that collection. I started by filtering my entire library to only show shots in 2015 with a rating of 3 stars or higher. Then, going through with an editors mindset I started filling up my &#39;2015 Candidates&#39; collection. After my first pass I was around 45 photos which wasn&#39;t too bad. I switched over to view the collection and started removing the ones that didn&#39;t wow me. A few passes later I was down to about 20 which is where it starts getting difficult. Martin Bailey talks about editing photos which most people confuse with post-processing. Editing your photos means selecting which ones to display and which ones to shelve. Other photographers stress being ruthless in this process and often use the term &#39;killing your babies&#39;, which doesn&#39;t sit well with me. The main point is not to become emotionally attached to a photo that might not be as strong as you think.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/posts/lightroom.jpg&quot;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Getting organized with Lightroom&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So lets take a look at, in my opinion, my best work of the 2015 calendar year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first shot I selected was actually intended to be a temporary scouting photo to be re-taken over the summer. In early March I took the L to Adams &amp;amp; Wabash, where I quietly setup my tripod on the overpass between the tracks, looking North towards Trump tower. My goal was to get the trains streaking past in both directions, but it was so cold I didn&#39;t stay for very long. This particular exposure was 15 seconds, f/8, at ISO100.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/catalog/over-the-l.jpg&quot;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Adams &amp;amp; Wabash&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In May I took my second trip to London and while I was there I had a small amount of free time to re-capture some images I wasn&#39;t happy with from my first visit. One evening I headed down to the Queen Elizabeth Bridge at sunset and took a series of long exposures of the London Eye over the Thames River. During this shot a tourist boat made its way down river leaving a wonderful light trail along the water. 60 seconds, f/9, ISO50.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/catalog/london-eye-2015.jpg&quot;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;The London Eye&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Back in Chicago over the summer I picked up a small commission project for some black &amp;amp; white abstract architectural photos for an art dealer in Canada. I spent a few afternoons walking around the Loop and trying some new techniques as I hadn&#39;t really done much abstract work before. My favorite shot from the set was taken from the base of Trump tower in its loading dock on the North side of the building, where very few pedestrians venture. Looking up at a slight angle created almost a layered look from the base, midsection, and main body of the tower. Taken at 1/500th, f/9, ISO100.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/catalog/trump-abstract.jpg&quot;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Trump Tower Chicago&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In August I headed downstate to shoot the Bigfoot Bandcamp where a large number of acts performed, my favorite of which were The Krank Daddies and Reverent Horton Heat. I selected three photos from the evening, starting with probably the most Rock n Roll photo I have taken - Chops McClintock of The Krank Daddies taking a second in the middle of a song to pound a beer. It was a really high energy set, and this frame captures the essence of it in all its glory. 1/250th, f/2.8, ISO2500.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure class=&quot;vertical&quot;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/bfbc/0K6A4393.jpg&quot;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;The Krank Daddies&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Reverend Horton Heat is a band that I had wanted to see for a very long time, so the fact that I got to shoot them at the same time was really exciting for me. It was a smaller festival so being right up against the stage gave me a lot of reach to get the Rev full frame. I usually hate having a mic in front of a singers face, but here it doesn&#39;t bother me so much as you can just tell he&#39;s in the moment singing and playing his big ol&#39; Gretsch guitar. 1/250th, f/2.8, ISO4000.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/bfbc/0K6A4708.jpg&quot;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Reverend Horton Heat&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During concerts I move around as much as possible to cover every angle the best I can. Sometimes being 6&#39;6&quot; is a hinderance when I am trying to be low-key shooting, but I can&#39;t help sticking out like a sore thumb sometimes - here it worked out in my favor. I was side stage towards the end of their set when Jimbo glanced in my direction as I was the only one over there. I raised my camera with the 70-200mm 2.8 on it which makes it really obvious I&#39;m taking your photo. When I did he looked straight down the barrel, threw up the horns, and then went straight back to playing. It was literally a second or two, but I got it, and I knew as soon as I released the shutter that it was probably the best shot of the night. I didn&#39;t even have to review the shot, I just kept on going until they wrapped up. 1/250th, f/2.8, ISO8000.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure class=&quot;vertical&quot;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/bfbc/0K6A4923.jpg&quot;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Jimbo - Reverend Horton Heat&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In November I found myself flying out to Los Angeles for a work event, but I was able to sneak up to Leo Carillo State Beach one evening and shoot a Pacific ocean sunset for the first time in my life. I was only there for maybe an hour and found it really challenging to keep the camera steady in the surf as the sands kept shifting, but I got a few shots I am happy with. I would really love to go back and spend more time there and a few other locations on the coast, but I am glad I got a few shots in during my brief stay. The first shot is of a few very large boulders as the waves slid up and down the beach. To give some perspective, the speck on top of the one closest to center is a seagull. 1.3 seconds, f/6.3, ISO1250.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/catalog/0K6A0772.jpg&quot;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Leo Carillo Beach&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The second shot from that night was not planned at all. When shooting landscapes I usually try to avoid man-made objects and keep them natural as possible, however as I was walking back to the car with soaked jeans I passed a life guard tower silhouetted against the fading sunset. The colors were brilliant so I set up my tripod again and made a few more exposures until the light was completely gone. 30 seconds, f/4, ISO100.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/catalog/0K6A0789.jpg&quot;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Leo Carillo Beach&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally in the middle of December I flew out to New York for a few days, staying in Carol Gardens in Brooklyn, a short walk from Brooklyn Bridge Park, one of my favorite spots. Having never shot a sunrise in Manhattan before I decided to get up at the break of dawn to lug my gear to a familiar spot along the river. With sunsets you usually get at least 30 to 45 minutes of great lighting, but I found with the sunrise I only had about 10. It went from almost pitch black to close to daylight seemingly in the blink of an eye. Thankfully I was set up and framed before the dramatic change in lighting so I got this exposure looking out over the river to the southern tip of Manhattan. 48 seconds, f/8, ISO50.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/catalog/0K6A7702.jpg&quot;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Manhattan skyline from Brooklyn&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My final selection of 2015 is actually a three shot panorama of One World Trade Center taken from North Cove Yacht Harbor along the Hudson River. I had shot nine frames here, but I am still struggling to get the buildings align correctly. The center stack of 3 merged well, although I would like to head over to the New Jersey side of the river and try to get One WTC with a long lens instead of being almost underneath it at 16mm. I still love the results here, the contrast is wonderful and I love how the clouds are moving by at quite a fast pace. 3 exposures of 30 seconds, f/8, ISO50.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure class=&quot;vertical&quot;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/catalog/one-wtc-bw-pano.jpg&quot;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;One World Trade Center&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thanks for reading, and Happy 2016 everyone!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Jan 2016 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
      <link>http://gorilla-studios.com//blog/2016/01/15/best-of-2015.html</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">http://gorilla-studios.com//blog/2016/01/15/best-of-2015.html</guid>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
