<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Gorilla-Studios Photography</title>
    <description>Gorilla-Studios Photography</description>
    <link>http://www.gorilla-studios.com/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://www.gorilla-studios.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
      <item>
        <title>Week 30 - Millenium Park Busts</title>
        <description>&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/p52/30.jpg&quot;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Head Sculptures, Millenium Park&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This week I headed back down to Millenium Park in the heart of the Loop to check out
a new art installation just across the pavilion from The Bean. Artist Jaume Plensa has
created four female heads ranging from twenty-one to thirty-nine feet hight, yet only a
few feet wide. You can&#39;t tell from this perspective, but they have been skewed so as you walk from
where the photo was taken down towards them you quickly realize they are very thin. It&#39;s
quite an optical illusion and draws a large crowd. These three are located just east of
Crown Fountain, while the largest of the four is right on Michigan Ave at the entrance to
the park.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I had a difficult time shooting because the lighting just wasn&#39;t there. It was getting
very dark and I had hoped to pick up the buildings in the background, but the foreground
lighting just wasn&#39;t enough to balance the exposure. This is one of the earlier shots from
before sunset. I brightened up the trees to almost an infra-red like photo to create some
contrast. I am definitely going to go back to see what other kinds of photos I can get,
it really is something to check out if you are in the Loop.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 28 Jul 2014 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://www.gorilla-studios.com/2014/07/28/photo52-week30/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.gorilla-studios.com/2014/07/28/photo52-week30/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Week 29 - Archways</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;A few months ago while working at a client&#39;s office downtown, I used to go for walks at lunch
to explore the neighborhood and one day stumbled across Mary Bartelme Park. Located just west of the
loop it&#39;s a wonderful park with a playground, dog play area, and on the west end, a very interesting
piece of art. A series of five steel or aluminum archways at various angles stand about 12 ft square,
and are equipped with nozzles that spray a fine mist of water to cool off patrons during the hot
Chicago summers. While there I snapped a few photos with my iPhone and told myself to come back at some
point to shoot with my SLR. A few nights ago I finally got the chance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As I always say preparation goes a long way so I wanted to get there before sundown to set everything
up and make sure I had my composition locked in. I wanted to shoot very low to exaggerate the angles of
the arches, so I set my Manfrotto as low as it would go with the neck flipped at a 90 degree angle, the bottom of the camera only a few inches off
the pavement.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/posts/arch-prep.jpg&quot;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Preparation is key&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As the sun finally settled below the horizon and the lights came up, the sky faded to a beautiful purple
blue hue with a touch of pink to the south. The ideal lighting was only around for about fifteen to twenty
minutes so I knew I had to get something relatively quickly. I loved the colors of the shots I was taking,
but it was really lacking something. I had expected the water to be misting from the arches, however when
anyone tried to turn it on nothing happened. I&#39;m not sure where the idea came from, but I thought this would
be the perfect opportunity to try some light painting - problem was I don&#39;t carry a flashlight in my day pack.
Undeterred, I set the camera to a 10 second timer, turned on my iPhone flashlight, and proceeded to walk back and forth
waiving it with the flashlight towards the camera. My first exposure was just arcs headed from back to front -
not as dramatic as I was hoping for, but the light was showing up crystal clear. I fired off another ten
exposures or so, wildly waving my arm and running back and forth each time (what a workout). I
eventually got exactly what I wanted - windmilling the phone like Pete Townshend while slowly walking towards
the camera created this weeks photo. Probably the most unique and fun photo I have ever taken.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/portfolio/archways.jpg&quot;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Archways&lt;span&gt;30s, f/8, ISO200&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 22 Jul 2014 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://www.gorilla-studios.com/2014/07/22/photo52-week29/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.gorilla-studios.com/2014/07/22/photo52-week29/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Week 28 - Sears Tower</title>
        <description>&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/portfolio/blue-sky-walk.jpg&quot;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;July 14th - Sears Tower skyboxes&lt;span&gt;1/400, f/9, ISO100&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;No matter what I do I can&#39;t stop taking photos of the Sears Tower, I&#39;ve probably surpassed the thousand mark a while ago.
It doesn&#39;t help that I work just a few blocks from it, and on some days I like to go for a walk during lunch with my camera.
I&#39;ve said before that I love taking photos of it because you can get dramatically different shots from all angles of the
building. I wanted to see if I had enough reach at 200mm to see people in the skyboxes that jut out from the west side of
the tower over Wacker Drive. This particular angle was from the north west corner on the pedestrian island out front. I
particularly like that you can&#39;t instantly figure out what you are looking at, and its certainly not a photo of the Sears I
have seen before. There is a very subtle lens flare from the afternoon sun taking up the right side of the exposure, but I
feel it adds a bit of warmth and character.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 17 Jul 2014 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://www.gorilla-studios.com/2014/07/17/photo52-week28/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.gorilla-studios.com/2014/07/17/photo52-week28/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Prints for sale</title>
        <description>&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/posts/for-sale.jpg&quot;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Select prints are available from 500px.com&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am pleased to announce that select prints from my portfolio are now &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.500pxart.com/gorilla-studios&quot;&gt;available for purchase at 500px.com&lt;/a&gt;. Eight beautiful photographs
are currently available in various sizes on framed paper, canvas wrap, aluminum, or acrylic. You can see them &lt;a href=&quot;/store/&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; or at
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.500pxart.com/gorilla-studios&quot;&gt;500px.com&lt;/a&gt;.  More photos will be added in the future so keep an eye out, or you can always request a print to become available.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 16 Jul 2014 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://www.gorilla-studios.com/2014/07/16/prints-for-sale/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.gorilla-studios.com/2014/07/16/prints-for-sale/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Week 27 - Fireworks</title>
        <description>&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/p52/27.jpg&quot;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;July 5th - Fireworks with the family&lt;span&gt;5s, f/5.6, ISO1000&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I already wrote a long post about my 4th of July weekend, so I want to keep this one brief. I selected another shot
from our family fireworks display in Indiana as my photo of the week. This is very close to what I had in mind when I
setup my tripod - I wanted a wide shot with the fireworks going off from in back of the house with a few people in frame
if possible. On my full-frame 5D MkIII at 19mm I was just shy of capturing the entire ark, but I love the overall exposure.
Great evening with the family.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 05 Jul 2014 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://www.gorilla-studios.com/2014/07/05/Fireworks/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.gorilla-studios.com/2014/07/05/Fireworks/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Fourth Of July</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Another great 4th of July is now in the books. My wife and I were again lucky enough to watch the Chicago fireworks over Navy Pier from a high rise on Lake Shore Drive. It&#39;s a large building of condominiums with a private deck on the 35th floor - a perfect place to watch the show. I took a few exposures during magic hour to get everything set, that way all I had to worry about was exposure time. I found ISO 100 was too low, so I quickly bumped it to 400 at f/10, shooting bursts between 5 and 10 seconds. This was very early in the show, because the smoke quickly got overwhelming and headed straight towards us.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/posts/navy-pier-fireworks-14.jpg&quot;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;July 4th - Fireworks over Navy Pier&lt;span&gt;7s, f/10, ISO400&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After the Navy Pier fireworks were over we were treated to an amazing view out west - we got to see all the west side and suburban fireworks, dozens of them all going off at once, from horizon to horizon. I can only imagine what the view would have been like from an airplane or helicopter. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/posts/fireworks-west.jpg&quot;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;July 4th - Looking west&lt;span&gt;10s, f/10, ISO400&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The next day we drove down to Indiana for a relaxing weekend with the family. After a day at the beach and lots of grilled food, we pulled out the fireworks for a personal show in the back yard. It was tricky as I wasn&#39;t sure exactly where they would go off, or how long they would go for, so I was again in Bulb mode, essentially guessing my exposures each time. A few rain drops on the lens added some fun distortion to some of the photos, and I think this was my favorite.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/posts/indiana-fireworks.jpg&quot;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;July 5th - Fireworks at home&lt;span&gt;4.8s, f/5.6, ISO1000&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After the large ones were shot off it was time for some roman candles and a little fun for the kids. Here is a prime example of almost exactly what I had in my mind working out as planned...with a lot of hard work. When I saw the first one lit I knew I wanted one of the kids faces light up by the firework from coming out of their hand, problem was it was almost pitch black so I had to manually focus while they were lighting the first few off. Once I locked in focus I had to time a 1/30th second shot right after the sparks shot out and briefly light the scene. It took quite a few attempts but I finally captured this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/posts/roman-candle.jpg&quot;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;July 5th - Roman Candle&lt;span&gt;1/30th, f/22, ISO6400&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I absolutely love this photo, but the feeling of showing her parents that shot was even better. That&#39;s what I love about candid portraiture, capturing that special moment that takes someones breath away when they see it. We had quite a few moments like that this weekend, but this one still makes me smile every time I see it. Happy 4th of July everyone.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 05 Jul 2014 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://www.gorilla-studios.com/2014/07/05/4th-of-July/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.gorilla-studios.com/2014/07/05/4th-of-July/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Week 26 - Bald Eagle</title>
        <description>&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/adult-bald-eagle.jpg&quot;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;June 29th - Adult Bald Eagle&lt;span&gt;1/320, f/4.5, ISO100&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Taking a break from cityscapes and architecture, this week I packed up my gear and headed back out into nature. A friend and I
went out for a morning shoot around the Fox River with no particular goal in mind, however we chanced upon two fisherman who told
us that some bald eagles had nested north of us in Mooseheart, where the juveniles were getting ready to fly for the first time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Arriving at the location it was obvious where the nest was. Bald eagles have the largest nest size of any bird in North America,
or possibly anywhere period. I estimate it was probably a good 8-10 feet around, and equally as deep. The juvenile bald eagle is a
very dark brown with a few white feathers poking out at various spots on their body. Their heads are not white, nor are their beaks
yellow until adulthood, which is at about 5 years old or so. It was very difficult to get any clean photos of the juveniles since
the pine tree was fairly thick.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After a few minutes of watching them we noticed an adult in an adjacent tree staring at us very closely. There is very little
difference between the male and females, the only distinct difference being size - the females tend to be about 25% larger than the
males. Judging by the size I presume this was the father. He hopped around a little bit when we spotted him presumably to watch us
closer, but didn&#39;t move apart from that. I took this with a 70-200mm 2.8, and this is a 100% crop which tells you how high up he was.
I shouldn&#39;t be surprised, but I was taken aback at how good their eyesight was. On exposure after exposure you could plainly see they
were watching us extremely closely - constantly looking right down the barrel of the lens. These are truly majestic creatures and I
hope to get a chance to photograph them flying and feeding at the river.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 29 Jun 2014 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://www.gorilla-studios.com/2014/06/29/bald-eagles/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.gorilla-studios.com/2014/06/29/bald-eagles/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Week 25 - Manhattan</title>
        <description>&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/p52/25.jpg&quot;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;June 19th - Manhattan&lt;span&gt;80s, f/9, ISO400&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This weeks Photo52 challenge was, obviously, taken during my &lt;a href=&quot;/2014/06/23/NYC/&quot;&gt;trip to NYC&lt;/a&gt; last weekend. This shot was from the first night down in Brooklyn, just across from the southern tip of Manhattan. Brooklyn Bridge Park is a gorgeous location on the west side of Brooklyn overlooking the river and there are so many great locations for shooting the skyline. This location is on the far south of the park, where there is a dilapidated boat launch surrounded by these wooden posts poking out of the water. I knew if I could open the shutter long enough to smooth out the water it would be a great effect. As the sun dipped below the horizon there were some really ugly clouds that took up the right side of the sky, but at the last minute they finally cleared. I had a 2 stop neutral density filter on a Canon 16-35mm f/2.8 wide angle lens, and was exposing for 2-4 minutes each.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This particular exposure was taken at 80 seconds and since it was at f/9 the streetlights on the horizon didn&#39;t turn into giant starbursts like they would at lower f-stops. The composition is probably my favorite part of this - the wooden posts and clouds all lead you right into the center and right side of the frame where One World Trade Center is standing tall. I was hoping to get the Statue of Liberty in the left side of the frame, but there was a large open air sports complex off camera left jutting out into the river that blocked her. Hopefully I can go back and explore NYC again soon, there is so much to capture and nowhere near enough time.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 27 Jun 2014 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://www.gorilla-studios.com/2014/06/27/photo52-week25/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.gorilla-studios.com/2014/06/27/photo52-week25/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Weekend in New York</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;This past weekend I had the opportunity to travel to NYC for Generate Conference, a Web Design gathering in the heart of Manhattan. Of course I jumped at the chance and spent all my free time exploring the city with my new 5D MkIII. After a long weekend I am exhausted but heading home with full memory cards and some beautiful shots to add to my portfolio.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Day 1 - Thursday&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thursday I packed my bags, picked up a Canon 16-35mm 2.8 from &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.lensrentals.com&quot;&gt;LensRentals.com&lt;/a&gt; and headed off to O&#39;Hare. I got in and surprisingly breezed through security I decided to trek over to Terminal 1 to take some shots of the tunnel of lights that connect the two parts of the terminal. There are two long moving walkways on either side but unfortunately one of them had big ugly construction gates on each entrance so shooting from either end was out of the question. I quietly setup my tripod and walked around a bit finding my angle, finally settling midway down the second set looking the long way back. I took an exposure of 1s at f/7.1, ISO2000 which captured enough light while blurring out the passengers enough to create some interest in the foreground. I have always loved coming down here since I was a little kid, so it was a real treat to get it on film for once.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/posts/ohare-tunnel.jpg&quot;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;June 19th - O&#39;Hare&lt;span&gt;1s, f/7.1, ISO2000&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once boarded I made sure my bag was below the seat in front of me and not above so I could grab my camera at any point. Knowing Chicago like the back of my hand and having a good guess of where the flight path was, I was fairly sure that we were going to pass along the north side of Chicago right after takeoff. Thankfully I was on the right side of the plane in a window seat so I was in the perfect position to grab whatever I could get. Sure enough right after takeoff we were cruising over the far north side, so I fired off a couple shots as the city came out from under the wing. I only had a window of a second or two because we started flying into some heavy clouds which obscured our view. Its always tough shooting out airplane windows and this was no exception. The haze from the glass was pretty bad, as well as the overall fog. After this shot things got really choppy so I had to put away the camera and try to stay calm.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/posts/takeoff.jpg&quot;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;June 19th - Chicago Skyline&lt;span&gt;1/250, f/8, ISO100&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The flight finally calmed down and I got into La Guardia, making my way to the hotel by mid-day. I was a little worn out but I didn&#39;t want to waste any time so I hopped the A train down to Brooklyn Bridge Park on the Brooklyn side of the river. From the park there are a large number of really beautiful views of one of my favorite pieces of architecture (seriously, I just finished reading &lt;i&gt;The Great Bridge&lt;/i&gt; by David McCullough), so I walked around about an hour before sunset scouting where I was going to shoot during magic hour. I went south to a location I had seen on Google Maps where there were a bunch of pylons in the water which I thought could make for an interesting foreground during a long exposure. To minimize the impact of the clouds that were rolling in I added a 2 stop ND filter to make my exposures even longer, finally settling on 4 minutes at f/11. I wish the sky was clearer, but I still really like this one.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/posts/manhattan.jpg&quot;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;June 19th - Manhattan Skyline&lt;span&gt;240s, f/11, ISO50&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Even though it was quite late and the lighting wasn&#39;t that good I wanted to scout another location while I was down there, so I headed north of the bridge, finding a great location on a boardwalk area at the very tip of the park. Looking back I made this exposure of 90 seconds at f/16. The sky is granier than I like but its still a beautiful image that I want to see in print. After getting up and out the door by 6:30, travelling all day and lugging my camera gear all over New York, it was close to 11 so it was finally time to head back to the hotel.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/posts/brooklyn-bridge-dark.jpg&quot;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;June 19th - Brooklyn Bridge&lt;span&gt;90s, f/16, ISO100&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Day 2 - Friday&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Friday was spent at the conference which was a lot of fun, but afterwards I wasn&#39;t up for the typical after conference bar crawl. I made my way over to Grand Central Station to check out the great hall there, but I quickly realized it was an absolute zoo. I am usually okay in crowds but this place was over the top. There was zero chance of setting up a tripod with all the pushing and shoving, so I made some hand-stabilized shots from a balcony. Of the 10 or 15 shots I attempted only two or three  were clear. I was shooting around 2-4 seconds each but was really struggling with anything longer than three seconds. After about 5 minutes I&#39;d had enough, I was out of there!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure class=&#39;vertical&#39;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/portfolio/grand-central-standing.jpg&quot;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;June 20th - Grand Central Terminal&lt;span&gt;3.2s, f/11, ISO100&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I didn&#39;t want to push myself too hard so I meandered around Midtown and checked out the scenery, eventually taking a stab at the famous New York slice of pizza. First place I tried looked okay, but was a dud, strike one. After a disappointing early dinner I rounded the corner to find myself right by the Chrysler building, one of Manhattan&#39;s crown jewels. I felt I was a little too close but shot a few frames to be sure, and was actually impressed with this shot when I converted it to black and white.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure class=&#39;vertical&#39;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/posts/chrysler2.jpg&quot;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;June 20th - Chrysler Building&lt;span&gt;1/200, f/8, ISO100&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some more wandering and I finally decided to head back to Brooklyn since the weather was much more cooperative. This time I got closer to the bridge, settling in at the best spot on the boardwalk just north of the bridge. There were about five photographers to my right and more over my left shoulder. This time the clouds added just a touch of drama to the shot, the lighting was amazing, creating almost a spotlight effect behind One World Trade Center, and I even got a party boat going upriver adding extra lights streaking across the frame. Certainly one of my favorite shots in recent history.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/portfolio/brooklyn-bridge-blue.jpg&quot;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;June 20th - Brooklyn Bridge&lt;span&gt;90s, f/16, ISO50&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Day 3 - Saturday&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By Saturday my feet and shoulders were telling me to slow down since I had lugged my camera gear all over Manhattan the past two days, so I stayed around Central Park. Grabbing some doughnuts I had a lovely breakfast down by Sheeps Meadow then wandered up to Strawberry Fields, the memorial just across from the Dakota Building where John Lennon was shot. As always it is surrounded by very inconsiderate tourists so taking a clean shot of the tiled &#39;IMAGINE&#39; is tricky. I watched a performer sing a few Beatles songs, finally tipping him after a great rendition of Here Comes The Sun, and snuck over to the circle. Nobody seemed to notice the mid-size stick that was laying over the G and I, or they just didn&#39;t care, but its small details like that that drive me nuts. Most people kneel down and give the peace sign while someone else takes their picture, so there are only split second windows where you can take an un-obstructed shot. I snuck in and grabbed the stick, throwing it into the grass, and had to patiently wait for my window. The area is covered by trees and the sun was beaming down creating a tricky shooting environment. I finally got this one between the gawking tourists. This shot I had wanted to re-take ever since my first trip to NYC when I got it with a point and shoot sometime around 2003, so needless to say I was a bit relieved.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/posts/imagine.jpg&quot;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;June 21st - Strawberry Fields&lt;span&gt;1/40th, f/8, ISO100&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once the sun started setting it was time for another shot I had planned long before coming to NY. I had wanted to take a dusk shot at the Flatiron Building at 5th Avenue and Broadway for a very long time. I scouted the shot and picked my location then headed off for another New York slice - trying 2 Brothers Pizza on 24th and was not disappointed. I grabbed two 1$ slices and headed back to Madison Square Park to eat and wait for sundown. I got my camera setup and started taking some test exposures, honing in my composition and making sure everything was ready to go, only to realize to my dismay that the Flatiron doesn&#39;t light up at night. There are a lot of things you can plan for, but sometimes its just not in the cards. I did manage to take this shot of the traffic zooming by, and while its a good shot, its rather flat and gray. I guess thats as close as I will get to a true nighttime shot of one of my favorite NY icons.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/portfolio/flatiron-horiz.jpg&quot;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;June 21st - Flat Iron Building&lt;span&gt;42s, f/13, ISO50&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As I headed back to the hotel I decided to stop back at the 5th Ave Apple store. This is one very tricky
exposure at night - you have to open the shutter long enough to get details in the foreground and surrounding
buildings but not blow out the Apple logo in the cube. I finally landed on an exposure around a third of a
second at f/11, ISO1600. This was taken at a very low angle, I was sitting on the sidewalk right next to a
hot dog vendor with my tripod completely collapsed. I kind of assumed the police officer was going to shoo me
along since I was sitting there for the better part of an hour, but he was incredibly friendly and didn&#39;t seem
to have any issues with me being there.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/posts/apple.jpg&quot;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;June 21st - 5th Ave Apple Store&lt;span&gt;0.3s, f/11, ISO1600&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Day 4 - Sunday&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By Sunday I was almost ready to drop, but I wanted to meet up with some family that lived in the city now that our schedules lined up. After brunch I started walking around Lexington and the mid-50&#39;s when I stumbled upon a wonderful building that was almost circular, completely glass and absolutely fascinating. I took some photos and was kind of standing around just admiring the architecture when an Audi pulled up and parked (after almost hitting me) and the driver proceeded to tell me that it was private property and there was no photography allowed. The key in any of these situations is to remain calm and determine what your rights are at that time. I was on public property, and I calmly informed him of that. He insisted that there was no photography, to which I asked if he was the building owner, building security or NYPD. He mumbled something and started walking away, again almost yelling that there was no photography allowed. I raised my voice a bit but calmly told him that I wasn&#39;t taking photos of him, and if he wanted to take it up with the police I was more than happy to speak to them. He kept walking, finally disappearing around a corner. I turned around to find a doorman looking at me sheepishly. I kept shooting and he just smiled at me, it was the second time I have been yelled at when taking pictures, and of course the other time was again in New York, back in 2003. Anyway, I finished up some more shots and finally made my way back to the hotel, then off to the airport.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure class=&#39;vertical&#39;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/posts/fight.jpg&quot;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;June 22nd - Altercation&lt;span&gt;1/40th, f/8, ISO100&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We were delayed coming out of LaGuardia but as we took off and banked around I spotted Manhattan out the window and scrambled to get out the camera. Unfortunately I was experimenting with some time-lapse work in the airport and had left it in JPEG mode. I quickly switched into Shutter Priority and dropped it to 1/60th, just a vague guess at something that was hand-holdable, slow enough to get some light in and yet fast enough not to blur as the plane moved. I snapped a few frames and noticed some bad glare coming from the cabin lights so I had to quickly try to shield as much of the window as I could. You can see from Central Park at the bottom of the frame all the way up to the Statue of Liberty which is the far right speck of light just above (in frame) Manhattan proper. It&#39;s not going to win any awards, but it&#39;s a great way to say goodbye to NYC.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure class=&#39;vertical&#39;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/posts/nyc-night.jpg&quot;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;June 22nd - NYC Flyover&lt;span&gt;1/60th, f/2.8, ISO12800&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The trip was a lot of fun and I was able to get some amazing photographs thanks to all the planning I did beforehand. I scoured Google Maps, Google Streetview, and Google Earth looking for some unique places to shoot from, which really paid off. I still have more shots to process and take a closer look at later, but for now it&#39;s back to the day job.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 23 Jun 2014 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://www.gorilla-studios.com/2014/06/23/NYC/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.gorilla-studios.com/2014/06/23/NYC/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Week 24 - Union Station</title>
        <description>&lt;figure class=&#39;vertical&#39;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/black-white/columns.jpg&quot;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;June 16th - Union Station&lt;span&gt;1/30, f/8, ISO160&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since I have found it difficult to keep up with the Photo52 project over the past few weeks I have been using my iPhone to try to get at least a photo a day. In doing so I have been exploring a few tools to really see what I can capture with it. Until recently I haven&#39;t been blown away by anything other than the convenience of having it in my pocket at all times. I have started using &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.instagram.com/gorillastudios&quot;&gt;Instagram&lt;/a&gt; quite a bit, which originally I hadn&#39;t cared for all that much. Instagram has released a new version of the app with better editing controls, really expanding (at least in my opinion) what it can do. I also purchased an app called &lt;a href=&quot;http://vsco.co/vscocam&quot;&gt;VSCOcam&lt;/a&gt; which I am very pleased with (more on those later). One thing I have found in using my iPhone every day is that its a great scouting tool to let me almost &#39;sketch&#39; out ideas for shots before returning with my SLR. That is exactly what happened this week.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since I commute into the city each day I get to see a lot of beautiful architecture, and of course every day I get to walk through Union Station. The Great Hall is gorgeous, but there are some interesting spots outside the building as well. This photograph is looking south from the east exit of the main building. If you turn facing north there is a big ugly view of a CVS sign through the archway, so I prefer this angle. The lines can be tricky, however scouting the day before helped me get the shot I wanted very quickly.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 16 Jun 2014 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://www.gorilla-studios.com/2014/06/16/photo52-week24/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.gorilla-studios.com/2014/06/16/photo52-week24/</guid>
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
