<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Gorilla-Studios Photography</title>
    <description>Gorilla-Studios Photography</description>
    <link>http://www.gorilla-studios.com/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://www.gorilla-studios.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
      <item>
        <title>Map Room, Chicago</title>
        <description>&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/map-room.jpg&quot;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Map Room, Chicago&lt;span&gt;1/125, f/5.0, ISO1000&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 30 May 2014 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://www.gorilla-studios.com/2014/05/30/map-room/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.gorilla-studios.com/2014/05/30/map-room/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Week 22 - Chicago Sunset</title>
        <description>&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/chicago/sunrays.jpg&quot;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;May 29th - Chicago Sunset&lt;span&gt;1/160, f/8, ISO50&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well, after a long hiatus I am finally back into the swing of things. Lately we have been getting some spectacular sunsets here in Chicago so I decided to head out and see what I could get on a very windy Thursday afternoon. I picked up a Divvy bike just around the corner from my office and headed down to the lake. To say it was windy is an understatement. It was close to 70 in the afternoon, but after a half hour I was uncomfortably cold. Not much really grabbed me as there was a pretty thick haze over the city, so I grabbed another Divvy and peddled my way around the Field Museum campus just to kill some time before sundown. A side note, I now consider a Divvy key fob to be an essential part of any Chicago-based photographers toolkit. Instead of lugging my gear all over the loop I was able to just pull a bike and head to where I want with very little effort.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After circling Solider Field and the Shedd Aquarium I braved the bitter wind and went back down to the lake by the Adler Planetarium, one of the best spots in the city to see the skyline. The haze started to part, but when the sun started dipping below the buildings it ducked down right behind 311 S. Wacker to create these beautiful sunbeams casting past the Sears Tower and right over the lake. I wanted to get in tight so I switched to my 55-200mm and shot that wide open at 55. I love the sun bursting out from the buildings, the silhouette of the skyline is much different than most shots with all of the lights on. I like how this one turned out.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 29 May 2014 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://www.gorilla-studios.com/2014/05/29/photo52-week22/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.gorilla-studios.com/2014/05/29/photo52-week22/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Canon 70-300mm IS L</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I was lucky enough to get my hands on a Canon 70-300mm IS L lens to play around with, and I had to share my initial impressions. I took a quick trip down to Navy Pier to play around with it and see how it handles in the field. The lens is all metal, so it is incredibly sturdy weighing in above 2 pounds. On a Black Rapid strap I didn&#39;t feel much fatigue letting it hang at my side, but shooting with it certainly gave my arms a good workout. While I wasn&#39;t blown over by the AF performance I was taken aback at how sharp the images came right out of the camera. I wanted to share two specific photos.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/seagull.jpg&quot;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Cawing Seagull&lt;span&gt;1/160, f/8.0, ISO125&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This noisy guy was hovering around the few tourists, trying to get scraps of food from wherever he could find it. I snapped this photo at 300mm (this is a 100% crop). I couldn&#39;t believe the detail on the birds beak, incredibly sharp.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/seagull-2.jpg&quot;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Seagull Portrait&lt;span&gt;1/160, f/6.3, ISO100&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here was another portrait shot of a seagull that was perched on a railing, again shot at 300mm. The texture around the eye was what makes this photo pop. Incredible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have the lens for another few days so I want to run it through its paces some more, and when I do I&#39;ll share some more photos.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 24 Apr 2014 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://www.gorilla-studios.com/2014/04/24/canon-70-300-L/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.gorilla-studios.com/2014/04/24/canon-70-300-L/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Spring on Lake Michigan</title>
        <description>&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/lighthouse-spring.jpg&quot;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Chicago Harbor Light&lt;span&gt;1/250, f/5.0, ISO100&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 23 Apr 2014 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://www.gorilla-studios.com/2014/04/23/spring-on-lake-michigan/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.gorilla-studios.com/2014/04/23/spring-on-lake-michigan/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The Exposure Triangle</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;This past Friday I gave a 5 minute lightning talk at my work about the basics of photography and how you can get out of Auto mode. Instead of sharing the slides I want to expand on the talk I gave and write something more substantial. With entry level DSLRs becoming very affordable these days lots of amateur photographers are entering the market having never touched a film SLR, and generally have a very rough understanding of camera fundamentals.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are three basic settings on the camera that are crucial to every photograph - photographers commonly refer to this as the Exposure Triangle. Every photograph is a balance of three settings - &lt;strong&gt;ISO, Aperture, &amp;amp; Shutter Speed&lt;/strong&gt; - and I want to talk about each one and how they affect each other.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;ISO&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Simply put, ISO is how sensitive the camera&#39;s sensor is to light. If you&#39;re old enough to remember buying film you might recall that it had an ISO rating between 50 to about 1600 give or take. With modern DSLRs it can range from 50 to 100,000+. Having the camera on a low ISO setting, say 100, will produce crisp noise-free images, but it will not be very sensitive to light. Setting the camera to a high ISO, say 25,600, will make it much more sensitive to light allowing faster shutter speeds, the images will have noticeable noise.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/iso-example.jpg&quot;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;(left)ISO 50 - (right)ISO 25,600&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here are two examples from real world shooting. On the left is a photo I took of a Great Blue Heron grooming itself one morning. I was shooting directly into the sun (not recommended at all) so I needed to drop my ISO down to 50 and raise my shutter speed to 1/4000th so I wouldn&#39;t blow out the image. The example is cropped but the original is sharp and almost completely noise free. On the right is a photo I took while shooting the Everly Hillbillies in concert. It was very dark and the drummer was poorly lit so I needed to raise my ISO to 25,600 to get enough light while opening the shutter for 1/200th of a second and you&#39;ll notice the image is extremely noisy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Aperture&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Think of Aperture like the iris of your eye - it is simply the adjustable size of the lens opening. This controls how much light comes through the lens to the sensor, as well as affecting depth of field. One thing students get caught up on is the terminology of how aperture is measured, in f stops. High apertures are when the lens allows the most light through, and conversely low apertures let the least light through. The confusing part is that high apertures are smaller numbers, and low apertures are high numbers. Lets take a look at two examples.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/aperture-example.jpg&quot;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;(left)High Aperture f/2.8 - (right)Low Aperture f/16&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the left is a Macro image taken at a very high aperture - f/2.8. For this shot the lens opening was as wide as it could go, allowing as much light as possible into the camera. This also created an extremely shallow depth of field (extremely exaggerated since it is a macro shot). The right image was taken at a very low aperture, f/16, letting very little light into the camera but getting almost everything in focus, from a few feet in front of the camera all the way to the horizon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Shutter Speed&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is probably the easiest to understand and causes so many headaches for inexperienced photographers. Shutter speed is simply how long the cameras sensor is exposed to the light coming in through the lens. When you press the shutter button the mirror allowing you to see through the lens from the eyepiece springs upward and the shutter curtain snaps open and then closed almost instantly. Shutter speed is measured in fractions of a second, usually between 1/4000th of a second, down to multiple second (or minute) exposures.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/shutter-example.jpg&quot;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;(left)Slow shutter 1/4th - (right)High shutter 1/2000th&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Slow shutter speeds usually cause blurry and shaky images if not done properly. However if you use a tripod (or an very steady hand) you can create some interesting effects when slowing the shutter speed down. On the left is a shot of a London double decker bus passing in front of Elizabeth Tower. Using a monopod I slowed my shutter down to a quarter of a second to make sure the bus was blurred out, yet it was fast enough to hold steady so the tower itself was still sharp. In order to freeze motion you need a higher shutter speed. On the right is a shot of birds flying into my parents bird bath. They were flitting about extremely quickly so I had to set the camera to 1/2000th of a second in order to even come close to freezing the motion. You can see they were so fast that the wings were still blurred out even at that speed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A good rule of thumb for shutter speed while hand held is it should never be slower than the focal length. I.e at 50mm lens should not be hand held for exposures under 1/50th, 200mm no less than 1/200th.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;How the triangle works&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Each setting impacts the other two so finding a balance between the three is critical to any exposure. If an exposure is too dark you can try to slow your shutter speed down, increase your ISO, or open up your aperture. If you want a longer depth of field you need to close down your aperture, but increase your shutter speed or ISO to compensate. If you don&#39;t understand how each side of the triangle works and how it impacts the others then practice until you do. This is the foundation of photography and having a working understanding of them is of the utmost importance. We&#39;ll dive deeper into all three in later posts, but until then, keep practicing!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 06 Mar 2014 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://www.gorilla-studios.com/2014/03/06/photo101-getting-out-of-auto/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.gorilla-studios.com/2014/03/06/photo101-getting-out-of-auto/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Week 8 - Chicago By Train</title>
        <description>&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/p52/08.jpg&quot;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;February 24th - Chicago By Train&lt;span&gt;1/100, f/16, ISO100&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have been taking a series of photos during my morning commute into the city from the train, and this weeks entry is my favorite from the past few days. While very similar to Week 1, this time I decided to slow my shutter speed down to introduce some motion blur in the foreground while keeping the subject and background sharp. After pulling the photo into Lightroom it looks like I panned from left to right to keep the water tower in frame, dragging the exposure a bit - the consequence of this is that the water tower is sharp, the foreground is extremely blurred, and the background is just barely blurred. This panning technique is used by photographers to keep very fast moving subjects in focus while blurring out the background, emphasizing motion.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 24 Feb 2014 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://www.gorilla-studios.com/2014/02/24/photo52-week8/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.gorilla-studios.com/2014/02/24/photo52-week8/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Week 7 - Snowy Bean</title>
        <description>&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/p52/07.jpg&quot;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;February 17th - The Bean&lt;span&gt;1/250, f/5, ISO160&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I love to take photos nobody else has or would, which means putting myself through some uncomfortable situations at times. When another 5-8 inches of snow was forecast I saw a great opportunity to capture something unique while most sane people were bundled up at home. Leaving work and heading down to Millenium Park I got blasted in the face with snow no matter which direction I walked making me almost throw in the towel a few times. Since I don&#39;t have a weather cover I had to keep my camera tucked up underneath my coat while not shooting to keep the camera relatively dry and the lens clear. I quickly pulled the camera out when I found these two people were the only ones having fun underneath the sculpture, snapping this exposure as the woman reached out to touch it. I really love the sense of scale - the silhouette effect really adds to the sense of how large the sculpture really is.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 17 Feb 2014 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://www.gorilla-studios.com/2014/02/17/photo52-week7/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.gorilla-studios.com/2014/02/17/photo52-week7/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Week 6 - Bald Eagle</title>
        <description>&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/p52/06.jpg&quot;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;February 9th - Juvenile Bald Eagle&lt;span&gt;1/2000, f/6, ISO2000&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My trek in week 6 was spent along the frozen banks of the Fox River in Montgomery, IL. Bald Eagles have made a reappearance along the Fox in recent years, coming to town in January and February feeding along the exposed areas of the river. Although we were close, shooting with the Canon 100-400mm lens was tough. I could have easily used another 200mm to get in tighter. During the morning the adult eagles were few and far between although flew overhead a few times, it was mostly the juveniles out feeding.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 09 Feb 2014 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://www.gorilla-studios.com/2014/02/09/photo52-week6/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.gorilla-studios.com/2014/02/09/photo52-week6/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Week 5 - Pritzker Pavilion</title>
        <description>&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/p52/05.jpg&quot;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;January 29th - Pritzker Pavilion&lt;span&gt;10s, f/9, ISO50&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another chilly evening in Chicago, but this time I went down to Millenium Park. While there are ropes around Pritzker Pavilion I didn&#39;t feel too bad stepping over since there were already tracks through the snow and the security guard by the Bean seemed pretty engrossed in his smartphone. I jogged out to the center of the field and snapped a few shots trying to frame the bandshell, Aon Tower and the overhead beams as carefully as I could. I love the colors and how sharp this photo turned out. Worth getting a boot-full of snow.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 29 Jan 2014 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://www.gorilla-studios.com/2014/01/29/photo52-week5/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.gorilla-studios.com/2014/01/29/photo52-week5/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Week 4 - Wrigley Building</title>
        <description>&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/p52/04.jpg&quot;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;January 24th - Wrigley Building&lt;span&gt;13s, f/10, ISO50&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While trying to determine my next lens purchase I decided to rent Canon&#39;s 17-40mm f/4 wide-angle zoom lens this week to test it out in the field. I went for an extremely cold walk along the Chicago River and around Michigan Ave getting a feel how it performs. It did great wide open at 17mm and was tack sharp at f/10 with no noticeable issues. I would love to try something in the neighborhood of 14mm, but this is a great general purpose wide-angle. This was my favorite from the walk this week - the river was frozen over and the lights were just starting to come on as the sun disappeared behind the camera. Its tough shooting so wide because of the vertical distortion from the buildings, but if you keep that in mind while shooting you can give yourself some room to fix in post.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 24 Jan 2014 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://www.gorilla-studios.com/2014/01/24/photo52-week4/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.gorilla-studios.com/2014/01/24/photo52-week4/</guid>
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
