<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Gorilla-Studios Photography</title>
    <description>Focusing on stunning landscape and high-energy music photography, Gorilla-Studios has been the online home of my portfolio since 2003. I specialize in landscapes, cityscapes and architecture, nature, candid portraiture, headshots, band promos and concert photography.
</description>
    <link>http://localhost:4000/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Sun, 07 Mar 2021 17:19:21 -0600</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 07 Mar 2021 17:19:21 -0600</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.8.5</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Competition vs Creativity</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Not making images for yourself, making them to be judged&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;External forces steering your photography, not your heart.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;how many likes is enough&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;discouragement&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 31 Jan 2021 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/blog/2021/01/31/competition.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/blog/2021/01/31/competition.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>blog</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Comet NEOWISE</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;The past few weeks have been rather exciting for the astrophotography community with the appearance of Comet NEOWISE (named after the space telescope that spotted it, the Near-Earth Object Wide-field Infrared Survey Explorer). It is a beautiful comet that can be seen by the naked eye in dark enough conditions. For a few weeks it's only been up in the early morning hours, but recently we've been able to see it from about 9:30 to 11:30pm here in the Chicago suburbs. I got a chance to head out last night and see if I could photograph this rare comet myself. While it will be visible until mid-August, after that you'll have to wait another 6000 years or so to see it again. I figured I didn't want to wait that long...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I packed up my gear - a 16-35mm, 50mm, 70-200mm, and my 11&quot; Schmidtt-Cassegrain Telescope for an extreme closeup, loaded it all in the car and headed out at sunset. I drove over to a local forest preserve and was delighted to find the small parking lot full already with a number of families out with binoculars ready for the evenings show. While I was getting everything setup and the scope aligned there were a few cloud bands but nothing significant. At around 9:40 people started spotting it with binoculars. My eyes are so bad I couldn't see it yet, so I took the camera off the telescope and started with some wide shots at 70mm to get honed in.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While I was dialing in my focus a car came by really slowly and was shining their lights at the group, a few of us were about to yell or say something, but it slowly turned around and we saw the back of the SUV said POLICE. Patience is a virtue.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Zooming in close at 200mm I flipped the camera to a vertical orientation and captured this shot. This is only a single exposure at 8s since I was on my tripod and not the CGEM mount as a practice run. I plan on going out in the next few nights to get tracked shots so I can create a composite and really get some details from the tail.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure class=&quot;vertical&quot;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/posts/0K6A3151.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Comet NEOWISE&quot;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;NEOWISE&lt;span&gt;200mm&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As it got darker I wanted to get a few wide shots before moving back over to the big 11&quot; SCT. I opened the camera up to 70mm and started taking exposures between 10 and 30 seconds. Since they were un-guided on a basic tripod they weren't super sharp, however I love the fireflies in the foreground.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/posts/0K6A3248.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Comet NEOWISE&quot;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;NEOWISE and fireflies &lt;span&gt;70mm&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After some wide shots I wanted to see what it looked like through my Celestron Ultima 11&quot;. I mounted the camera back on and tried to slew to the comet, but really struggled. I've never tried to find something that wasn't already in the hand controller, and I didn't easily find a way to manually enter coordinates. After a little bit of frustration I took the camera off the scope, setup the tripod directly behind it with the 70-200mm lens essentially over the telescope, and got NEOWISE aligned dead center. Once it was centered on the camera I slewed the telescope blindly to bring it into alignment with the 70-200mm lens. I re-mounted the SLR on the scope and after a minor adjustment was right on the comet. However, it being 11&quot; even with the f/6.3 reducer on the back, it was still way over-powered.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Its a wonderful closeup but if I am going to stack 50 shots, I want the whole tail in frame as well. Here's a single exposure closeup of the comet head itself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/posts/0K6A3210.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Comet NEOWISE&quot;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;NEOWISE closeup through an 11&quot; SCT&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was a wonderful evening despite the mosquitoes, and a good test-run. I should get some much sharper images by mounting my 70-200mm directly on the CGEM mount itself, and I also plan on taking out my old 600-1000mm lens to see if I can get something from that. Its f/8 wide open if I recall correctly, so it's going to be tough.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Be sure to checkout NEOWISE in the early evenings between now and mid-August. A good pair of binoculars should be all you need - to find it, look Northwest and you'll see the Big Dipper. Follow that down to the horizon, and NEOWISE should be about 20 degrees up (about two fists at arms length, one on top of the other). Take your time, and if it is a good dark evening you might be able to spot it without binoculars. Clear skies!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jul 2020 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/astrophotography/2020/07/17/neowise.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/astrophotography/2020/07/17/neowise.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>astrophotography</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>ISS Transit</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;One of my favorite things to do with the telescope is to chase and photograph the International Space Station, and catching it transiting the moon is a fun challenge that I don't get to try too often. &lt;a href=&quot;#&quot; target=&quot;blank&quot;&gt;My last attempt&lt;/a&gt; was all the way back in December of 2018. Needless to say I was excited when I noticed that I had an opportunity coming up in the next few weeks that was only a few minutes from the house, and even better, my cousin's house was right on the path so I didn't have to worry about where to go.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I packed up my gear the night before so I woudln't forget anything when I headed out the door around 4:15 the next morning. Despite it being so early it was rather bright out getting everything setup. I quickly got the mount tracking, and fine tuned the focus, but after that I had some time to contemplate why I don't drink any coffee.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/posts/IMG_6510.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Setting up the telescope&quot;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Setting up the telescope&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The tranist was set to happen at 05:09:18am, so I pulled up my &lt;a href=&quot;https://apps.apple.com/us/app/skyview-lite/id413936865&quot; target=&quot;blank&quot;&gt;SkyView Lite&lt;/a&gt; app which tracks the station. At 17,500 mph it moves from horizon to horizon within a few minutes, so you have to pay attention. I saw it behind me fast approaching the horizon at 4:56, and knew it would be on the opposite side of the sky within 10 minutes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;vertical&quot;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/posts/iss_tracking_july_2020.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Tracking the stations location&quot;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Tracking the station&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once it rose above the houses it took me about 10 seconds to find it and start tracking visually. I watched it fly overhead, and then downwards towards the moon, letting me hit the shutter just before the transit. Here's a close up single frame as the station passed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/posts/iss_single_frame_july_2020.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Single frame of the ISS lunar transit&quot;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Single frame closeup of the ISS lunar transit&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With my Canon 5D MkIII I was able to get 10 frames. At 45&amp;deg; it wasn't the largest station photo I've taken, but there was still some significant detail. It's always fun to catch the station going by, I highly recommend everyone give it a try.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/posts/iss-flyby-july-20.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;10 frame stack of the ISS lunar transit&quot;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Full 10 frame grab of the transit&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jul 2020 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/astrophotography/2020/07/13/ISS-spotting.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/astrophotography/2020/07/13/ISS-spotting.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>astrophotography</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Chasing the Dragon</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;On May 30th, SpaceX and NASA teamed up to launch astronauts from American soil for the first time since 2011, using the brand new Crew Dragon capsule atop a Falcon 9 rocket. It was an astounding success and while I still have never seen a launch in person at least I got to watch online. Astronomers waste no time tracking rockets in orbit, so almost immediately information about how to see the crew capsule on its way to the ISS started being posted online. A few people recommended &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.heavens-above.com&quot; target=&quot;blank&quot;&gt;Heavens-Above&lt;/a&gt;, from which I was able to discern that it might be visible from the backyard that evening. It was worth a shot and I wasn't going to miss the opportunity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I knew that using my Celestron 11&quot; SCT would be overkill and almost impossible to catch the capsule going by, so I decided to setup a simple 16-35mm and get a trail of it going by. A few neighbors came out and we were watching closely were it was supposed to fly by, but unfortunately we didn't see anything. I locked the camera shutter release down to continuously keep shooting and while I didn't see it go by I did catch it in the lower left side of the frame.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/posts/dragon.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Dragon Capsule&quot;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;The Dragon Capsule&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Despite missing the Dragon capsule I knew the ISS was not far behind, and that is obvious when it goes overhead, so at least we'd be able to see that. Sure enough about 15 minutes later the ISS tracked from the horizon up overhead, delighting everyone watching. It quietly slipped into the Earth's shadow and disappeared just past the zenith.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I wasn't 100% sure about whether or not that was the Dragon going by, but looking at the time stamp, angle, and direction in the sky I can't imagine its anything else. When I stacked everything together you can see the capsule is moving the same direction as the space station as it attempts to catch up to it for docking.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/posts/dragon-and-iss.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Timelapse capturing the Dragon Capsule and ISS&quot;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;The Dragon Capsule and ISS time lapse&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Doug and Bob should be aboard the station for the next few months, so &lt;a href=&quot;https://spotthestation.nasa.gov/&quot; target=&quot;blank&quot;&gt;see if you can spot the ISS going overhead&lt;/a&gt;. Clear skies!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 05 Jun 2020 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/astrophotography/2020/06/05/dragon-chasing.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/astrophotography/2020/06/05/dragon-chasing.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>astrophotography</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>CGEM Firmware Update</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;It's been almost a year since I've done anything with this site, but I am happy to say I am picking my camera and telescope gear back up, blowing off the dust, and putting some more time into the hobby I love so much. Over the past year I welcomed my second daughter to the world, bought my first house, and now  we are keeping to ourselves safe and sound while this whole Covid-19 situation settles down. For the most part it has been a great year and I am looking forward to posting here more often.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Last week the weather started warming up so I got the telescope set up in the back yard for some simple lunar observing, making sure all the gear survived the move and was in good working order. We had a bonfire going and even invited the neighbors over to look at the moon (from a safe distance of course). One of the greatest parts of having a telescope is hearing the reactions of people who've never looked through one. Their 4 year old son was amazed looking at all the craters and detail the 11&quot; Celestron reveals.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My plan was to give the scope a good cleaning, collimate it, and since I had never done it before, update the firmware for both the mount and the StarSense alignment camera. As with all good plans, it never goes how you think it will.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Update headaches&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;TLDR; If you found this looking for help, &lt;a href=&quot;#the-process&quot;&gt;read the step-by-step instructions&lt;/a&gt; down below.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I got the mount upstairs and set it up next to my desk. I then went to Celestron's website and downloaded their firmware manager Java applet, thinking I could just plug the mount in and would be done in a few minutes. I'm not sure why I expected this - I work in the software industry and I know it never is that easy. On top of that, Mac support in the Astronomy/Astrophotography community is lagging very far behind the PC world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I plugged everything in, powered on the mount, and launched the CFM. It downloaded some new packages but it wasn't communicating with the mount. After some initial exploration I realized when I turn the mount on I needed to hold the Celestron button + 7 to access a Boot Loader mode. After that still no luck. I came across a post on Cloudy Nights message board from someone troubleshooting the process on the Mac and they said Serial to USB drivers were needed. I was initially confused because the updated StarSense controller has a mini USB port at the bottom, not the old RJ-11/Serial connector. However after &lt;i&gt;more&lt;/i&gt; research I found out that there is a serial adapter inside the controller. I got the drivers installed and had to do some digging to make sure the mount was actually communicating with my MacBook.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/posts/usb-chain.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;The CGEM listed in the System Profile USB Chain&quot;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;The CGEM listed in the System Profile USB Chain&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Looking at the System Profile I saw it listed there in the USB chain, so I knew it was talking to my Mac. This tells me something isn't configured correctly in the CFM software.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Trying something...&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To test this and verify that I wasn't being fooled by the System Profile I went into Stellarium to see if I could use it to control the mount. I knew it was possible, however I had never tried before. After about a minute of configuration that was painless Stellarium said it successfully was connected to the CGEM. I picked a target in the sky and clicked 'Slew To' and sure enough, the mount started slewing! This is pretty neat, I plan on testing this out in the field over the summer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I still wanted to update the firmware so it was back to Cloudy Nights where I found someone had posted they went to &lt;code&gt;/dev&lt;/code&gt;, grabbed the cu.usbserial listing, and set that to the Serial Port Name in the CFM software.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/posts/correct-port.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Setting the port information in the CFM&quot;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Setting the correct port information in the CFM&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Honestly I wasn't optimistic, but sure enough, the CFM instantly found both the mount and the StarSense controller, however it couldn't update the firmware because it couldn't download the latest packages from software.celestron.com. I went to Celestron's main site and realized the problem...it had crashed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/posts/celestron-crash.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Celestrons website is down&quot;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Celestron's website was down&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well that's some bad timing. I sat there for a half hour, occasionally checking both the main site and the software subdomain with no luck. I threw in the towel and would come back to it tomorrow.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The next day their site seemed to be up and running just fine, so I turned the mount back on and tried again. The CFM connected to the mount, downloaded the packages, and I was able to successfully update the firmware on both the CGEM and the StarSense camera. Success!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;vertical&quot;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/posts/firmware-update.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Successfully updating the firmware&quot;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Firmware update successful&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So now that the CGEM mount and StarSense have the latest firmware it's time to give the OTA a good collimation check, clean everything up, and get it out under the night sky. Clear skies everyone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-process&quot;&gt;TLDR - The Process&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Setup the mount and any accessories, but do not connect the USB cable to the computer.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.celestron.com/pages/drivers-and-software&quot; target=&quot;blank&quot;&gt;Download the CFM java app&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.prolific.com.tw/US/ShowProduct.aspx?p_id=229&amp;pcid=41&quot; target=&quot;blank&quot;&gt;Download the Prolific Serial to USB drivers&lt;/a&gt;, launch, install, and restart. Be careful, certain versions of MacOS may flag it and prevent you from installing unless you allow it in System Preferences &amp;gt; Security &amp;amp; Privacy &amp;gt; General.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;On the hand controller hold the Celestron Button and 7, then power the mount on. The hand controller should say Boot Loader.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Plug the USB cable into your Mac.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Go to About This Mac, click System Report, then under Hardware in the left column, click USB. You should see something like 'USB Serial Controller' listed.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Open the Terminal app and type &lt;code&gt;cd /dev&lt;/code&gt;, press enter, then type &lt;code&gt;ls&lt;/code&gt; and press enter. This will list everything in the dev directory. Look for an entry of &lt;code&gt;cu.usbserialXXXX&lt;/code&gt;. Copy that entry and open up the CFM software. Click Options then Connections. Set the Discovery Mode to manual, then under Default Port Settings paste the line you copied from the Terminal app. Click OK.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;You may need to quit and restart the CFM softare.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Click Seek Devices if it doesn't automatically look for them. At this point it should detect the mount and any accessories you have plugged in. Click Update and it will go through the process of updating the firmware. Do not power them off during this process, I assume it's possible to brick the mount if it doesn't go correctly.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Once everything is finished, compare the firmware versions listed in the window to the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.celestron.com/pages/firmware-update-history&quot; target=&quot;blank&quot;&gt;latest versions listed on Celestron's support site&lt;/a&gt; to make sure you're completely up to date.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 15 May 2020 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/astrophotography/2020/05/15/cgem.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/astrophotography/2020/05/15/cgem.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>astrophotography</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>StarSense Auto Align</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I've been looking into options for improving my polar alignment and tracking during astrophotography, so as a first step I decided to get a Celestron StarSense Auto Align camera. I didn't want to jump all the way to a full auto-guide camera + laptop, so I figured this would be a good solution until my skills improved.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During my initial research I had read a lot of reviews where people were having problems using the StarSense but I had a hunch that a lot of it was just user error. The setup and usage instructions were pretty straight forward so I wasn't too nervous.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The camera arrived in a handsome and well packed box. It comes with a basic RJ-11 (phone jack) cable to connect to the AUX port on any compatible GOTO mount, along with both a large and small mounting plate to fit a variety of optical tubes. It also comes with an updated hand controller for the mount, from what I gather this is where a lot of the processing happens.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/posts/star-sense-box.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Celestron StarSense packaging&quot;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Celestron StarSense packaging&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/posts/star-sense-camera.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Celestron Star Sense Camera&quot;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;The Celestron StarSense camera&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I had to take my optical view finder off the scope to make room for the StarSense. My Ultima 11&quot; was built back in 1994, so I think the accessory mounts on it aren't quite to the current industry standards so I couldn't mount both the StarSense and piggyback mount at the same time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;vertical&quot;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/posts/star-sense-controller.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Celestron StarSense hand controller&quot;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Celestron StarSense hand controller&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The camera needs to be calibrated to the mount the first time you use it, but after that it should automatically align the scope by itself. Celestron has a very straightforward &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=OqqoFZyxzQg&quot; target=&quot;blank&quot;&gt;instructional video&lt;/a&gt; walking you through the process. While I found that to be very helpful, I still had a few stumbles out in the field.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/posts/star-sense-on-ota.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Celestron Star Sense Camera on telescope&quot;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Celestron StarSense mounted on my Ultima 11&quot;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;After the monthly &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.fvasil.org&quot; target=&quot;blank&quot;&gt;Fox Valley Astronomical Society&lt;/a&gt; meeting we setup for some casual observing in the parking lot. I used this opportunity to test out the StarSense to see how it worked. I had some stops and starts with getting everything aligned, but nothing major. I entered the time and date into the controller and let it do its initial scan then tried to calibrate to Sirius only to have it almost 40 degrees off.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I turned off the mount, re-centered it, and noticed that the altitude on my mount was off by almost 10&amp;deg;. Fixed that and tried again, only this time I forgot to enter the time and date, so when it tried to slew to Mars it was pointing pretty much at the ground. Hrmph. I reset everything again, and was extremely careful to follow the alignment and calibration procedure. I told it to auto align and it scanned the sky for about 2 minutes or so. I then selected a star to slew to. Again I chose Sirius and the mount put it almost dead center. I selected calibrate, chose Sirius as the instructions say to calibrate off the last star used, and then got it absolutely dead center in the camera. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After finishing the calibration I tried slewing to another target, this time Arcturus which was rapidly setting. I held my breath as it swung around and then stopped with it bang in the center of the frame. Slew to Capella, same result. Awesome! Now a tough one - The Whirlpool Galaxy. I have wanted to photograph deep sky objects for a long time but haven't had any luck yet. It slewed to where I knew it should be, but obviously it wouldn't show up on the camera until I tried a long exposure. I set it to bulb mode and went for a 60 second exposure right off the bat.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/posts/whirlpool-single.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;The Whirlpool Galaxy&quot;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Single unprocessed frame of the Whirlpool Galaxy&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There it was. Faint, and only a single frame, but I had it dead to rights and I was tracking for at least 60 seconds at ISO 1600. Most brilliant photos of deep sky objects take multiple hours worth of exposures so I still have a long way to go, but I was incredibly happy to take that first step. I took about 10 minutes of exposures and went on to try Bode's Galaxy as well as The Pinwheel Galaxy just to make sure the mount was slewing and tracking well. When I have more time I'll get to spend an evening on one target. I can't wait.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As for the StarSense Auto Align camera, I'm very happy with it. The only problems I had were user errors and that was only during the initial setup. I think it's a bit expensive but it does exactly what it advertises. I plan on using this for the next year or so then next spring upgrading to a ZWO ASI Air + Auto Guide camera to actively track the mount without a laptop. I think the StarSense is very well suited for people who do a lot of visual astronomy, where as those of us who are more astro-imagers are better suited with a guide camera. I'm just not quite there yet, I still have a lot to learn.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Clear skies!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 14 Apr 2019 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/astrophotography/2019/04/14/star-sense.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/astrophotography/2019/04/14/star-sense.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>astrophotography</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Coopers Hawk</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Warning: The following images are slightly graphic, if you feel some nature photos are upsetting then you may want to skip this post&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So last weekend my wife and I were cleaning the house and doing our usual routine when all of a sudden she gasped and told me to look out the back window. She said a giant bird had grabbed a Cardinal and was de-feathering it in the backyard. We've had some large hawks and animals in the back from time to time, but whenever I open the door they always take off so I wasn't optimistic. However I grabbed my camera and eased my way outside still wearing my bathrobe.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As I stepped out on the back stoop the Coopers Hawk was on the back fence madly tearing feathers out of the poor Cardinal and thankfully didn't seem to mind me at all. I snapped a few photos thinking that is all I would get.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/posts/0K6A8638.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;A Coopers Hawk sitting on my backyard fence after grabbing a Northern Cardinal&quot;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Coopers Hawk&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I slowly made my way across the yard when suddenly it hopped off the fence and down into the neighbors backyard. Thankfully the side fence is nothing more than open wire, so I kept inching my way forwards. I was eventually crouching against the fence about 10 feet away. It seems the hawk was more hungry than worried about me so it didn't mind my shutter clicking away.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/posts/0K6A8719.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;A Coopers Hawk picking at the remains of a Northern Cardinal&quot;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Coopers Hawk&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I stayed there crouched over the fence freezing since I only had the chance to throw my robe on, but I didn't want to go back in. Every so often it would look up at me to make sure I wasn't a threat, and then go back to tearing apart the poor Cardinal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/posts/0K6A8771.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;A Coopers Hawk staring at the camera as it de-feathers the remains of a Northern Cardinal&quot;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Coopers Hawk&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As it kept eating I was wondering how much more it could pick apart and what would be left, I had never seen anything like this before. Suddenly I saw what I thought was a foot just before it gobbled it down. I was shocked, I didn't think it would eat absolutely everything, feet and all. Sure enough a few seconds later I got a better look as it grabbed the second leg and started to pick it up with its beak. I started hammering the shutter hoping to catch it as it went down. After it picked apart the rest and took off I headed back inside not sure of what I got. Cycling through the photos I almost dropped the camera when I saw this next shot.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/0K6A8893.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;A Coopers Hawk gulping down the final remains of a Northern Cardinal&quot;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Coopers Hawk&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I had managed to get the second leg as it was sticking straight out of the hawk's beak. It has to be one of the more startling nature images I have captured. Every time I see it, it reminds me of the Xenomorphs from &lt;i&gt;Alien&lt;/i&gt; (the 1979 movie with Sigourney Weaver).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As luck would have it 500px was running a 'Just Wild' photo quest looking for submissions showing 'the innate behavior of animals in their natural habitat'. The prize was $500 and a portfolio review by the guest judge, world renowned nature photographer &lt;a href=&quot;https://roymangersnes.wordpress.com&quot; target=&quot;blank&quot;&gt;Roy Mangersnes&lt;/a&gt;. From past experience I know these contests are usually &lt;i&gt;loaded&lt;/i&gt; with photos from people lucky enough to travel to Africa or Antarctica, so a photo from my backyard was up against some stiff competition, but I gave it a chance anyway.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I've also submitted it to a few other places so we'll see if it gets any attention.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update:&lt;/strong&gt; While I didn't win the contest I was pleasantly surprised when 500px added my photo to the top 100 gallery from the quest. You can see &lt;a href=&quot;https://500px.com/500px/galleries/just-wild-quest-top-100-photos&quot; target=&quot;blank&quot;&gt;my photo along with the other amazing finalists here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/posts/top-100-gallery-hero.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;The hero image for the 500px.com Just Wild photo quest&quot;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;500px - Top 100 photos&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/posts/top-100-gallery.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;An image gallery of the finalists for the 500px.com Just Wild photo quest&quot;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Not bad company to be in&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 26 Feb 2019 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/blog/2019/02/26/coopers-hawk.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/blog/2019/02/26/coopers-hawk.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>blog</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Lunar Eclipse</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;This past weekend I was able to get out and somewhat enjoy the most recent total lunar eclipse. Despite my better judgement knowing that it was going to be in the single digits I packed up my gear and headed down to Peck Farm Park in Geneva where the &lt;a href=&quot;http://fvasil.org&quot; target=&quot;blank&quot;&gt;Fox Valley Astronomical Society&lt;/a&gt; was hosting a viewing party. I've been a member for a number of years now, and its always enjoyable to share these experiences with a number of people. Thankfully we had a heated barn with doughnuts and coco right next to where we setup all our telescopes and viewing equipment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Despite the temperature hanging around 5&amp;deg; there was a large number of people who stopped by. Mark C gave a wonderful lecture about why lunar eclipses happen, best viewing practices, and what everyone could expect to see.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/posts/eclipse-lecture.jpg&quot;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Pre event lecture given by Mark C.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As the eclipse got underway people would periodically pop outside to look through the various telescopes and binoculars everyone had setup. Using an 11&quot; Schmidt Cassegrain telescope, I was a bit overpowered for a full moon - viewing through the eyepiece you can only see about 60% of the surface, and its almost too bright without any filters. To make things easier on everyone I just turned my camera over to live view and let everyone see that way. I had a fun time answering everyone's questions, and hearing them ooh and ahh as they got a close up view of the moon (some for the first time).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/posts/lunar-eclipse-setup.jpg&quot;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;We had a good turnout at Peck Farm Park&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As the earth's shadow crept along the moons surface I would pop outside and snap a few frames. It wasn't until it was about 30% covered when I could fit the entire lit surface in one shot.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/posts/lunar-eclipse-2019-midway.jpg&quot;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Midway through&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By the time of totality the temperature had plunged to just above 0&amp;deg;. It was so cold that I couldn't have my glove off for more than a few seconds to adjust my camera. I was also getting camera shake from my remote shutter release cable - it was so cold that it was almost completely stiff, and if I moved my hand the cable would introduce enough vibration to ruin the shot.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since a lunar eclipse is a rather slow event I was able to take my camera off the telescope and get my 70-200mm f/2.8 lens out for some wide shots. Mark C had mentioned that the &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Beehive_Cluster&quot; target=&quot;blank&quot;&gt;Beehive Cluster&lt;/a&gt; of stars was about 7 degrees to the south east, and should be visible with any exposure of more than a few seconds. I tried a number of shots, but found that at 150mm anything over 6 seconds would introduce star trails since I was on an unguided tripod. I took this exposure at 4 seconds and it came out perfectly. Below and to the left of the moon you can see the cluster.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/eclipse-and-beehive.jpg&quot;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;The lunar eclipse and Beehive Cluster of stars to the lower left&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As the night wore on it started to get almost unbearable being outside. I was able to stay from the beginning of the eclipse at about 9:30 to just after midnight. Had it been warmer I would have stayed for all phases, but my hands were numb and my back hurt from being up and down all night so I decided to pack up my gear and head home. Despite the freezing cold my camera battery was still at 50% which I was not expecting, so tip of the hat to Canon. The 5D MkIII had zero issues being out in the cold for hours on end. I was delighted with my results though. Here is a progression from the the beginning to totality.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/eclipse-2019-progression.jpg&quot;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Progression of the lunar eclipse&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And here is my first pass at editing a single photo of totality. Using my telescope as a lens gives me an effective focal length of about 2800mm, so the full moon does not fit in one frame. I took groups of three shots to make sure I was wide enough not to just capture the moon, but at totality to get some stars in the frame as well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;vertical&quot;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/lunar-eclipse-2019.jpg&quot;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Three shot composite of totality&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another eclipse in the books, and despite the cold I am really happy with how everything turned out. The only downside is that we have to wait until 2022 for the next full lunar eclipse. The next astrological event to look forward to is Mercury will transit the sun in November, so stay tuned for that!&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 22 Jan 2019 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/astrophotography/2019/01/22/lunar-eclipse.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/astrophotography/2019/01/22/lunar-eclipse.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>astrophotography</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>My top 10 images of 2018</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;It's become a tradition that at the end of every calendar year I look back and choose the top 10 photographs I have taken over the past twelve months. While it certainly hasn't been one of my more active years I did create some of my best work. To find my top shots I create a smart gallery in Lightroom of anything with over three stars in 2018, then start narrowing down to a final set of ten. So lets take a look at my top ten photographs of 2018, presented in chronological order.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first three images were all taken on the same day in February during one of the few heavy snow storms we got this past winter. In December of 2016 I captured a small number of shots of a copse of trees in a local park during another storm which I absolutely loved the look of. Since that time I was anxiously waiting for the same snowy conditions to no avail. When I saw that we were about to get a foot of snow I got my camera gear ready and headed out west.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To the east of my house is the dense Chicago suburbs and the city proper, but to the west is almost completely open farmland. This presents some wonderful opportunities for minimalist landscape photography. During the summertime I would drive down various random farm roads looking for interesting trees and possible shots for wintertime. Marking them in Google Maps lets me find them again with no guesswork. I plotted a route that would take me past about six interesting spots I had flagged, then jumped in the car and headed out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I easily found my first location and was delighted to see that it looked exactly how I thought it would in this situation. The snow was absolutely blinding and very difficult to work with. While the 5DMkIII is weather sealed and fairly water resistant I don't like taking my chances so I had a rain cover wrapped around it, and kept it under my coat as I jumped out of the car. From the side of the road a large copse of trees was maybe a hundred yards away or so, completely on its own, buried in the increasing snow. A small line of trees in the background was just visible on the horizon leading the eye into frame and grounding the main subject, ensuring it didn't feel like it was floating in the ether.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/0K6A4611.jpg&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Burlington Township, Illinois&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This next location was one I found while scouring Google Maps when I was bored one day. Looking for single trees in the middle of fields I marked this as something to look into. As I pulled up I found a chain blocking the side road saying no vehicle traffic. It didn't say anything about foot traffic, and while there wasn't any 'No Trespassing' signs, I was a bit curious if I was technically allowed to be there. Knowing I was just taking photos and not causing any harm I headed up the road. There were five crooked trees all in a row, with a generous amount of space between them giving me different composition options. I took some shots of all five, some singles and different groupings, but my favorite was a frame with two trees and one in the distance being cut off by the horizon. Just a simple centered composition, like the last shot, almost overexposed to avoid picking up details in the foreground.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/0K6A4700.jpg&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Burlington Township, Illinois&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My final shot from that day was quite possibly one of my all time favorite photos. As luck would have it I came across this location randomly. After hitting a few locations I had flagged I decided to try and loop my way around back heading east and get home. Driving north I came to an intersection where I glanced at my GPS, noting that I could find major roads in either direction. I flipped a coin in my head and turned left. A minute or two later I found a single tree on a hill with a short fence tracing along the spine of the hill, just poking out of the deep snow. I was the only one crazy enough to be out in that weather so I just threw the car in park not knowing if there was a shoulder. I thank my lucky stars I did because as I got out and walked over to get a closer look I sunk down into a ditch and was up to my thighs in snow. I worked my way out and took this photo, keeping the tree on the right third line as the fence dipped off to the left. This was probably the first time I wish I had a 24-70mm. I initially got out my 16-35 but it was just too wide. My 50mm didn't give me what I was looking for, so I nervously grabbed my 70-200mm thinking it would be too tight. At 70mm I was able to get enough of the scene while keeping details.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/0K6A4774.jpg&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;i&gt;Tree on the hill&lt;/i&gt;, Burlington Township, Illinois&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I'm always looking to improve my astrophotography, and this next shot is a good example of why you should always keep pushing yourself. In May the weather was starting to get nicer out, so on a crystal clear evening I setup the telescope because I wanted to try stacking multiple frames of the moon to get as sharp of an image as possible. I spent a while dialing in the focus and then took about 50 frames. After some wonderful visual observation I packed everything up and went in to see what I got. I sorted through and picked out the best 24 shots and then combined them in Photoshop. The result speaks for itself. Every crater and detail on the surface is tack sharp. I feel like I could reach out and run my hand across this image. I'd love to see it in a glass print from Fracture.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/0K6A5593.jpg&quot;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Waxing Gibbous Moon (24 frames)&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I didn't get out too much this year, so a large portion of my favorite photographs were from my &lt;a href=&quot;/travelogue/2018/10/04/scramble.html&quot;&gt;New England Scramble&lt;/a&gt; so I won't go into too much detail again. First up was an abstract shot I took deliberately using a slow shutter speed while panning the camera. I love the color of the fall leaves with the white streak of the birch trunk in the middle. Stepping outside your comfort zone and shooting different subjects can yield unexpected results.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/0K6A7232.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Colors of fall&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another shot I like is from the drive up to Mt Washington, of a small cabin cozily nested among the changing trees. I suspect I missed peak foliage by about a week or two, but beggars can't be choosers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/0K6A7564.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;A solitary house among the fall colors&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This next photo was taken at the top of Mt Washington, one of dozens of small rock piles called cairns that I believe guide hikers along the summit. I especially love the different layers of mountains fading off into the distance. I'd like to see this in an oversized canvas wrap some day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/0K6A7398.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Cairns atop Mt Washington&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The next two photos were taken at the Portland Head Light in Portland ME. This was a bucket list location for me, so I couldn't decide which one I liked better. I took the first photo from the overlook on the south side of the lighthouse just as the sun crept over the horizon. It's a panorama of five individual shots stitched together, so the detail in the final result is impressive.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/head-light-sunrise.jpg&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Portland Head Light, Portland Maine&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Immediately after the sun was over the horizon I scrambled across to the north side of the park to shoot from another angle. I was able to get down onto a large field of rocks and capture the waves crashing over them as the sun came up catching the spray and bathing the entire scene in a warm glow.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/0K6A7138.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Portland Head Light, Portland Maine&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My final shot from 2018 was one I had wanted for years, and for more details you can read &lt;a href=&quot;/astrophotography/2018/12/26/iss-transit.html&quot; /&gt;my blog post about it&lt;/a&gt;. The morning after Christmas I was able to catch the ISS, illuminated, just before transiting the moon. It was my third try and second success, but by far the best capture I've made. The moon could be sharper due to it being so hazy on the ground, but overall I really love this one.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/0K6A8260-2.jpg&quot;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;The ISS just before lunar transit&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While this has been my slowest year for photography in quite a while I am still happy with the results. I can't wait to get out for some shoots in 2019 and see where the year takes me.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 09 Jan 2019 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/blog/2019/01/09/best-of-2018.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/blog/2019/01/09/best-of-2018.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>blog</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Capturing the ISS again</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Back in June I was able to &lt;a href=&quot;/astrophotography/2018/06/01/chasing-a-bullet.html&quot; target=&quot;blank&quot;&gt;photograph the ISS transiting the moon&lt;/a&gt; for the first time, and while I was generally happy with it, I knew I could do better. So ever since I have been keeping an eye on &lt;a href=&quot;https://transit-finder.com/&quot; target=&quot;blank&quot;&gt;transit-finder.com&lt;/a&gt; to see when I could get another chance to try again.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Just a few days before Christmas I saw a pass would occur to the west of me by a few miles, and as luck would have it, pass almost right over my friends Doug &amp;amp; Heather's house! Fantastic! The only thing was it was going to be at 5:58am, and the day after Christmas, meaning the weather was a definite wild card.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/posts/iss-third-attempt.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Using the transit finder tool to plot another ISS capture&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I woke up at 4:30am and poking my head outside saw it was pretty clear, just a slight haze around the moon. I packed everything up and jumped in the car, getting more and more concerned with the fog. Thankfully it was staying close to the ground and straight up was still pretty good.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I set everything up with a few minutes to spare and it started getting more and more hazy. Test shots in the camera still looked really good so I thought I would have a good chance. The ISS finder app on my phone indicated that it was tracking straight up and just breaking over the horizon, so I started visually scanning the sky for it. During my last attempt it was not lit by the sun so I couldn't see it until during transit. This time it was illuminated so it would look like a fast moving star. Depending on the altitude of the ISS and a few other factors the station can appear anywhere from very small to somewhat large in the sky. I was delighted to find it exactly where it should be, shining brightly and right on track to pass over the moon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure class=&quot;vertical&quot;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/posts/iss-third-just-before.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Spotting the ISS just before transit&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The bright speck just above the tree is the ISS, exactly where it should be, exactly on time. This time I was able to record the flyby on my iPhone since I wasn't crouched behind the scope looking through the camera. I watched it as it flew overhead, firing the remote just before transit. I got four frames just before, and another four as it passsed in front of the moon. I quickly disconnected my camera, checked out the preview, and let out a little yell.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here is the 8 frames I captured of the station just before and during transit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/posts/iss-third-stack-s.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;The International Space Station lunar transit 8 stack shot&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here is a close up of the station just before transit. It's one of the few times I have gone from what I see in my head to exactly what I see on the screen perfectly. That is always extremely satisfying.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/0K6A8260-2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;The International Space Station just before transiting the moon&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I've wanted to capture this exact shot for &lt;i&gt;years&lt;/i&gt;, it took a lot of patience and a few attempts but it was worth the hard work. I am still blown away by the results. You can clearly see the structure of the station and even the color of the solar arrays. For an object moving at about 17,500mph I think it's pretty clear. I got lucky with the position, capturing it just before crossing over.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'm definitely hooked and will be trying to get even clearer shots in the future. At 51.41 arc seconds the station was fairly large, but I've seen transits listed in the 60's before. Just for reference my first successful attempt was only about 28 arc seconds. Always room for improvement!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Next up is the lunar eclipse in January, and possibly attempting an ISS solar transit. Stay tuned!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 26 Dec 2018 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/astrophotography/2018/12/26/iss-transit.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/astrophotography/2018/12/26/iss-transit.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>astrophotography</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
