<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Gorilla-Studios Photography</title>
    <description>Gorilla-Studios Photography</description>
    <link>http://www.gorilla-studios.com/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://www.gorilla-studios.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
      <item>
        <title>Rolliflex Kit</title>
        <description>&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/posts/rolliflex.jpg&quot;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Recesky 35mm TLR Camera Kit&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&#39;ve always wanted an original &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Rolleiflex&quot;&gt;Rolliflex Twin Lens Reflex camera&lt;/a&gt; but could never pull the trigger due to the cost
of one in good condition. I was poking around Amazon a few weeks ago and found some replica kits for only $25, so I
added it to my wish-list. Lo and behold one arrived at my door a few days after my birthday! The kit comes completely
disassembled, with a screwdriver and a single roll of 35mm ISO200 film.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/posts/rolliflex-assembly.jpg&quot;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Assembly&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Opening it up I was rather surprised &lt;i&gt;how much&lt;/i&gt; assembly was required. Everything down to the shutter was
in pieces, and unfortunately the instructions were obviously translated into English, meaning they were about as
clear as mud. Thankfully I know my way around a film camera so everything was fairly easy to figure out, the biggest
problem was that two of the shutter springs were mis-labelled. Once I figured that out assembly wasn&#39;t too bad.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The quality is exactly what you would expect from a $25 dollar kit. Everything is plastic and on the flimsier side,
but as completed kit it holds up okay. I will load it up with film and pick something to shoot in the next few days.
Stay tuned for the results.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Check out the kit at Amazon &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.amazon.com/dp/B004PALJBA/&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 11 Aug 2014 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://www.gorilla-studios.com/2014/08/11/rolliflex/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.gorilla-studios.com/2014/08/11/rolliflex/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Week 31 - Meadow Saxifrage</title>
        <description>&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/p52/31.jpg&quot;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Meadow Saxifrage&lt;span&gt;1/125, f/2.8, ISO50&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This week I wanted to mix it up a little bit and try practicing macro work again.
Years ago I bought a Quantaray 50mm macro, and from time to time I like to photograph
flowers and bugs up close. My parents work very hard on their gardens so the backyard
is an absolute playground for someone who wants to do flower-scapes. I grabbed
my gear and headed out to the backyard Sunday afternoon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Shooting at 50mm for subjects like this means getting the lens less than an inch or two
from the subject quite often, which means you block out a lot of natural light. To compensate
for this I used my flash off camera on a long cable. This allows me to use the flash hand-held,
giving me the flexibility to orientate it any way I needed. I kept the camera on my Manfrotto
tripod with the center column locked perpendicular to the legs, swinging the camera out over
the flowers instead of trying to make it work as a traditional tripod.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I started with some yellow daisies, but nothing was quite grabbing me. I wanted to get in
extremely close and hopefully wind up with a photo that could be printed and framed. I made
my way around the garden, eventually setting up directly above a large pot full of what I believe
are Meadow Saxifrage. They couldn&#39;t have been more than an inch across, so it was going to be
difficult to say the least. I struggled trying not to blow out the petals with the flash while
getting the exposure of the stamen correct, finally settling on 1/125th at 2.8, with the flash
stopped down to 1/32nd power with a puffer defuser, held just to the right of the lens. At 2.8
this close the depth of field was incredibly shallow - the stamen are sharp, as well as the edge
of the right most petal, with a little bit of details on each petal at the center. Two stems
directly underneath add just the right touch to break up what would have been a dull background.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 04 Aug 2014 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://www.gorilla-studios.com/2014/08/04/photo52-week31/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.gorilla-studios.com/2014/08/04/photo52-week31/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Week 30 - Millenium Park Busts</title>
        <description>&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/p52/30.jpg&quot;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Head Sculptures, Millenium Park&lt;span&gt;3.2s, f/8, ISO50&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This week I headed back down to Millenium Park in the heart of the Loop to check out
a new art installation just across the pavilion with The Bean. Artist Jaume Plensa has
created four female heads ranging from twenty-one to thirty-nine feet hight, yet only a
few feet wide. You can&#39;t tell from this perspective, but they have been skewed so as you walk from
where the photo was taken down towards them you quickly realize they are very thin. It&#39;s
quite an optical illusion and draws a large crowd. These three are located just east of
Crown Fountain, while the largest of the four is right on Michigan Ave at the entrance to
the park.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I had a difficult time shooting because the lighting just wasn&#39;t there. It was getting
very dark and I had hoped to pick up the buildings in the background, but the foreground
lighting just wasn&#39;t enough to balance the exposure. This is one of the earlier shots from
before sunset. I brightened up the trees to almost an infra-red like photo to create some
contrast. I am definitely going to go back to see what other kinds of photos I can get,
it really is something to check out if you are in the Loop.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 28 Jul 2014 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://www.gorilla-studios.com/2014/07/28/photo52-week30/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.gorilla-studios.com/2014/07/28/photo52-week30/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Week 29 - Archways</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;A few months ago while working at a client&#39;s office downtown, I used to go for walks at lunch
to explore the neighborhood and one day stumbled across Mary Bartelme Park. Located just west of the
loop it&#39;s a wonderful park with a playground, dog play area, and on the west end, a very interesting
piece of art. A series of five steel or aluminum archways at various angles stand about 12 ft square,
and are equipped with nozzles that spray a fine mist of water to cool off patrons during the hot
Chicago summers. While there I snapped a few photos with my iPhone and told myself to come back at some
point to shoot with my SLR. A few nights ago I finally got the chance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As I always say preparation goes a long way so I wanted to get there before sundown to set everything
up and make sure I had my composition locked in. I wanted to shoot very low to exaggerate the angles of
the arches, so I set my Manfrotto as low as it would go with the neck flipped at a 90 degree angle, the bottom of the camera only a few inches off
the pavement.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/posts/arch-prep.jpg&quot;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Preparation is key&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As the sun finally settled below the horizon and the lights came up, the sky faded to a beautiful purple
blue hue with a touch of pink to the south. The ideal lighting was only around for about fifteen to twenty
minutes so I knew I had to get something relatively quickly. I loved the colors of the shots I was taking,
but it was really lacking something. I had expected the water to be misting from the arches, however when
anyone tried to turn it on nothing happened. I&#39;m not sure where the idea came from, but I thought this would
be the perfect opportunity to try some light painting - problem was I don&#39;t carry a flashlight in my day pack.
Undeterred, I set the camera to a 10 second timer, turned on my iPhone flashlight, and proceeded to walk back and forth
waiving it with the flashlight towards the camera. My first exposure was just arcs headed from back to front -
not as dramatic as I was hoping for, but the light was showing up crystal clear. I fired off another ten
exposures or so, wildly waving my arm and running back and forth each time (what a workout). I
eventually got exactly what I wanted - windmilling the phone like Pete Townshend while slowly walking towards
the camera created this weeks photo. Probably the most unique and fun photo I have ever taken.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/portfolio/archways.jpg&quot;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Archways&lt;span&gt;30s, f/8, ISO200&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 22 Jul 2014 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://www.gorilla-studios.com/2014/07/22/photo52-week29/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.gorilla-studios.com/2014/07/22/photo52-week29/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Week 28 - Sears Tower</title>
        <description>&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/portfolio/blue-sky-walk.jpg&quot;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;July 14th - Sears Tower skyboxes&lt;span&gt;1/400, f/9, ISO100&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;No matter what I do I can&#39;t stop taking photos of the Sears Tower, I&#39;ve probably surpassed the thousand mark a while ago.
It doesn&#39;t help that I work just a few blocks from it, and on some days I like to go for a walk during lunch with my camera.
I&#39;ve said before that I love taking photos of it because you can get dramatically different shots from all angles of the
building. I wanted to see if I had enough reach at 200mm to see people in the skyboxes that jut out from the west side of
the tower over Wacker Drive. This particular angle was from the north west corner on the pedestrian island out front. I
particularly like that you can&#39;t instantly figure out what you are looking at, and its certainly not a photo of the Sears I
have seen before. There is a very subtle lens flare from the afternoon sun taking up the right side of the exposure, but I
feel it adds a bit of warmth and character.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 17 Jul 2014 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://www.gorilla-studios.com/2014/07/17/photo52-week28/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.gorilla-studios.com/2014/07/17/photo52-week28/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Prints for sale</title>
        <description>&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/posts/for-sale.jpg&quot;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Select prints are available from 500px.com&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am pleased to announce that select prints from my portfolio are now &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.500pxart.com/gorilla-studios&quot;&gt;available for purchase at 500px.com&lt;/a&gt;. Eight beautiful photographs
are currently available in various sizes on framed paper, canvas wrap, aluminum, or acrylic. You can see them &lt;a href=&quot;/store/&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; or at
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.500pxart.com/gorilla-studios&quot;&gt;500px.com&lt;/a&gt;.  More photos will be added in the future so keep an eye out, or you can always request a print to become available.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 16 Jul 2014 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://www.gorilla-studios.com/2014/07/16/prints-for-sale/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.gorilla-studios.com/2014/07/16/prints-for-sale/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Week 27 - Fireworks</title>
        <description>&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/p52/27.jpg&quot;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;July 5th - Fireworks with the family&lt;span&gt;5s, f/5.6, ISO1000&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I already wrote a long post about my 4th of July weekend, so I want to keep this one brief. I selected another shot
from our family fireworks display in Indiana as my photo of the week. This is very close to what I had in mind when I
setup my tripod - I wanted a wide shot with the fireworks going off from in back of the house with a few people in frame
if possible. On my full-frame 5D MkIII at 19mm I was just shy of capturing the entire ark, but I love the overall exposure.
Great evening with the family.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 05 Jul 2014 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://www.gorilla-studios.com/2014/07/05/Fireworks/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.gorilla-studios.com/2014/07/05/Fireworks/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Fourth Of July</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Another great 4th of July is now in the books. My wife and I were again lucky enough to watch the Chicago fireworks over Navy Pier from a high rise on Lake Shore Drive. It&#39;s a large building of condominiums with a private deck on the 35th floor - a perfect place to watch the show. I took a few exposures during magic hour to get everything set, that way all I had to worry about was exposure time. I found ISO 100 was too low, so I quickly bumped it to 400 at f/10, shooting bursts between 5 and 10 seconds. This was very early in the show, because the smoke quickly got overwhelming and headed straight towards us.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/posts/navy-pier-fireworks-14.jpg&quot;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;July 4th - Fireworks over Navy Pier&lt;span&gt;7s, f/10, ISO400&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After the Navy Pier fireworks were over we were treated to an amazing view out west - we got to see all the west side and suburban fireworks, dozens of them all going off at once, from horizon to horizon. I can only imagine what the view would have been like from an airplane or helicopter. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/posts/fireworks-west.jpg&quot;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;July 4th - Looking west&lt;span&gt;10s, f/10, ISO400&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The next day we drove down to Indiana for a relaxing weekend with the family. After a day at the beach and lots of grilled food, we pulled out the fireworks for a personal show in the back yard. It was tricky as I wasn&#39;t sure exactly where they would go off, or how long they would go for, so I was again in Bulb mode, essentially guessing my exposures each time. A few rain drops on the lens added some fun distortion to some of the photos, and I think this was my favorite.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/posts/indiana-fireworks.jpg&quot;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;July 5th - Fireworks at home&lt;span&gt;4.8s, f/5.6, ISO1000&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After the large ones were shot off it was time for some roman candles and a little fun for the kids. Here is a prime example of almost exactly what I had in my mind working out as planned...with a lot of hard work. When I saw the first one lit I knew I wanted one of the kids faces light up by the firework from coming out of their hand, problem was it was almost pitch black so I had to manually focus while they were lighting the first few off. Once I locked in focus I had to time a 1/30th second shot right after the sparks shot out and briefly light the scene. It took quite a few attempts but I finally captured this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/posts/roman-candle.jpg&quot;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;July 5th - Roman Candle&lt;span&gt;1/30th, f/22, ISO6400&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I absolutely love this photo, but the feeling of showing her parents that shot was even better. That&#39;s what I love about candid portraiture, capturing that special moment that takes someones breath away when they see it. We had quite a few moments like that this weekend, but this one still makes me smile every time I see it. Happy 4th of July everyone.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 05 Jul 2014 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://www.gorilla-studios.com/2014/07/05/4th-of-July/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.gorilla-studios.com/2014/07/05/4th-of-July/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Week 26 - Bald Eagle</title>
        <description>&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/adult-bald-eagle.jpg&quot;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;June 29th - Adult Bald Eagle&lt;span&gt;1/320, f/4.5, ISO100&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Taking a break from cityscapes and architecture, this week I packed up my gear and headed back out into nature. A friend and I
went out for a morning shoot around the Fox River with no particular goal in mind, however we chanced upon two fisherman who told
us that some bald eagles had nested north of us in Mooseheart, where the juveniles were getting ready to fly for the first time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Arriving at the location it was obvious where the nest was. Bald eagles have the largest nest size of any bird in North America,
or possibly anywhere period. I estimate it was probably a good 8-10 feet around, and equally as deep. The juvenile bald eagle is a
very dark brown with a few white feathers poking out at various spots on their body. Their heads are not white, nor are their beaks
yellow until adulthood, which is at about 5 years old or so. It was very difficult to get any clean photos of the juveniles since
the pine tree was fairly thick.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After a few minutes of watching them we noticed an adult in an adjacent tree staring at us very closely. There is very little
difference between the male and females, the only distinct difference being size - the females tend to be about 25% larger than the
males. Judging by the size I presume this was the father. He hopped around a little bit when we spotted him presumably to watch us
closer, but didn&#39;t move apart from that. I took this with a 70-200mm 2.8, and this is a 100% crop which tells you how high up he was.
I shouldn&#39;t be surprised, but I was taken aback at how good their eyesight was. On exposure after exposure you could plainly see they
were watching us extremely closely - constantly looking right down the barrel of the lens. These are truly majestic creatures and I
hope to get a chance to photograph them flying and feeding at the river.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 29 Jun 2014 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://www.gorilla-studios.com/2014/06/29/bald-eagles/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.gorilla-studios.com/2014/06/29/bald-eagles/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Week 25 - Manhattan</title>
        <description>&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/p52/25.jpg&quot;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;June 19th - Manhattan&lt;span&gt;80s, f/9, ISO400&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This weeks Photo52 challenge was, obviously, taken during my &lt;a href=&quot;/2014/06/23/NYC/&quot;&gt;trip to NYC&lt;/a&gt; last weekend. This shot was from the first night down in Brooklyn, just across from the southern tip of Manhattan. Brooklyn Bridge Park is a gorgeous location on the west side of Brooklyn overlooking the river and there are so many great locations for shooting the skyline. This location is on the far south of the park, where there is a dilapidated boat launch surrounded by these wooden posts poking out of the water. I knew if I could open the shutter long enough to smooth out the water it would be a great effect. As the sun dipped below the horizon there were some really ugly clouds that took up the right side of the sky, but at the last minute they finally cleared. I had a 2 stop neutral density filter on a Canon 16-35mm f/2.8 wide angle lens, and was exposing for 2-4 minutes each.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This particular exposure was taken at 80 seconds and since it was at f/9 the streetlights on the horizon didn&#39;t turn into giant starbursts like they would at lower f-stops. The composition is probably my favorite part of this - the wooden posts and clouds all lead you right into the center and right side of the frame where One World Trade Center is standing tall. I was hoping to get the Statue of Liberty in the left side of the frame, but there was a large open air sports complex off camera left jutting out into the river that blocked her. Hopefully I can go back and explore NYC again soon, there is so much to capture and nowhere near enough time.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 27 Jun 2014 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://www.gorilla-studios.com/2014/06/27/photo52-week25/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.gorilla-studios.com/2014/06/27/photo52-week25/</guid>
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
