<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Gorilla-Studios Photography</title>
    <description>Gorilla-Studios Photography</description>
    <link>http://www.gorilla-studios.com/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://www.gorilla-studios.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
      <item>
        <title>Wabash Ave</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;While downtown I don&#39;t typically ride the L, and when I do it&#39;s usually work related so I am heading to client offices. Late last year I happened to get off of the brown line at Wabash &amp;amp; Adams where there is an overpass looking straight up Wabash with a clear view of Trump Tower. At the time I didn&#39;t have my camera on me, but I made a mental note to head back at some point with my gear to see what I could get.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&#39;s the beginning of March and the Chicago weather is still very poor so I decided to only take a few quick shots to see what I could get when the weather gets nicer. I quickly setup my tripod at the center of the overpass between platforms, looking north up Wabash. As the trains rumbled by the overpass would shake quite a bit, but I was surprised to find it didn&#39;t affect any shots. This exposure was taken for 15 seconds, f/8 at ISO100.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/chicago/over-the-l.jpg&quot;&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Timing the shots was particularly tricky - I wanted to get trains going in both directions, but being pressed for time I didn&#39;t have any luck in the 15 minutes I was there. Overall I like the shot with the one train streaking into the station, but I want to go back in the spring or summer when there isn&#39;t snow on the platform roofs and the sky isn&#39;t so overcast and dull.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 04 Mar 2015 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://www.gorilla-studios.com/photo/2015/03/04/over-the-l/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.gorilla-studios.com/photo/2015/03/04/over-the-l/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Selective Sharpening</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;This month has been exclusively shooting portraits of my daughter as we play in the morning, so my portrait editing skills have been getting better and better lately. Here is a sharpening technique that I have been working on recently. For most of my landscape work I just do a simple Unsharp Mask applied to the entire frame which isn&#39;t the best technique since it isn&#39;t that flexible..&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In our example here we have a portait of Alison, zoomed in half way to get a good feel for whats happening. First I duplicate the background layer, then go to Filter &amp;gt; Other &amp;gt; High Pass.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/sharp/step1.jpg&quot;&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The layer will turn a dark grey with the edges of your subject are visible. I adjust the slider until the eyes are reaslly standing out a bit, but not too much. If you do go too high you can always adjust later, thats the great thing about this technique is its non-destructive and easily adjustable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/sharp/high-pass.jpg&quot;&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Change the layer from Normal to Overlay. While holding Option click create layer mask. By holding Option it will fill the layer mask with black. On a layer mask black is transparent, showing the layer below, while white makes it opaque, showing the layer sharpened with our High Pass filter.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/sharp/overlay.jpg&quot;&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With the sharpened layer transparent, we can use our paint brush to selectively sharpen only what we want. Make sure you have the black layer mask selected:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/sharp/select-mask.jpg&quot;&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Select a soft paint brush and make sure its white. Paint over the eyes and you can see the sharp layer coming through. You can see here I painted over her left eye - you can see how sharp it is compared to her right.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/sharp/mask.jpg&quot;&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I use this to paint over the eyes, nose, and lips, sometimes the ears and chin as well depending on the photo. Once you have painted over the areas you want sharp, then you can adjust the opacity of the layer to make sure its not too much.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By doing it this way we only sharpen what we want, and the rest of the photo is smooth - this is even better with photos taken at really wide apertures.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/sharp/final.jpg&quot;&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you&#39;d like to see this technique in action here&#39;s a quick screencast:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/SndYnCRfWpE&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 07 Feb 2015 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://www.gorilla-studios.com/tutorial/2015/02/07/selective-sharpening/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.gorilla-studios.com/tutorial/2015/02/07/selective-sharpening/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Sedona</title>
        <description>&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/sedona/1.jpg&quot;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;span&gt;1/500th, f/8, ISO100&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In early December we flew out to visit family down in Sedona, Arizona, where I have never actually been before. I have heard lots of great things about the landscape out there, especially the rock formations and valleys surrounding Sedona proper. We would only be there for a few days, but I wanted to try to get out at least a few times to shoot, not knowing when I would be back. I rented a brand new Canon 16-35 2.8 MkII specifically to capture some landscapes and hopefully starscapes. The first shot was taken on our way down to Phoenix, somewhere out over southern Colorado I believe. Being from Illinois it was amazing seeing such beautiful mountain ranges.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We landed in Phoenix and hopped a quick flight up to Flagstaff, then driving down to Sedona. The first day the weather was not cooperating at all, it was very overcast, chilly, and a little drizzly here and there. Our first stop was Midglee Bridge Park, just north of Sedona on the &#39;Y&#39;. Its a beautiful park with tons of footpaths and a very large steel bridge over the canyon supporting the road above. Even though it was so cloudy I knew I could probably get some nice black and whites, so I took quite a few photos as I tried to soak in the amazing scenery.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/sedona/3.jpg&quot;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;span&gt;1/320th, f/5.6, ISO100&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All the rock formations and ranges have names from what I gather, I&#39;ll have to do some research to find them all. The paths around the park went from flat and even to downright dangerous, even I had a tricky time navigating some. After about ten minutes there I felt a longing to just quit my job and come out to shoot landscapes for the next year or two. Thankfully my wife was there to snap me back to reality.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/sedona/4.jpg&quot;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;span&gt;1/500th, f/5.6, ISO100&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We found a large number of aloe plans scattered throughout the park and I was surprised at how large they were, probably a good two feet in diameter with these razor sharp leaves fanned out in all directions. I had never seen anything like it before.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/sedona/2.jpg&quot;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Aloe Plant&lt;span&gt;1/160th, f/3.5, ISO100&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Passing down below Midglee Bridge to the south side of the park there is a ledge looking out over Oak Creek and Wilson Canyon. There is a small path that heads back off to the east with a wonderful view of Steamboat Rock. Thankfully about 15 minutes into my hike the clouds started to part a bit, allowing the sun to shine down on Steamboat enough to get a few shots in.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/sedona/6.jpg&quot;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Midglee Bridge&lt;span&gt;1/250th, f/8, ISO100&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/sedona/5.jpg&quot;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;span&gt;1/640th, f/5.6, ISO100&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/sedona/7.jpg&quot;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Midglee Bridge Park&lt;span&gt;1/50th, f/9, ISO100&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Just up the road from Midglee Bridge Park is another one you can very easily miss, Grasshopper Point. It&#39;s almost a hidden turn off, and you wind your way down to the bottom of the canyon. We went down during the day to explore, but it was misty and very overcast. We met a family who were hiking down to the Oak Creek to go fishing. After exploring a while we headed back to the hotel for dinner and family time. The number one shot on my wishlist was a starscape with the rock formations in the foreground, so when it cleared up that night I headed back to Grasshopper Point, but to my dismay it was a full moon - the absolute worst time to shoot stars. Since there is very little light pollution the moon light everything up to where an exposure over 15 seconds looked almost like daytime. I took a few shots while I was down there, but was heartbroken that I didn&#39;t get many more stars than I usually get in the Chicago suburbs. On the upside I guess its a great excuse to book a trip back when its a new moon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/sedona/11.jpg&quot;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Grasshopper Park&lt;span&gt;15s, f/8, ISO2500&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The next morning I got up early to go catch the sunrise from Amitabha Stupa and Peace Park, a small park at the base of Chimney Rock. I got up to the park and hiked around for a while before the sun started cresting over the surrounding rock formations, finding some great locations to shoot from. The weather was a complete 180&amp;deg; from the day before - it was a crystal clear blue sky and a very comfortable temperature hovering in the mid-50&#39;s. I have never shot mountainscapes before so I really had to remember pouring over Ansel Adams books when I was younger, and try to capture a tiny sliver of the magic he was able to. I found an interesting patch of cactus to put in the foreground of some early shots as the sun painted the rock face with very warm light.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/sedona/8.jpg&quot;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;span&gt;1/100th, f/8, ISO100&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The park is located at the base of Chimney Rock to the west, panning around to Coffeepot Rock on the east edge of the formation. The morning was almost a scramble to get as many shots as I could as the lighting was perfect, and I had so much area to cover. Here is Chimney Rock right at sunrise, I love how the warm morning light really brings out how red it really is, contrasted against the deep blue sky.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/sedona/9.jpg&quot;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Chimney Rock&lt;span&gt;1/125th, f/8, ISO100&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Even at 16mm there was no way to get everything in one frame, or even two. Thankfully I have been practicing shooting panoramas the month before, so took a few minutes to visualize a few large panoramas. This next shot was a four frame panorama panning from west to east.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/sedona/10.jpg&quot;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;span&gt;4 shot panorama&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On some of the conversions Photoshop got rather confused by the deep blue skys and attempted to merge them together with interesting results - the sky would skew up another 3000 pixels in the center of the stitching. I got a few other panoramas, but none better than the &lt;a href=&quot;/2014/12/09/photo52-week49/&quot;&gt;nine shot panorama of the entire formation that morning&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I genuinely wish I had a few weeks to just camp out and shoot landscapes, but alas I only had a few hours to spend in and around Sedona. It is one of the most beautiful locaitions I have ever seen and really hope to get back some day.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 19 Dec 2014 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://www.gorilla-studios.com/travelogue/2014/12/19/sedona-traveloge/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.gorilla-studios.com/travelogue/2014/12/19/sedona-traveloge/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Week 49 - Sedona Panorama</title>
        <description>&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/p52/49.jpg&quot;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Sedona Arizona panorama&lt;span&gt;9 shot panorama&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This past weekend was spent down in Sedona Arizona, just a quick trip down to see family and get some quick photos. I had never been down before so I wasn&#39;t sure exactly what to expect, but I was almost overwhelmed with the beauty and sheer size of some of the rock formations around town. The weather was pretty poor on day one, so it was spent mostly scouting for spots to shoot at when it did clear up. Day two was forecasted to me much nicer and clear all day so I packed up my gear and headed out to The Amitabha Stupa and Peace Park before the sun came up. Its nestled at the base of a few large rock formations, and out of the way enough where I was the only one there all morning.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Even at 16mm I didn&#39;t have enough range to get everything I wanted, so I decided to shoot some panoramas, this time taking at least 6-10 shots for each final shot. I hiked up into the park a bit and found myself at a wonderful location just as the sun started creeping down the rockface. From what I understand Chimney Rock is off to the left, while Coffeepot Rock is on the right side. This particular photo is a composite of nine photos at about 20mm each, taken at sunrise. The final resolution is 23,132 x 7,193, which works out to a whopping 166MP, clocking in around 1GB.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I had to adjust each photo before compositing because the exposure level was thrown off during panning due to the sun being very close to the right-most frame. Once they were all correctly exposed and color-balanced I ran them through Photoshop&#39;s Photomerge feature to combine them into one gargantuan file. From there I edited out a spot that was on the lens which showed up nine times, as well as a high-pass layer mask sharpening to make sure the sky stayed smooth while the rocks were as sharp as they could be.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Getting nine exposures down into one large panorama is pretty tricky but I am getting much better. I hope to take what I have learned and use it for a 15-20 exposure panorama of the city skyline, but I have never stacked them both horizontally and vertically. We&#39;ll see how that goes.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 09 Dec 2014 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://www.gorilla-studios.com/photo52/2014/12/09/photo52-week49/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.gorilla-studios.com/photo52/2014/12/09/photo52-week49/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Week 48 - Family Portrait Shoot</title>
        <description>&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/p52/48.jpg&quot;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Candid portrait&lt;span&gt;1/125th, f/5, ISO100&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For our last week on the east coast my wife wanted to do a quick family portrait session for our Christmas cards, needless to say I couldn&#39;t say no. We headed down to Mason&#39;s Island where I captured &lt;a href=&quot;/2014/11/16/photo52-week46/&quot;&gt;the sunset for Week 46&lt;/a&gt;. Shooting a family portrait is always a challenge, but adding the fact I had to be in the photo was a real pain.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We did a few poses on the steps of the clubhouse, and got some really good shots, but it was overcast and starting to drizzle so we went under the porch to pack up my gear and get ready to go. Right before I put the camera away I noticed the soft light coming from camera left lighting up our little one&#39;s face, and the fact she was all smiles made me take a few candid photos as my wife was playing with her. I have found recently that anything below 1/125th or 1/150th is too slow for infant photography. I wrongly assumed they didn&#39;t move that much, and they don&#39;t, but when they move their heads the whip them around causing quite a few shots to be motion blurred. This one however was absolutely great as she smiled looking out over the ocean.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have been putting a lot of effort back into the editing process lately, and I tried a few things I don&#39;t usually do here. I tried a different selective sharpening technique using a high-pass filter and opacity mask, combined with a gradient map for the black and white conversion. Adding a touch of vingetting and this is one of my favorite photos of my wife and baby. I absolutely love shooting candid portraits, they are almost always leaps and bounds better than posed photos.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 02 Dec 2014 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://www.gorilla-studios.com/photo52/2014/12/02/photo52-week48/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.gorilla-studios.com/photo52/2014/12/02/photo52-week48/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Week 47 - Starry Night at Watch Hill</title>
        <description>&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/new-england/starry-watch-hill-2.jpg&quot;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Starry night at Watch Hill&lt;span&gt;15s, f/4, ISO4000&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This weeks shot is one I have had in my head for a number of years. I&#39;ve always wanted to capture a sandy beach with the tall grass and slat fence, but I have always thought it would be great at night with the stars as the background. Keeping an eye on the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.moonconnection.com/moon_phases_calendar.phtml&quot;&gt;Lunar Calendar&lt;/a&gt; I took a drive out to Watch Hill, Rhode Island the night before the new moon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I parked around 8:30 and headed off to the small dune area at Napatree Point, the wind was howling off the coast and it was hovering around freezing. It being a new moon I didn&#39;t have a whole lot of light to see with, so I had to let my eyes adjust and slowly make my way up and over the largest hill on the dunes. Much to my chagrin the nearby towns were casting quite a bit of light pollution, so I couldn&#39;t escape a yellow glow on the horizon. Despite this, I think it actually helps here, creating a silhouetting effect of the fence towards the right side, while the light from Watch Hill&#39;s town center behind me light up the reeds on the left side of the frame.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once in Camera Raw I cooled off the white balance a bit to bring it back to where it was, then punched up the black a bit. Not a whole lot more was done to the exposure. It was a bit grainier than I had hoped, but I was shooting at ISO4000. This was my second time out shooting stars with my new 5D MkIII so I am still looking for the best settings. I had bumped the ISO a little bit to keep the exposure at 15s, avoiding any star trails - I learned on my first trek a week earlier that shooting at 30s the stars start streaking just a hair.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I only have a few more nights here in Connecticut, so while I don&#39;t know if I can go back for another shoot, I would love to try it at a lower ISO and hopefully get more of the ocean in the frame (you can barely see the waves hitting th beach at the bottom right). Overall I do like this shot, but I think it will land in the &#39;learning&#39; pile once I get some better star shots in the future.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 24 Nov 2014 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://www.gorilla-studios.com/photo52/2014/11/24/photo52-week47/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.gorilla-studios.com/photo52/2014/11/24/photo52-week47/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Week 46 - Sunset at Masons Island</title>
        <description>&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/portfolio/masons-dock.jpg&quot;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Sunset on Mason&#39;s Island&lt;span&gt;8s, f/22, ISO50&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Being out in Connecticut, specifically right down on the coast, one thing we get here is spectacular sunsets. I have been going out every few days and photographing the sun as it dips below the horizon out over the water. Since its closer to wintertime the track of the sun heads a bit more south than the winter months, which is perfect for shooting out over the Atlantic ocean. For this week&#39;s trek I ventured down to another childhood favorite, Mason&#39;s Island in Stonington CT.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mason&#39;s Island looks out over Fishers Island Sound, Block Island Sound, and right out into the Atlantic. You can see Noank to the west all the way around to Watch Hill, Rhode Island to the east. It was a crystal clear afternoon as I grabbed my gear and started looking for places to shoot. As the sun was going down I started shooting straight down the dock, then off to the side silhouetting a smaller finger dock against the sun, but it wasn&#39;t quite grabbing me. As I was walking back down the dock I spotted this particular cleat that was being used to tie up a small rowboat. I love the texture of the lines that wrap around it, as well as how they create a nice curving leading line that draws the eyes over to the boat.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure class=&#39;vertical&#39;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#39;/images/p52/p52-46bs.jpg&#39;&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I wanted to get the boat out by itself without the post seemingly coming out of the top, yet I still wanted the cleat in the foreground. To achieve this shot I collapsed my tripod down all the way and flipped the center post into a horizontal position, setting the camera up an inch or two above the wood planks of the dock, completely laying prone while shooting. It was only a few inches away from the cleat, so in live vew I temporarily set the exposure wide open to focus manually, locking on the cleat itself. Even at f/22 the background turned a little soft, which I think works here. After I had set the focus I backed the exposure down to eight seconds, and took some shots as the sun disappeared.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is probably one of my favorite shots I have taken in a while, I can clearly see this either framed or as an oversize canvas wrap hanging on my wall.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 16 Nov 2014 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://www.gorilla-studios.com/photo52/2014/11/16/photo52-week46/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.gorilla-studios.com/photo52/2014/11/16/photo52-week46/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Week 45 - Mystic River Bascule Bridge</title>
        <description>&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/p52/45.jpg&quot;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Mystic River Bascule Bridge - 5 shot panorama&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have always wanted to photograph one of my childhood favorites - the Mystic River bascule bridge - and since we are staying in Connecticut for the month I finally have the opportunity. My family owned a dry goods store on the corner here for years, so I have many childhood memories of being around downtown Mystic and specifically watching the bridge raise and lower once an hour - its quite a sight.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Using &lt;a href=&quot;https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/rick-sammons-photo-sundial/id689328812?mt=8&quot;&gt;Rick Sammon&#39;s Photo Sundial app&lt;/a&gt; I checked to see when the light would be ideal, and my hunch was correct - just after sunrise the bridge would be bathed in a warm yellow orange light. I forced myself out of bed at 5:45 am and drove downtown, walking around the boardwalk as the sun started creeping over the horizon. Finally around 7:15am the sun was high enough to paint the entire scene with a nice soft light. After playing around with panoramas in week 43 I decided to try it out correctly this time. I shot 5 frames hand-held vertically starting with the bridge to my right, then panning down river to the left. I was sure to overlap my images by about 30% to give Photoshop&#39;s photomerge feature enough room to work with while stitching together everything. I carefully aligned each shot to complete an almost 180&amp;deg; shot, making sure to avoid any traffic over the bridge.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I touched up each photo before running the composite, if I didn&#39;t photoshop gets confused by the lens vingetting and averages them out to create some ugly dark spots in the sky. For panoramas I prefer to crop down to a 16x9 aspect ratio, it seems better than the custom ultra-wide and short ones artists sell, but more focused than a basic 4x3. I&#39;m not 100% sold on the warping effect of the foreground dock, but overall I love the image and want to print and frame this right away. So much more of New England to get this month!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 08 Nov 2014 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://www.gorilla-studios.com/photo52/2014/11/08/photo52-week45/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.gorilla-studios.com/photo52/2014/11/08/photo52-week45/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Week 43 - Fall Panorama</title>
        <description>&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/posts/panorama.jpg&quot;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Three image stitched panorama&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This weeks photo was taken from a hiking trail overlooking Eagle Ridge Resort in Galena, IL. My company held a corporate retreat over the weekend, so I had to bring along my camera gear to capture some late fall colors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The final image is comprised of three separate exposures. While I hauled some photo gear on our hike for portraits, I left the tripod in the car to save weight, not thinking I would do any panoramas (which I rarely shoot). Unfortunately this meant I had to hand hold the camera, while being extremely steady. With any panorama shot it is vital to keep the horizon level in each shot, while overlapping by 20-30% to ensure smooth stitching in post. Once the images are captured I use Adobe Bridge to Photomerge each image into one composite shot. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/posts/photomerge.jpg&quot;&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/posts/original-panorama.jpg&quot;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Un-cropped panorama&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the best results you should shoot more exposures vertically with a tripod, this gives you room in post to crop down without sacrificing vital portions of the image. You can see above the three images merged into one. In order to create the final image I had to crop out quite a bit from the top and bottom. I do like the final exposure, but it definitely loses a lot when viewed online unless you can zoom in all the way. Ideally this could be printed out to over 40&quot; wide to capture all the detail.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 28 Oct 2014 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://www.gorilla-studios.com/photo52/2014/10/28/photo52-week43/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.gorilla-studios.com/photo52/2014/10/28/photo52-week43/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Week 41 - Off Camera Flash</title>
        <description>&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/posts/phottix-test.jpg&quot;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Off camera flash &amp;amp; 24&quot; softbox&lt;span&gt;1/160th, f/2.8, ISO1250&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Obviously I have been rather busy the past six weeks, although I would never complain about the work. The baby has been growing like crazy and things are going very well. While I never had any experience in photographing newborns before, I have been through baby-photo boot-camp and come out the other side a little bit more experienced in getting some fun photos of my little one.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With an infant its obvious that you don&#39;t want to be firing off a flash in their eyes, but you also want studio quality portraits right from day one, so what do you do? For her first few weeks I did natural light only, taking advantage of the sun shining through the windows when I could, but its difficult. Now that she is moving around a bit more I decided to try a bit of fill light using my new Phottix Ares wireless flash trigger. I mounted it with my Canon 430EX flash on a portable 24&quot; softbox, setting the flash down to 1/64 power, and placing the light stand a few feet behind me while she laid on mommies tummy on the couch. I found shooting anything less than 1/160th was not going to work - she doesn&#39;t move a lot, but when she turns or bobs her head it&#39;s quicker than you&#39;d expect. ISO was set around 1250, while my 50mm was opened up to f/2.8.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The softbox diffused the light so well Alison didn&#39;t bat an eye. Positioning a one-month old is a challenge to say the least - additionally I am super sensitive to make sure I don&#39;t upset her, so we pretty much let her do her own thing. She&#39;s not sitting up on her own, and propping her up for photos can easily turn a baby cranky very fast - we don&#39;t like going that route. Tummy time on a big blanket over mommy makes for a calm baby. While making some funny sounds she lifted her head and looked straight down the lens to make this my favorite photo of the session. When she gets older we can do some more posed shots, and in more of a studio setup, but its still fun to get some while playing around in the living room.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 10 Oct 2014 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://www.gorilla-studios.com/photo52/2014/10/10/photo52-week41/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.gorilla-studios.com/photo52/2014/10/10/photo52-week41/</guid>
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
