<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Gorilla-Studios Photography</title>
    <description>Focusing on stunning landscape and high-energy music photography, Gorilla-Studios has been the online home of my portfolio since 2003. I specialize in landscapes, cityscapes and architecture, nature, candid portraiture, headshots, band promos and concert photography.
</description>
    <link>http://localhost:4000/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Sun, 26 May 2019 07:23:17 -0500</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 26 May 2019 07:23:17 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.8.5</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>StarSense Auto Align</title>
        <description>&lt;h3&gt;My initial impressions of the Celestron StarSense Auto Align Camera&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I've been looking into options for improving my polar alignment and tracking during astrophotography, so as a first step I decided to get a Celestron StarSense Auto Align camera. I didn't want to jump all the way to a full auto-guide camera + laptop, so I figured this would be a good solution until my skills improved.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During my initial research I had read a lot of reviews where people were having problems using the StarSense but I had a hunch that a lot of it was just user error. The setup and usage instructions were pretty straight forward so I wasn't too nervous.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The camera arrived in a handsome and well packed box. It comes with a basic RJ-11 (phone jack) cable to connect to the AUX port on any compatible GOTO mount, along with both a large and small mounting plate to fit a variety of optical tubes. It also comes with an updated hand controller for the mount, from what I gather this is where a lot of the processing happens.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/posts/star-sense-box.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Celestron StarSense packaging&quot;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Celestron StarSense packaging&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/posts/star-sense-camera.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Celestron Star Sense Camera&quot;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;The Celestron StarSense camera&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I had to take my optical view finder off the scope to make room for the StarSense. My Ultima 11&quot; was built back in 1994, so I think the accessory mounts on it aren't quite to the current industry standards so I couldn't mount both the StarSense and piggyback mount at the same time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;vertical&quot;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/posts/star-sense-controller.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Celestron StarSense hand controller&quot;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Celestron StarSense hand controller&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The camera needs to be calibrated to the mount the first time you use it, but after that it should automatically align the scope by itself. Celestron has a very straightforward &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=OqqoFZyxzQg&quot; target=&quot;blank&quot;&gt;instructional video&lt;/a&gt; walking you through the process. While I found that to be very helpful, I still had a few stumbles out in the field.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/posts/star-sense-on-ota.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Celestron Star Sense Camera on telescope&quot;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Celestron StarSense mounted on my Ultima 11&quot;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;After the monthly &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.fvasil.org&quot; target=&quot;blank&quot;&gt;Fox Valley Astronomical Society&lt;/a&gt; meeting we setup for some casual observing in the parking lot. I used this opportunity to test out the StarSense to see how it worked. I had some stops and starts with getting everything aligned, but nothing major. I entered the time and date into the controller and let it do its initial scan then tried to calibrate to Sirius only to have it almost 40 degrees off.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I turned off the mount, re-centered it, and noticed that the altitude on my mount was off by almost 10&amp;deg;. Fixed that and tried again, only this time I forgot to enter the time and date, so when it tried to slew to Mars it was pointing pretty much at the ground. Hrmph. I reset everything again, and was extremely careful to follow the alignment and calibration procedure. I told it to auto align and it scanned the sky for about 2 minutes or so. I then selected a star to slew to. Again I chose Sirius and the mount put it almost dead center. I selected calibrate, chose Sirius as the instructions say to calibrate off the last star used, and then got it absolutely dead center in the camera. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After finishing the calibration I tried slewing to another target, this time Arcturus which was rapidly setting. I held my breath as it swung around and then stopped with it bang in the center of the frame. Slew to Capella, same result. Awesome! Now a tough one - The Whirlpool Galaxy. I have wanted to photograph deep sky objects for a long time but haven't had any luck yet. It slewed to where I knew it should be, but obviously it wouldn't show up on the camera until I tried a long exposure. I set it to bulb mode and went for a 60 second exposure right off the bat.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/posts/whirlpool-single.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;The Whirlpool Galaxy&quot;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Single unprocessed frame of the Whirlpool Galaxy&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There it was. Faint, and only a single frame, but I had it dead to rights and I was tracking for at least 60 seconds at ISO 1600. Most brilliant photos of deep sky objects take multiple hours worth of exposures so I still have a long way to go, but I was incredibly happy to take that first step. I took about 10 minutes of exposures and went on to try Bode's Galaxy as well as The Pinwheel Galaxy just to make sure the mount was slewing and tracking well. When I have more time I'll get to spend an evening on one target. I can't wait.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As for the StarSense Auto Align camera, I'm very happy with it. The only problems I had were user errors and that was only during the initial setup. I think it's a bit expensive but it does exactly what it advertises. I plan on using this for the next year or so then next spring upgrading to a ZWO ASI Air + Auto Guide camera to actively track the mount without a laptop. I think the StarSense is very well suited for people who do a lot of visual astronomy, where as those of us who are more astro-imagers are better suited with a guide camera. I'm just not quite there yet, I still have a lot to learn.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Clear skies!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 14 Apr 2019 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/astrophotography/2019/04/14/star-sense.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/astrophotography/2019/04/14/star-sense.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>astrophotography</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Coopers Hawk</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Warning: The following images are slightly graphic, if you feel some nature photos are upsetting then you may want to skip this post&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So last weekend my wife and I were cleaning the house and doing our usual routine when all of a sudden she gasped and told me to look out the back window. She said a giant bird had grabbed a Cardinal and was de-feathering it in the backyard. We've had some large hawks and animals in the back from time to time, but whenever I open the door they always take off so I wasn't optimistic. However I grabbed my camera and eased my way outside still wearing my bathrobe.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As I stepped out on the back stoop the Coopers Hawk was on the back fence madly tearing feathers out of the poor Cardinal and thankfully didn't seem to mind me at all. I snapped a few photos thinking that is all I would get.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/posts/0K6A8638.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;A Coopers Hawk sitting on my backyard fence after grabbing a Northern Cardinal&quot;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Coopers Hawk&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I slowly made my way across the yard when suddenly it hopped off the fence and down into the neighbors backyard. Thankfully the side fence is nothing more than open wire, so I kept inching my way forwards. I was eventually crouching against the fence about 10 feet away. It seems the hawk was more hungry than worried about me so it didn't mind my shutter clicking away.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/posts/0K6A8719.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;A Coopers Hawk picking at the remains of a Northern Cardinal&quot;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Coopers Hawk&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I stayed there crouched over the fence freezing since I only had the chance to throw my robe on, but I didn't want to go back in. Every so often it would look up at me to make sure I wasn't a threat, and then go back to tearing apart the poor Cardinal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/posts/0K6A8771.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;A Coopers Hawk staring at the camera as it de-feathers the remains of a Northern Cardinal&quot;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Coopers Hawk&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As it kept eating I was wondering how much more it could pick apart and what would be left, I had never seen anything like this before. Suddenly I saw what I thought was a foot just before it gobbled it down. I was shocked, I didn't think it would eat absolutely everything, feet and all. Sure enough a few seconds later I got a better look as it grabbed the second leg and started to pick it up with its beak. I started hammering the shutter hoping to catch it as it went down. After it picked apart the rest and took off I headed back inside not sure of what I got. Cycling through the photos I almost dropped the camera when I saw this next shot.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/catalog/0K6A8893.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;A Coopers Hawk gulping down the final remains of a Northern Cardinal&quot;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Coopers Hawk&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I had managed to get the second leg as it was sticking straight out of the hawk's beak. It has to be one of the more startling nature images I have captured. Every time I see it, it reminds me of the Xenomorphs from &lt;i&gt;Alien&lt;/i&gt; (the 1979 movie with Sigourney Weaver).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As luck would have it 500px was running a 'Just Wild' photo quest looking for submissions showing 'the innate behavior of animals in their natural habitat'. The prize was $500 and a portfolio review by the guest judge, world renowned nature photographer &lt;a href=&quot;https://roymangersnes.wordpress.com&quot; target=&quot;blank&quot;&gt;Roy Mangersnes&lt;/a&gt;. From past experience I know these contests are usually &lt;i&gt;loaded&lt;/i&gt; with photos from people lucky enough to travel to Africa or Antarctica, so a photo from my backyard was up against some stiff competition, but I gave it a chance anyway.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I've also submitted it to a few other places so we'll see if it gets any attention.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update:&lt;/strong&gt; While I didn't win the contest I was pleasantly surprised when 500px added my photo to the top 100 gallery from the quest. You can see &lt;a href=&quot;https://500px.com/500px/galleries/just-wild-quest-top-100-photos&quot; target=&quot;blank&quot;&gt;my photo along with the other amazing finalists here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/posts/top-100-gallery-hero.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;The hero image for the 500px.com Just Wild photo quest&quot;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;500px - Top 100 photos&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/posts/top-100-gallery.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;An image gallery of the finalists for the 500px.com Just Wild photo quest&quot;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Not bad company to be in&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 26 Feb 2019 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/post/2019/02/26/coopers-hawk.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/post/2019/02/26/coopers-hawk.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>post</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Lunar Eclipse</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;This past weekend I was able to get out and somewhat enjoy the most recent total lunar eclipse. Despite my better judgement knowing that it was going to be in the single digits I packed up my gear and headed down to Peck Farm Park in Geneva where the &lt;a href=&quot;http://fvasil.org&quot; target=&quot;blank&quot;&gt;Fox Valley Astronomical Society&lt;/a&gt; was hosting a viewing party. I've been a member for a number of years now, and its always enjoyable to share these experiences with a number of people. Thankfully we had a heated barn with doughnuts and coco right next to where we setup all our telescopes and viewing equipment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Despite the temperature hanging around 5&amp;deg; there was a large number of people who stopped by. Mark C gave a wonderful lecture about why lunar eclipses happen, best viewing practices, and what everyone could expect to see.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/posts/eclipse-lecture.jpg&quot;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Pre event lecture given by Mark C.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As the eclipse got underway people would periodically pop outside to look through the various telescopes and binoculars everyone had setup. Using an 11&quot; Schmidt Cassegrain telescope, I was a bit overpowered for a full moon - viewing through the eyepiece you can only see about 60% of the surface, and its almost too bright without any filters. To make things easier on everyone I just turned my camera over to live view and let everyone see that way. I had a fun time answering everyone's questions, and hearing them ooh and ahh as they got a close up view of the moon (some for the first time).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/posts/lunar-eclipse-setup.jpg&quot;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;We had a good turnout at Peck Farm Park&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As the earth's shadow crept along the moons surface I would pop outside and snap a few frames. It wasn't until it was about 30% covered when I could fit the entire lit surface in one shot.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/posts/lunar-eclipse-2019-midway.jpg&quot;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Midway through&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By the time of totality the temperature had plunged to just above 0&amp;deg;. It was so cold that I couldn't have my glove off for more than a few seconds to adjust my camera. I was also getting camera shake from my remote shutter release cable - it was so cold that it was almost completely stiff, and if I moved my hand the cable would introduce enough vibration to ruin the shot.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since a lunar eclipse is a rather slow event I was able to take my camera off the telescope and get my 70-200mm f/2.8 lens out for some wide shots. Mark C had mentioned that the &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Beehive_Cluster&quot; target=&quot;blank&quot;&gt;Beehive Cluster&lt;/a&gt; of stars was about 7 degrees to the south east, and should be visible with any exposure of more than a few seconds. I tried a number of shots, but found that at 150mm anything over 6 seconds would introduce star trails since I was on an unguided tripod. I took this exposure at 4 seconds and it came out perfectly. Below and to the left of the moon you can see the cluster.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/catalog/eclipse-and-beehive.jpg&quot;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;The lunar eclipse and Beehive Cluster of stars to the lower left&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As the night wore on it started to get almost unbearable being outside. I was able to stay from the beginning of the eclipse at about 9:30 to just after midnight. Had it been warmer I would have stayed for all phases, but my hands were numb and my back hurt from being up and down all night so I decided to pack up my gear and head home. Despite the freezing cold my camera battery was still at 50% which I was not expecting, so tip of the hat to Canon. The 5D MkIII had zero issues being out in the cold for hours on end. I was delighted with my results though. Here is a progression from the the beginning to totality.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/catalog/eclipse-2019-progression.jpg&quot;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Progression of the lunar eclipse&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And here is my first pass at editing a single photo of totality. Using my telescope as a lens gives me an effective focal length of about 2800mm, so the full moon does not fit in one frame. I took groups of three shots to make sure I was wide enough not to just capture the moon, but at totality to get some stars in the frame as well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;vertical&quot;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/catalog/lunar-eclipse-2019.jpg&quot;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Three shot composite of totality&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another eclipse in the books, and despite the cold I am really happy with how everything turned out. The only downside is that we have to wait until 2022 for the next full lunar eclipse. The next astrological event to look forward to is Mercury will transit the sun in November, so stay tuned for that!&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 22 Jan 2019 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/astrophotography/2019/01/22/lunar-eclipse.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/astrophotography/2019/01/22/lunar-eclipse.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>astrophotography</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>My top 10 images of 2018</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;It's become a tradition that at the end of every calendar year I look back and choose the top 10 photographs I have taken over the past twelve months. While it certainly hasn't been one of my more active years I did create some of my best work. To find my top shots I create a smart gallery in Lightroom of anything with over three stars in 2018, then start narrowing down to a final set of ten. So lets take a look at my top ten photographs of 2018, presented in chronological order.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first three images were all taken on the same day in February during one of the few heavy snow storms we got this past winter. In December of 2016 I captured a small number of shots of a copse of trees in a local park during another storm which I absolutely loved the look of. Since that time I was anxiously waiting for the same snowy conditions to no avail. When I saw that we were about to get a foot of snow I got my camera gear ready and headed out west.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To the east of my house is the dense Chicago suburbs and the city proper, but to the west is almost completely open farmland. This presents some wonderful opportunities for minimalist landscape photography. During the summertime I would drive down various random farm roads looking for interesting trees and possible shots for wintertime. Marking them in Google Maps lets me find them again with no guesswork. I plotted a route that would take me past about six interesting spots I had flagged, then jumped in the car and headed out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I easily found my first location and was delighted to see that it looked exactly how I thought it would in this situation. The snow was absolutely blinding and very difficult to work with. While the 5DMkIII is weather sealed and fairly water resistant I don't like taking my chances so I had a rain cover wrapped around it, and kept it under my coat as I jumped out of the car. From the side of the road a large copse of trees was maybe a hundred yards away or so, completely on its own, buried in the increasing snow. A small line of trees in the background was just visible on the horizon leading the eye into frame and grounding the main subject, ensuring it didn't feel like it was floating in the ether.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/catalog/0K6A4611.jpg&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Burlington Township, Illinois&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This next location was one I found while scouring Google Maps when I was bored one day. Looking for single trees in the middle of fields I marked this as something to look into. As I pulled up I found a chain blocking the side road saying no vehicle traffic. It didn't say anything about foot traffic, and while there wasn't any 'No Trespassing' signs, I was a bit curious if I was technically allowed to be there. Knowing I was just taking photos and not causing any harm I headed up the road. There were five crooked trees all in a row, with a generous amount of space between them giving me different composition options. I took some shots of all five, some singles and different groupings, but my favorite was a frame with two trees and one in the distance being cut off by the horizon. Just a simple centered composition, like the last shot, almost overexposed to avoid picking up details in the foreground.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/catalog/0K6A4700.jpg&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Burlington Township, Illinois&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My final shot from that day was quite possibly one of my all time favorite photos. As luck would have it I came across this location randomly. After hitting a few locations I had flagged I decided to try and loop my way around back heading east and get home. Driving north I came to an intersection where I glanced at my GPS, noting that I could find major roads in either direction. I flipped a coin in my head and turned left. A minute or two later I found a single tree on a hill with a short fence tracing along the spine of the hill, just poking out of the deep snow. I was the only one crazy enough to be out in that weather so I just threw the car in park not knowing if there was a shoulder. I thank my lucky stars I did because as I got out and walked over to get a closer look I sunk down into a ditch and was up to my thighs in snow. I worked my way out and took this photo, keeping the tree on the right third line as the fence dipped off to the left. This was probably the first time I wish I had a 24-70mm. I initially got out my 16-35 but it was just too wide. My 50mm didn't give me what I was looking for, so I nervously grabbed my 70-200mm thinking it would be too tight. At 70mm I was able to get enough of the scene while keeping details.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/catalog/0K6A4774.jpg&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;i&gt;Tree on the hill&lt;/i&gt;, Burlington Township, Illinois&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I'm always looking to improve my astrophotography, and this next shot is a good example of why you should always keep pushing yourself. In May the weather was starting to get nicer out, so on a crystal clear evening I setup the telescope because I wanted to try stacking multiple frames of the moon to get as sharp of an image as possible. I spent a while dialing in the focus and then took about 50 frames. After some wonderful visual observation I packed everything up and went in to see what I got. I sorted through and picked out the best 24 shots and then combined them in Photoshop. The result speaks for itself. Every crater and detail on the surface is tack sharp. I feel like I could reach out and run my hand across this image. I'd love to see it in a glass print from Fracture.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/catalog/0K6A5593.jpg&quot;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Waxing Gibbous Moon (24 frames)&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I didn't get out too much this year, so a large portion of my favorite photographs were from my &lt;a href=&quot;/post/2018/10/04/scramble.html&quot;&gt;New England Scramble&lt;/a&gt; so I won't go into too much detail again. First up was an abstract shot I took deliberately using a slow shutter speed while panning the camera. I love the color of the fall leaves with the white streak of the birch trunk in the middle. Stepping outside your comfort zone and shooting different subjects can yield unexpected results.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/catalog/0K6A7232.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another shot I like is from the drive up to Mt Washington, of a small cabin cozily nested among the changing trees. I suspect I missed peak foliage by about a week or two, but beggars can't be choosers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/catalog/0K6A7564.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This next photo was taken at the top of Mt Washington, one of dozens of small rock piles called cairns that I believe guide hikers along the summit. I especially love the different layers of mountains fading off into the distance. I'd like to see this in an oversized canvas wrap some day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/catalog/0K6A7398.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The next two photos were taken at the Portland Head Light in Portland ME. This was a bucket list location for me, so I couldn't decide which one I liked better. I took the first photo from the overlook on the south side of the lighthouse just as the sun crept over the horizon. It's a panorama of five individual shots stitched together, so the detail in the final result is impressive.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/catalog/head-light-sunrise.jpg&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Portland Head Light, Portland Maine&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Immediately after the sun was over the horizon I scrambled across to the north side of the park to shoot from another angle. I was able to get down onto a large field of rocks and capture the waves crashing over them as the sun came up catching the spray and bathing the entire scene in a warm glow.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/catalog/0K6A7138.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Portland Head Light, Portland Maine&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My final shot from 2018 was one I had wanted for years, and for more details you can read &lt;a href=&quot;/post/2018/12/26/iss-transit.html&quot; /&gt;my blog post about it&lt;/a&gt;. The morning after Christmas I was able to catch the ISS, illuminated, just before transiting the moon. It was my third try and second success, but by far the best capture I've made. The moon could be sharper due to it being so hazy on the ground, but overall I really love this one.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/posts/0K6A8260-2.jpg&quot;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;The ISS just before lunar transit&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While this has been my slowest year for photography in quite a while I am still happy with the results. I can't wait to get out for some shoots in 2019 and see where the year takes me.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 09 Jan 2019 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/post/2019/01/09/best-of-2018.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/post/2019/01/09/best-of-2018.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>post</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Capturing the ISS again</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Back in June I was able to &lt;a href=&quot;/astrophotography/2018/06/01/chasing-a-bullet.html&quot; target=&quot;blank&quot;&gt;photograph the ISS transiting the moon&lt;/a&gt; for the first time, and while I was generally happy with it, I knew I could do better. So ever since I have been keeping an eye on &lt;a href=&quot;https://transit-finder.com/&quot; target=&quot;blank&quot;&gt;transit-finder.com&lt;/a&gt; to see when I could get another chance to try again.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Just a few days before Christmas I saw a pass would occur to the west of me by a few miles, and as luck would have it, pass almost right over my friends Doug &amp;amp; Heather's house! Fantastic! The only thing was it was going to be at 5:58am, and the day after Christmas, meaning the weather was a definite wild card.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/posts/iss-third-attempt.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Using the transit finder tool to plot another ISS capture&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I woke up at 4:30am and poking my head outside saw it was pretty clear, just a slight haze around the moon. I packed everything up and jumped in the car, getting more and more concerned with the fog. Thankfully it was staying close to the ground and straight up was still pretty good.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I set everything up with a few minutes to spare and it started getting more and more hazy. Test shots in the camera still looked really good so I thought I would have a good chance. The ISS finder app on my phone indicated that it was tracking straight up and just breaking over the horizon, so I started visually scanning the sky for it. During my last attempt it was not lit by the sun so I couldn't see it until during transit. This time it was illuminated so it would look like a fast moving star. Depending on the altitude of the ISS and a few other factors the station can appear anywhere from very small to somewhat large in the sky. I was delighted to find it exactly where it should be, shining brightly and right on track to pass over the moon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure class=&quot;vertical&quot;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/posts/iss-third-just-before.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Spotting the ISS just before transit&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The bright speck just above the tree is the ISS, exactly where it should be, exactly on time. This time I was able to record the flyby on my iPhone since I wasn't crouched behind the scope looking through the camera. I watched it as it flew overhead, firing the remote just before transit. I got four frames just before, and another four as it passsed in front of the moon. I quickly disconnected my camera, checked out the preview, and let out a little yell.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here is the 8 frames I captured of the station just before and during transit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/posts/iss-third-stack-s.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;The International Space Station lunar transit 8 stack shot&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here is a close up of the station just before transit. It's one of the few times I have gone from what I see in my head to exactly what I see on the screen perfectly. That is always extremely satisfying.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/posts/0K6A8260-2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;The International Space Station just before transiting the moon&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I've wanted to capture this exact shot for &lt;i&gt;years&lt;/i&gt;, it took a lot of patience and a few attempts but it was worth the hard work. I am still blown away by the results. You can clearly see the structure of the station and even the color of the solar arrays. For an object moving at about 17,500mph I think it's pretty clear. I got lucky with the position, capturing it just before crossing over.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'm definitely hooked and will be trying to get even clearer shots in the future. At 51.41 arc seconds the station was fairly large, but I've seen transits listed in the 60's before. Just for reference my first successful attempt was only about 28 arc seconds. Always room for improvement!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Next up is the lunar eclipse in January, and possibly attempting an ISS solar transit. Stay tuned!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 26 Dec 2018 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/astrophotography/2018/12/26/iss-transit.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/astrophotography/2018/12/26/iss-transit.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>astrophotography</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>15 Years</title>
        <description>&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/posts/15-years.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Gorilla-Studios is celebrating 15 years of photography&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Exactly fifteen years ago, on December 12th, 2003, I launched Gorilla-Studios Photography as my online photography portfolio. I had been shooting since the mid 1990's, but had not gotten serious about my work until August of 2003. It was then that I purchased a 6.1MP Canon EOS 10D DSLR and fell in love with photography.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have been lucky enough to take my camera all over the world - from London, Tokyo, New York, and beyond. I've found my artistic style, seen my portfolio grow exponentially, and most importantly the quality of my work has dramatically improved as I have grown as an artist. I have two exhibitions in the coming months and can't wait to see where the future takes me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thank you for the support and here's to another 15!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 12 Dec 2018 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/post/2018/12/12/fifteen-years.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/post/2018/12/12/fifteen-years.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>post</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>New England Scramble</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I was in Boston this past weekend for work and had a little bit of time to explore afterwards. I've had the Portland Head Light on my photography bucket list for years, so I wasn't going to pass up the opportunity. Also since the fall colors were just starting to pop I jumped in the car and headed up to New Hampshire so I could do the Mt Washington Auto Road.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/posts/0K6A7407.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was nervous on the way up because a lot of the trees weren't changing at all, but was relieved the further north I got as I saw some wonderful colors on the way up. By the time I arrived at the base of the mountain things were looking great, although it was still a little bit early. I have a feeling the colors are going to absolutely explode next week, but it was nice to see it starting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure class=&quot;vertical&quot;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/catalog/0K6A7573.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As I pulled in to start the climb I was behind an intrepid couple in an old Austin Healey 3000 convertible. Kudos to them as while the temperature at the base was in the 70s, it was much much cooler at the summit. A large group of motorcyclists took off, as well as the Austin. Just before I started I spotted an old Land Cruiser coming down.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/posts/0K6A7262.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/catalog/0K6A7564.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The drive is a slow climb up 6000 ft with lots of places to stop on the way up. I tried my hand at some intentional camera movement to just capture the colors I was seeing. This next shot is of a birch tree that was surrounded by bright orange leaves. I rotated it to a landscape orientation just to make it a bit more abstract.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/catalog/0K6A7232.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As you drive back and forth up the switchbacks you start realizing how much elevation you are gaining and as a kid from Illinois it's always a treat being on anything taller than a small hill. This was a shot I had wanted since I flew to Los Angeles years ago and snapped a similar photo from out the plane window. The layers of mountains off into the distance was surprisingly calming, the photo really doesn't do it justice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/catalog/0K6A7391.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In addition to driving up or taking the cog railway, there are five hiking trails available. Talking to people at the top it sounds like you can make it all the way up in about four hours if you are experienced or most of the day if you take your time. The trails are spotted with these interesting and beautiful rock piles called cairns, to guide people up the mountain.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/catalog/0K6A7339.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the top is a large parking lot, a visitors center, lookout, a few large radio &amp;amp; cell antenna, as well as some small huts. A plaque states that the highest wind speed ever recorded, a staggering 231mph, happened here in 1934. Because of this some of the buildings are literally chained down. The Tip Top Shop is made out of stacked stones where I found one of the side windows very interesting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/catalog/0K6A7385.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As soon as I got out of the car I realized how cold it was but it didn't really click until about twenty minutes later. Walking around I started seeing strange white things in the grass, they looked almost like coarsely chopped onions. It wasn't until I walked around to the back of one of the buildings when I realized that it was ice! The shingle siding was completely covered in ice, built up from the howling wind.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/catalog/0K6A7355.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/catalog/0K6A7398.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not long after that I spotted the cog railway train working its way up the mountain. I was surprised at the angle it was climbing up at, the tour guide was leaning out the front at quite an angle. I learned that the seats inside the train are also at a significant angle, so when the train is on flat terrain its a bit awkward. I kept the camera level relative to the horizon to show how it was pulling into the station.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure class=&quot;vertical&quot;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/catalog/0K6A7466.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The railway runs three trains, two run on biodiesel, but a third is a coal-fired steam locomotive. After the green train pulled into the station I spotted the plume of smoke coming around into view. You can see how the engine is angled downward, I'm assuming to keep the boiler as close to level as possible during the climb.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/catalog/0K6A7487.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/catalog/0K6A7517.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Just before leaving the clouds came sweeping in and visibility dropped to nothing. While hanging around for a few minutes seeing if it would clear up I looked down at my feet and noticed that at one of the trail heads people had left rocks hand signed with little messages and pictures - family names, locations, well wishes, etc. What a great idea. Next time when I bring the family I'll be sure to remember a few colored sharpies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/catalog/0K6A7558.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The next morning I got up at an ungodly hour to head over to the famous Portland Head Light in Portland Maine, and it was definitely worth the trip. Crossing my fingers as I arrived I found the gate open at 5:30am just as some other photographers said it most likely would be. I was the first one down there, but as sunrise approached a few more intrepid souls joined me at the overlook just south of the lighthouse. I took a 5 shot panorama just as the sun started breaking over the horizon. Using my Lee Big Stopper filter I manually varied my exposures from 10 seconds on the far right to 20 seconds on the left most exposure. It was tricky but well worth the trouble.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/catalog/head-light-sunrise.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Knowing I only had a few minutes I grabbed my gear and sprinted over to the other side of the lighthouse to get another angle before losing the good light. On the north side of the lighthouse there was an overlook with a large field of positively beautiful rounded stones along with some huge boulders. I got some shots from the overlook but it wasn't grabbing me. While the other side had a chain link fence that was obvious you shouldn't go past, here there was only a small orange cone on a path. I took a shot and made my way down to the water, laying flat on a large boulder to get a better composition.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/catalog/0K6A7138.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Just after I snapped this last shot a &lt;strong&gt;massive&lt;/strong&gt; cruise ship came around from behind, completely ruining any more shots. I felt happy with what I got and climbed my way back up. Knowing I had to be back at Logan airport in Boston I headed out to get some breakfast and make my way back to Chicago.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another trip where I only had a few hours but I made the most of my time. I absolutely loved Maine and New Hampshire and am definitely going to take the family back here next year when the colors are in their prime to see everything and soak it all in without scrambling to get from one place to another.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 04 Oct 2018 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/post/2018/10/04/scramble.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/post/2018/10/04/scramble.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>post</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Loupedeck+ First Impressions</title>
        <description>&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/posts/loupedeck-box.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Loupedeck+ Box&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I've had my eye on the &lt;a href=&quot;https://loupedeck.com&quot; target=&quot;blank&quot;&gt;Loupedeck&lt;/a&gt; console for quite some time so last week I finally pulled the trigger and ordered their new + version. It was originally a Kickstarter project designed for editing photos in Lightroom using dedicated physical buttons, dials, and sliders. Recently Loupedeck released an updated version called the Loupedeck+. The console works with Lightroom Classic CC, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.phaseone.com/en/Products/Software/Capture-One-Pro/Highlights.aspx&quot; target=&quot;blank&quot;&gt;Capture One Pro&lt;/a&gt; (which I have been meaning to check out), and another program called &lt;a href=&quot;https://skylum.com/aurorahdr&quot; target=&quot;blank&quot;&gt;Aurora HDR&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It arrived in a few days and I was immediately impressed with the packaging. The box was nicely designed and the console itself was wrapped in a sturdy foam enclosure making sure it could survive any bumps and drops during shipping.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It has a nice weight to it, but it's not too heavy. The knobs and dials are all crisp and feel great while spinning. It's just about as wide as my 15&quot; Macbook Pro and has a very low profile so when I set it in front I can quickly reach over it to use my trackpad or keyboard.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/posts/loupedeck-in-box.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Loupedeck+ interior packaging&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;Installation and setup&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The instructions were very adamant that you install the software before plugging in the console so I downloaded and installed it with no issues. The Loupedeck+ connects over and is powered by a standard USB connector. I plugged it in, fired up Lightroom, and was delighted by a brief message saying &quot;Loupedeck thinks you look lovely&quot;. Unfortunately that feeling didn't last long as I started spinning knobs but nothing happened. I tried unplugging and plugging it in, restarting the Loupedeck application, restarting Lightroom, even tried a different USB-C adapter, no luck. Nothing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After a lot of troubleshooting I eventually found out I was running Lightroom CC Classic (2015), &lt;i&gt;not&lt;/i&gt; Lightroom Classic CC. Once I updated Lightroom everything worked perfectly. Crisis avoided. One side note: apparently it doesn't support the new cloud-based Creative Cloud (don't get me started on Adobe's naming conventions).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/posts/loupedeck-instructions.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Loupedeck+ instructions&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A lot of reviews online complain about the build quality. I've spent about a week with it and I can tell you the build quality is great for the most part. My one concern is the large control dial - it wobbles a bit more than I would prefer, but I think it should hold up okay. Looking at the dates of said reviews I think the majority of them were about the first version, where as I have the second revision.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The other significant question online was does this make your editing process faster? While I've only used it a handful of time so far I can tell you for sure, yes it does. Not having to hunt for specific panels and sliders in the sidebar is a blessing. Instead of shifting my focus back and forth between the photo to the sidebar I can see the photo full screen and use the Loupedeck while my eyes stay where they need to be. I'm starting to get a feel for where each control knob is and I'm sure I will get faster the more muscle memory I build up. All the controls have a great amount of sensitivity, so making subtle changes to things like color temperature are easy without swinging too far one way or the other. So far the only control that I can't use the console for is adjusting my tone curve.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One neat thing about the knobs and dials is that you can press down on them and it will reset that adjustment back to the default setting. Very handy, and a nice touch.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/posts/loupedeck-settings.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Loupedeck+ control panel&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are dedicated controls for your HSL levels, exposure, contrast, clarity, shadows, highlights, blacks, whites, vibrance, color temperature, and tint. Additionally, there are also buttons for things like viewing a before &amp;amp; after, color labels and star ratings, black &amp;amp; white development, and more. On top of all that, there are 17 programmable buttons you can customize to fit your workflow. I haven't learned about the Custom Mode toggle yet, but I assume that's even more customization. In the control panel you can click on any of the custom function controls and map it to just about any function in Lightroom (see below).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/posts/loupedeck-custom-settings.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Loupedeck+ control panel custom settings&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Overall I am really happy with the purchase. The build quality is great, and after using it to edit a handful of photos I really like using it. I'll share my thoughts in a few months after I get more comfortable using this in my workflow, but right now I am very optimistic that it's going to become a valuable addition to my process. Stay tuned!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 06 Sep 2018 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/post/2018/09/06/loupedeck.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/post/2018/09/06/loupedeck.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>post</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Chasing a bullet</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;For as long as I can remember I've always been fascinated by everything to do with space. Recently, I tore through Mike Massimino's book &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/Spaceman-Astronauts-Unlikely-Journey-Universe-ebook/dp/B01A4B1SK0/ref=sr_1_1?ie=UTF8&amp;qid=1527892448&amp;sr=8-1&amp;keywords=mike+massimino&quot; target=&quot;blank&quot;&gt;&lt;i&gt;Spaceman&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt; and now am reading &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/Interstellar-Age-Forty-Year-Voyager-Mission-ebook/dp/B00L9AXW4G/ref=sr_1_1?s=digital-text&amp;ie=UTF8&amp;qid=1527892488&amp;sr=1-1&amp;keywords=interstellar+age&quot; target=&quot;blank&quot;&gt;&lt;i&gt;The Interstellar Age&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, which is about NASA's Voyager 1 &amp;amp; 2 missions. My daughter delights in watching Commander Chris Hadfield's videos from the International Space Station so much that we've seen every one many many times, and I've watched both series of Cosmos multiple times. Since I am a certified Space Geek, it's only natural that I try to combine that with my passion for photography.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the coolest photos I have ever seen is of the Space Shuttle docking with International Space Station while in transit past the sun, but I always wondered how on earth did they do that? Could I do that? The station itself is orbiting the earth 250 miles up moving at 17,500mph, which makes photographing it like chasing a bullet. The first hurdle was to find a tool to tell me where and when it would be. After some searching I stumbled across &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.transit-finder.com&quot; target=&quot;blank&quot;&gt;Transit Finder&lt;/a&gt; which when given lat/long and date range would tell me exactly where and when I needed to be down to the millisecond.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/posts/iss-transit/options.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Transit Finder results&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Results listing&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Not surprisingly, options are limited if you don't want to travel a few hours to make an attempt. I checked the site weekly for at least a year, but most opportunities slipped by due to scheduling conflicts or just poor weather. I finally made my first attempt a month ago on May 1st at sunrise. I rolled out of bed at 4:30 and drove 45 minutes south to see if I could capture the ISS just before moonset set. To track the path of the ISS I used an iPhone app called SkyView Lite, and everything looked perfect. I was ready.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;vertical&quot;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/posts/iss-transit/IMG_8517.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;SkyView Lite&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Looking good&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I checked my phone a few more times, and when I got about two minutes out I just sat there, staring through the camera's eye piece watching as hard as I could. Waiting. Waiting. Waiting. Nothing. Checked the app again and the ISS had blown right past - I had no idea if it was close, I never even spotted it. I was disappointed, but determined to figure out what happened. When I got home I realized that at the time the ISS was illuminated and would have appeared as a white spot reflecting sunlight, while I was looking for the distinct black silhouette. Okay, rookie mistake. I made a note and went back to checking Transit Finder every few days.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally two weeks ago I saw a favorable opportunity where I could get to the center line only having to travel about 25 minutes from home, and 12:06pm was reasonable. I plotted out three backup sites just incase of unforeseen impediments. The spot I chose was a back road off the beaten path where I could setup and hopefully not be bothered. I had the time, I had the place, now the only x-factor was the weather.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/posts/iss-transit/gilberts.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Plotting my spot&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Plotting the best spot&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That night I packed up my gear and despite some intermittent clouds, headed out. I found the location easily enough thanks to scouring Google Maps a few times a day during the past week. Checking SkyView Lite I was a bit confused - the ISS was tracking to rise in the West just a few minutes before it was due to cross the Moon in the South East. I still setup my gear but kept an eye on the station wondering if the app was wrong. I knew it travelled fast but didn't realize it would shoot horizon to horizon in a matter of minutes. By the time I got the telescope setup and tracking the Moon I checked SkyView again and saw the ISS was already directly at the zenith and headed to intersect the Moon at an alarming pace.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Just like my first attempt I had my eye glued to the eyepiece for a few minutes, concentrating on where the station should begin it's transit. I glanced up once or twice to see if I could catch it with my naked eye, but no luck. Finally I spotted it coming out from between the Sea of Serenity and the Sea of Tranquility, and mashed the remote cable release. I successfully got nine frames of the ISS transiting the Moon.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;vertical&quot;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/catalog/iss-transit.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;ISS Lunar Transit&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;ISS Lunar Transit&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I checked the image previews as fast as I coulld and let out a yell. I had gotten it! It's angular size was 27.46&quot; so it was much smaller than ideal, but you could still see the distinct shape cutting across the lunar surface. After importing the images and doing some minor tweaks, I stacked them in Photoshop and set the blending mode to stack each frame together, creating the final composite.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Looking at other opportunities in Transit Finder I realize that the stations angular size can vary from the low 20s all the way into the 60s, meaning it would appear two to three times bigger in ideal conditions. I'm going to keep trying for some better results and will probably try a solar transit at some point. Anyway, as Neil deGrasse Tyson always says, keep looking up!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jun 2018 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/astrophotography/2018/06/01/chasing-a-bullet.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/astrophotography/2018/06/01/chasing-a-bullet.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>astrophotography</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>52 Book Challenge - Exhibitions &amp;amp; Adams</title>
        <description>&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/posts/week-2-3.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;This weeks books are Exhibiting Photography and Ansel Adams: Divine Performance&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'm keeping up with my reading challenge, but was side tracked by getting the flu which knocked me out for almost a week. During the down time I was able to tear through two books. First up was in preparation for my upcoming show at the local library called &lt;i&gt;Exhibiting Photography - a practical guide to displaying your work&lt;/i&gt; by Shirley Read. The second was &lt;i&gt;Ansel Adams - Divine Performance&lt;/i&gt; by Anne Hammond.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;Exhibiting Photography&lt;/i&gt; is a dense book covering a variety of methods for displaying your work in public which I found very helpful. In the book there are a number of case studies walking through real world projects, covering the process from start to finish. I'll definitely be re-checking this one out as my exhibition comes closer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am primarily a landscape photographer, so of course I was going to get a book on Ansel Adams. I was surprised by this one though, most books I've thumbed through are mostly just portfolio studies, where as &lt;i&gt;Divine Performance&lt;/i&gt; takes a large portion of the book talking about his life. I wasn't aware that he was an extremely talented musician as well as the grandfather of landscape photography. While it's a great read, it's not a book I'm going to put on my shelf as a part of my permanent collection - I would much prefer one of his portfolio studies that I can pick up and just soak in his photographs.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 29 Jan 2018 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/post/2018/01/29/book-challenge.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/post/2018/01/29/book-challenge.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>post</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
