<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Gorilla-Studios Photography</title>
    <description>Gorilla-Studios Photography</description>
    <link>http://www.gorilla-studios.com/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://www.gorilla-studios.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
      <item>
        <title>Week 34 - Bret Michaels</title>
        <description>&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/bm/4.jpg&quot;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Bret Michaels Band - &lt;i&gt;CD &amp;amp; Me August 22nd&lt;/i&gt;&lt;span&gt;1/250th, f/2.8, ISO3200&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This week proved that you can&#39;t give up and hard work eventually pays off. I have been
reaching out to bands, venues, and promoters trying to get into a larger concert for quite
some time now and I finally got in touch with a stage manager who hooked me up with my first
official press pass to see The Bret Michaels Band in Frankfort, IL on Friday night.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was a medium sized outdoor festival, and to my dismay there was no photo pit. Bret
had sold out the first two rows as part of a meet-and-greet package, and the seats were right
up against the stage - I knew getting in close was going to be a challenge. I used a Canon
70-200mm 2.8 so I knew I had some reach, and combined with my height it wasn&#39;t a major issue.
I was able to visualize my shots with a few practice shots of the first opener, and then dial in
my exposure settings during Driven Under&#39;s set. The main problem of the evening turned out to be
the red LED lights that were blowing everything out when they turned on, which compromised more than
a few shots.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Just before Bret went on management told me I had a three song limit and then I had to
leave, which is fairly common for big acts so I wasn&#39;t shocked. The three songs went by in a blur,
but I was able stay cool and get the shots I wanted. I was on the left side of the stage for the first song
but quickly realized that since Bret is right handed, his hand and mic were covering up most of his
face. When the song ended I quickly darted behind stage and back out to the left side, getting much
better shots. It was a lot of fun to shoot a really professional act, and I think I got some great
pieces for my portfolio. Check out the rest of the shots &lt;a href=&#39;/bret-michaels&#39;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 26 Aug 2014 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://www.gorilla-studios.com/2014/08/26/photo52-week34/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.gorilla-studios.com/2014/08/26/photo52-week34/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Week 33 - Kodiak</title>
        <description>&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/kodiak/7.jpg&quot;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Kodiak&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Last week I went out with Kodiak, a local folk trio who just love playing
music. They asked to go out and get a few promo shots, as well as some fun
candids of them playing. We walked down to Montrose Beach on Lake Michigan and
they just started playing while I was getting set up. We shot around various locations
as the sun set, so I had to use a Speedlite on a remote trigger as fill light.
I shot with a 70-200mm 2.8 which is kind of an odd choice for group portraits,
but I like using it because I can stand rather far back and let them feel a bit
more natural, its nice not shoving a camera in their faces while they are just
trying to play. Additionally shooting at 3.5 or 4 really compresses and blows
out the background, putting all the focus on the band. It was a ton of fun and
I cant wait to be able to shoot them in concert soon.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 19 Aug 2014 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://www.gorilla-studios.com/2014/08/19/photo52-week33/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.gorilla-studios.com/2014/08/19/photo52-week33/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>NMOS14 - Chicago</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Last night a rally was held at Daley Plaza here in Chicago to show solidarity with
the people of Ferguson, MO. The demonstration centered around a moment of silence at 6:20pm.
Here are some of my photographs presented without comment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/posts/ferguson/1.jpg&quot;&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/posts/ferguson/2.jpg&quot;&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/posts/ferguson/3.jpg&quot;&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/posts/ferguson/4.jpg&quot;&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/posts/ferguson/5.jpg&quot;&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/posts/ferguson/6.jpg&quot;&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/posts/ferguson/15.jpg&quot;&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/posts/ferguson/7.jpg&quot;&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/posts/ferguson/14.jpg&quot;&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/posts/ferguson/13.jpg&quot;&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/posts/ferguson/12.jpg&quot;&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/posts/ferguson/11.jpg&quot;&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/posts/ferguson/8.jpg&quot;&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;figure class=&#39;vertical&#39;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/posts/ferguson/10.jpg&quot;&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/posts/ferguson/9.jpg&quot;&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 15 Aug 2014 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://www.gorilla-studios.com/2014/08/15/ferguson-chicago/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.gorilla-studios.com/2014/08/15/ferguson-chicago/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Week 32 - Porsche Speedster</title>
        <description>&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/p52/32.jpg&quot;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Porsche Speedster&lt;span&gt;1/100, f/2.8, ISO400&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This week my father and I finally got around to pulling his Porsche Speedster
replica out of the back of the garage, blowing off the dust and firing it up. We
spent the afternoon tinkering around with it and getting it back into running shape
after it sitting since last summer. As a surprise I wanted to take some glamor shots
of it to make a calendar or some framed prints for him, so I dug up my studio lights
and got to work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I wanted to go for more of a dramatic look where the background fades to black
because I expected to convert most shots to high-contrast black and white, so my key light
was a simple speedlight in a softbox on a light stand. The garage was only light by
a single light bulb on the ceiling, and the lightbox here was right against the passenger
rear tire shooting down into the cab. The steering wheel and gauge cluster look absolutely
fantastic so I grabbed my 50mm macro and shot at f/2.8 to make some really beautiful closeups.
I spent an hour or so shooting the interior, and once we get the car completely cleaned up I
would like to try some full body exterior shots.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 12 Aug 2014 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://www.gorilla-studios.com/2014/08/12/photo52-week32/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.gorilla-studios.com/2014/08/12/photo52-week32/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Rolliflex Kit</title>
        <description>&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/posts/rolliflex.jpg&quot;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Recesky 35mm TLR Camera Kit&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&#39;ve always wanted an original &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Rolleiflex&quot;&gt;Rolliflex Twin Lens Reflex camera&lt;/a&gt; but could never pull the trigger due to the cost
of one in good condition. I was poking around Amazon a few weeks ago and found some replica kits for only $25, so I
added it to my wish-list. Lo and behold one arrived at my door a few days after my birthday! The kit comes completely
disassembled, with a screwdriver and a single roll of 35mm ISO200 film.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/posts/rolliflex-assembly.jpg&quot;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Assembly&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Opening it up I was rather surprised &lt;i&gt;how much&lt;/i&gt; assembly was required. Everything down to the shutter was
in pieces, and unfortunately the instructions were obviously translated into English, meaning they were about as
clear as mud. Thankfully I know my way around a film camera so everything was fairly easy to figure out, the biggest
problem was that two of the shutter springs were mis-labelled. Once I figured that out assembly wasn&#39;t too bad.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The quality is exactly what you would expect from a $25 dollar kit. Everything is plastic and on the flimsier side,
but as completed kit it holds up okay. I will load it up with film and pick something to shoot in the next few days.
Stay tuned for the results.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Check out the kit at Amazon &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.amazon.com/dp/B004PALJBA/&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 11 Aug 2014 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://www.gorilla-studios.com/2014/08/11/rolliflex/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.gorilla-studios.com/2014/08/11/rolliflex/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Week 31 - Meadow Saxifrage</title>
        <description>&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/p52/31.jpg&quot;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Meadow Saxifrage&lt;span&gt;1/125, f/2.8, ISO50&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This week I wanted to mix it up a little bit and try practicing macro work again.
Years ago I bought a Quantaray 50mm macro, and from time to time I like to photograph
flowers and bugs up close. My parents work very hard on their gardens so the backyard
is an absolute playground for someone who wants to do flower-scapes. I grabbed
my gear and headed out to the backyard Sunday afternoon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Shooting at 50mm for subjects like this means getting the lens less than an inch or two
from the subject quite often, which means you block out a lot of natural light. To compensate
for this I used my flash off camera on a long cable. This allows me to use the flash hand-held,
giving me the flexibility to orientate it any way I needed. I kept the camera on my Manfrotto
tripod with the center column locked perpendicular to the legs, swinging the camera out over
the flowers instead of trying to make it work as a traditional tripod.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I started with some yellow daisies, but nothing was quite grabbing me. I wanted to get in
extremely close and hopefully wind up with a photo that could be printed and framed. I made
my way around the garden, eventually setting up directly above a large pot full of what I believe
are Meadow Saxifrage. They couldn&#39;t have been more than an inch across, so it was going to be
difficult to say the least. I struggled trying not to blow out the petals with the flash while
getting the exposure of the stamen correct, finally settling on 1/125th at 2.8, with the flash
stopped down to 1/32nd power with a puffer defuser, held just to the right of the lens. At 2.8
this close the depth of field was incredibly shallow - the stamen are sharp, as well as the edge
of the right most petal, with a little bit of details on each petal at the center. Two stems
directly underneath add just the right touch to break up what would have been a dull background.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 04 Aug 2014 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://www.gorilla-studios.com/2014/08/04/photo52-week31/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.gorilla-studios.com/2014/08/04/photo52-week31/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Week 30 - Millenium Park Busts</title>
        <description>&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/p52/30.jpg&quot;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Head Sculptures, Millenium Park&lt;span&gt;3.2s, f/8, ISO50&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This week I headed back down to Millenium Park in the heart of the Loop to check out
a new art installation just across the pavilion with The Bean. Artist Jaume Plensa has
created four female heads ranging from twenty-one to thirty-nine feet hight, yet only a
few feet wide. You can&#39;t tell from this perspective, but they have been skewed so as you walk from
where the photo was taken down towards them you quickly realize they are very thin. It&#39;s
quite an optical illusion and draws a large crowd. These three are located just east of
Crown Fountain, while the largest of the four is right on Michigan Ave at the entrance to
the park.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I had a difficult time shooting because the lighting just wasn&#39;t there. It was getting
very dark and I had hoped to pick up the buildings in the background, but the foreground
lighting just wasn&#39;t enough to balance the exposure. This is one of the earlier shots from
before sunset. I brightened up the trees to almost an infra-red like photo to create some
contrast. I am definitely going to go back to see what other kinds of photos I can get,
it really is something to check out if you are in the Loop.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 28 Jul 2014 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://www.gorilla-studios.com/2014/07/28/photo52-week30/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.gorilla-studios.com/2014/07/28/photo52-week30/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Week 29 - Archways</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;A few months ago while working at a client&#39;s office downtown, I used to go for walks at lunch
to explore the neighborhood and one day stumbled across Mary Bartelme Park. Located just west of the
loop it&#39;s a wonderful park with a playground, dog play area, and on the west end, a very interesting
piece of art. A series of five steel or aluminum archways at various angles stand about 12 ft square,
and are equipped with nozzles that spray a fine mist of water to cool off patrons during the hot
Chicago summers. While there I snapped a few photos with my iPhone and told myself to come back at some
point to shoot with my SLR. A few nights ago I finally got the chance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As I always say preparation goes a long way so I wanted to get there before sundown to set everything
up and make sure I had my composition locked in. I wanted to shoot very low to exaggerate the angles of
the arches, so I set my Manfrotto as low as it would go with the neck flipped at a 90 degree angle, the bottom of the camera only a few inches off
the pavement.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/posts/arch-prep.jpg&quot;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Preparation is key&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As the sun finally settled below the horizon and the lights came up, the sky faded to a beautiful purple
blue hue with a touch of pink to the south. The ideal lighting was only around for about fifteen to twenty
minutes so I knew I had to get something relatively quickly. I loved the colors of the shots I was taking,
but it was really lacking something. I had expected the water to be misting from the arches, however when
anyone tried to turn it on nothing happened. I&#39;m not sure where the idea came from, but I thought this would
be the perfect opportunity to try some light painting - problem was I don&#39;t carry a flashlight in my day pack.
Undeterred, I set the camera to a 10 second timer, turned on my iPhone flashlight, and proceeded to walk back and forth
waiving it with the flashlight towards the camera. My first exposure was just arcs headed from back to front -
not as dramatic as I was hoping for, but the light was showing up crystal clear. I fired off another ten
exposures or so, wildly waving my arm and running back and forth each time (what a workout). I
eventually got exactly what I wanted - windmilling the phone like Pete Townshend while slowly walking towards
the camera created this weeks photo. Probably the most unique and fun photo I have ever taken.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/portfolio/archways.jpg&quot;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Archways&lt;span&gt;30s, f/8, ISO200&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 22 Jul 2014 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://www.gorilla-studios.com/2014/07/22/photo52-week29/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.gorilla-studios.com/2014/07/22/photo52-week29/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Week 28 - Sears Tower</title>
        <description>&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/portfolio/blue-sky-walk.jpg&quot;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;July 14th - Sears Tower skyboxes&lt;span&gt;1/400, f/9, ISO100&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;No matter what I do I can&#39;t stop taking photos of the Sears Tower, I&#39;ve probably surpassed the thousand mark a while ago.
It doesn&#39;t help that I work just a few blocks from it, and on some days I like to go for a walk during lunch with my camera.
I&#39;ve said before that I love taking photos of it because you can get dramatically different shots from all angles of the
building. I wanted to see if I had enough reach at 200mm to see people in the skyboxes that jut out from the west side of
the tower over Wacker Drive. This particular angle was from the north west corner on the pedestrian island out front. I
particularly like that you can&#39;t instantly figure out what you are looking at, and its certainly not a photo of the Sears I
have seen before. There is a very subtle lens flare from the afternoon sun taking up the right side of the exposure, but I
feel it adds a bit of warmth and character.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 17 Jul 2014 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://www.gorilla-studios.com/2014/07/17/photo52-week28/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.gorilla-studios.com/2014/07/17/photo52-week28/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Prints for sale</title>
        <description>&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/posts/for-sale.jpg&quot;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Select prints are available from 500px.com&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am pleased to announce that select prints from my portfolio are now &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.500pxart.com/gorilla-studios&quot;&gt;available for purchase at 500px.com&lt;/a&gt;. Eight beautiful photographs
are currently available in various sizes on framed paper, canvas wrap, aluminum, or acrylic. You can see them &lt;a href=&quot;/store/&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; or at
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.500pxart.com/gorilla-studios&quot;&gt;500px.com&lt;/a&gt;.  More photos will be added in the future so keep an eye out, or you can always request a print to become available.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 16 Jul 2014 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://www.gorilla-studios.com/2014/07/16/prints-for-sale/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.gorilla-studios.com/2014/07/16/prints-for-sale/</guid>
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
