<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Gorilla-Studios Photography</title>
    <description>Focusing on stunning landscape and high-energy music photography, Gorilla-Studios has been the online home of my portfolio since 2003. I specialize in landscapes, cityscapes and architecture, nature, candid portraiture, headshots, band promos and concert photography.
</description>
    <link>http://gorilla-studios.com</link>
    <atom:link href="http://gorilla-studios.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>London Travelogue</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This past week I flew over to London for work and while I was there I had a few nights to go out and explore a bit. I fly out of O&#39;Hare airport and knowing this I have a good idea as to what the flight path will be. With this knowledge I try to get a window seat on the side of the plane that will present the best opportunities to me on both takeoff or landing. Monday this forethought paid off.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;O&#39;Hare is located just north west of Chicago proper so a lot of eastbound flights pass either right over the city or just to the north. The flight took off and just seconds after getting airborne I was treated with a wonderful view of the city being bathed in a warm afternoon light. Shooting out of airplane windows is usually a toss up, so getting anything is a miracle. I fired off a bunch of shots as we passed overhead, but I like this one the most.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/posts/0K6A1328.jpg&quot;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Chicago skyline&lt;span&gt;1/320th, f/8, ISO500&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While coming into London I was absentmindedly shooting some Hyperlapse videos as we were getting close to landing. The plane banked hard making the sun popped out over the wing, blinding me for a few seconds. When we leveled back out and I could see again I recognized that we were going to pass right over the heart of the city on approach. I scrambled and grabbed my camera out of my bag and started firing off more shots hoping to get something similar to when we took off. Unfortunately the window was polarizing pretty bad, so all the shots I took had a very significant color shift over the entire frame. Despite this I had fun with one I took looking straight down at the London Eye over the Thames river. The only way to make this even close to presentable was to convert it to black and white which I really didn&#39;t want to do, so I figured why not have some fun and make it a tilt-shift as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/posts/0K6A1377.jpg&quot;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;London tilt-shift&lt;span&gt;1/200th, f/4, ISO125&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After work I ran back to my hotel because it was raining very heavily and crashed after having some dinner. Unfortunately due to jetlag I woke up around 10:30, fully awake, so I decided to go for a brief walk since the storms had passed. Since it was around 11pm on a Tuesday night the city was virtually empty. Typically after magic-hour at sunset I pack it in and don&#39;t shoot when the sky is completely black, but I wanted to use the limited time I had so I went ahead and tried to get what I could. I took a few exposures but wasn&#39;t thrilled until a young couple came over the bridge headed towards me, suddenly pausing at the apex to share a long kiss. I made a 25 second exposure which was just enough to get them during their embrace with a little motion between the two.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/catalog/0K6A1402.jpg&quot;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;St. Pauls and Jubilee Bridge&lt;span&gt;f/8, 90s, ISO50&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A few exposures later I felt I wanted to try another angle, so I walked down to the south end of the bridge where the walkway switches back on itself presenting some interesting lines. From this angle we get multiple layers in the composition - the dark night sky and great dome, the top level of the bridge and railings, a brief glimpse at the river with the brilliant colors reflecting on the water, and finally the lower walkway. This is a definite example of stepping outside of my comfort zone as I usually prefer very simple compositions and a limited color palette.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/catalog/0K6A1411.jpg&quot;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;St. Pauls from Jubilee Bridge&lt;span&gt;f/8, 30s, ISO50&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Continuing down to the river walk this next frame is from just east of the bridge. Previously I had tried this angle that was zoomed in tight to the dome with a small piece of the bridge in the foreground but I wasn&#39;t thrilled with it. This night I wanted to capture a wider view since the colors reflecting off the river were very vibrant against the deep purple sky.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/catalog/0K6A1416.jpg&quot;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;St. Pauls and Jubilee Bridge&lt;span&gt;f/8, 90s, ISO50&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I followed the river walk down to More London Riverside, located right by Tower Bridge and city hall. My goal was to re-shoot a photo I had taken during the day last time that I knew I could improve upon. There is a small walkway leading towards city hall with a number of interesting buildings that a lot of people would pay no attention to. On my last trip I looked up and took a photo of one of them at 19mm, not thinking much of it until I saw it in post when I got home.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This time I could use my 16-35 f/4 wide open and get even more of the surrounding buildings, and shooting at night I wouldn&#39;t have a completely blown out sky. I collapsed my tripod all the way down and laid on the ground looking almost completely up - the security guard had a good chuckle but didn&#39;t bother me since I was the only one there. I love how this one turned out, especially after running it through Silver Efex Pro. Note - if you haven&#39;t heard, Google just released the entire NIK Collection for free, so go &lt;a href=&quot;#&quot;&gt;download them now&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/catalog/0K6A1420.jpg&quot;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;More London Riverside&lt;span&gt;f/8, 32s ISO50&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On my last trip while shooting this area I focused primarily on Tower Bridge, getting some amazing panoramas. Knowing I already had those in my portfolio I tried to take some more interesting and unique photos of City Hall and &#39;the scoop&#39;, an interesting public space that hosts art installations and various presentations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/catalog/0K6A1426.jpg&quot;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;City Hall&lt;span&gt;f/9, 30s ISO50&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After work the next day I headed down towards Jubilee Gardens at the foot of the London Eye. While waiting for the sun to set I took some different angles of the ferris wheel pods, did some people watching, and mainly just relaxed a little bit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/catalog/0K6A1442.jpg&quot;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;The London Eye&lt;span&gt;1/200th, f/6.3, ISO250&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I sat down on and set up my tripod to shoot wide open at 16mm an interesting angle that I hadn&#39;t seen before of the Eye and Elizabeth Tower in the background with these unique trees in the foreground. With a slow enough shutter speed I was hoping to get blurs of people walking around, so I attached a variable ND filter, slowing my exposures down to around 2-4 seconds each. Suddenly the sky over Elizabeth Tower lit up with vibrant pinks and purples, so I captured this photo before scrambling to get my 70-200mm out for some close ups.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/catalog/0K6A1542.jpg&quot;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;London Eye at sunset&lt;span&gt;4s, f/9, ISO50&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I hoped that the whole sky would light up, but it was limited to the cloud cover down river from me. So I swapped in my 70-200mm 2.8, took my camera off the tripod, and went in close on Elizabeth Tower. I knew I only had a minute or two of perfect lighting so I had to find the right composition and fast. I wanted to be in tight on the tower with the beautiful sunset behind, but I also wanted some interesting people in the foreground as well as a little bit of the London Eye on the left side of the frame.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure class=&quot;vertical&quot;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/catalog/0K6A1546.jpg&quot;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Elizabeth Tower at sunset&lt;span&gt;1/160th, f/2.8, ISO1000&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Just as I had expected the color show had faded within minutes, so I packed up and headed over to the Golden Jubilee footbridge for another viewpoint from over the river. It was difficult to get a sharp exposure from the bridge as trains were rumbling past every few minutes, but I was able to figure out the timing and continue working. As I was putting together a four shot panorama a party boat passed directly underneath me creating a wonderful light trail leading right back into the center of the frame. This shot is the four frames stitched together, each around 90 seconds long.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/catalog/london-eye-2016-pano.jpg&quot;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Downtown London from Golden Jubilee Bridge&lt;span&gt;90s, f/8, ISO50&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I only had two nights to go out, but I tried to get what I could. Next time I go back I want to shoot more street photography and non-touristy locations. Looking forward to my next trip whenever that may be.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Apr 2016 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <link>http://gorilla-studios.com//blog/2016/04/01/london.html</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">http://gorilla-studios.com//blog/2016/04/01/london.html</guid>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building a custom time-lapse slider</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I have been sketching out ideas for a custom built time-lapse slider for probably years now, so when I opened up an Arduino Uno on Christmas day I realized its time to get on with it and put something together. It should be a straight forward build, as it&#39;s only comprised of a few components: a set of rails for the camera to slide on, a stepper motor to move the dolly the camera will be on, a shutter release, and a controller to coordinate the shutter release and camera movement.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/posts/slider-notes.jpg&quot;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;My initial sketch and brain dump&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The goal of this build is to have something simple I can shoot basic time-lapses with, nothing more than that. It&#39;s a learning exercise. Could I go drop $2000 on a pro-grade rig and be out shooting this weekend? Sure, but where is the fun in that? No, it won&#39;t have a rotating ball head, or carbon fiber components, but it also doesn&#39;t have the massive price tag. I think I can complete this build with about $100 worth of parts. So lets get started.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With daytime time-lapses you don&#39;t need to worry about alternating movement and capture as the shutter speeds will be so fast it won&#39;t impact the exposure, however I want to shoot sunrises, sunsets, and at night which means exposures of 15-30 seconds each, so movement during exposure is a no-go. Thats where the Arduino comes in. The Arduino will alternate between opening the shutter for a set amount of time, then shifting the camera while the shutter is closed between shots.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first step is wiring up the shutter release to the Arduino board so in essence it can talk to the camera.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/posts/remote-prototype.jpg&quot;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Breadboarding the shutter controls&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I took my old Canon RS-80 shutter release cable and removed the plastic housing around the button to reveal it&#39;s simply 3 wires attached to metal reeds. When you depress the button two reeds come into contact activating the AF, and when all three touch it completes the circuit, activating the shutter. For time-lapses I always use manual focus, so I can ignore one wire right off the bat. That means all I have to do is plug the two wires into a breadboard and use the Arduino to complete the circuit. I plugged everything in and wrote a quick script to open the shutter for 1 second, close it, wait a second, and repeat.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/posts/uno-program-1.jpg&quot;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Arduino code - getting started&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I pushed the program over to the Uno and the camera started taking 1 second exposures every 2 seconds. It&#39;s not much, but it&#39;s a great start. Next up is wiring up the stepper motor and alternating between activating it and opening the shutter. The &lt;a target=&quot;blank&quot; href=&quot;https://brainy-bits.com/shop/new/nema-17-stepper-motor/&quot;&gt;stepper motor&lt;/a&gt; is on the way, so I&#39;ll be working on this in the next week or so. I&#39;ll be giving periodic updates as everything comes together, and when I am done I will provide a parts list and instructions. Here&#39;s a rough list of tasks to complete and using the Agile mindset from work these are my epics to hit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;input type=&quot;checkbox&quot; checked=&quot;checked&quot;&gt;Get Arduino to control shutter&lt;/input&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;input type=&quot;checkbox&quot;&gt;Get Arduino to control stepper motor&lt;/input&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;input type=&quot;checkbox&quot;&gt;Arduino shield to enable shutter speed variable definition in the field&lt;/input&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;input type=&quot;checkbox&quot;&gt;Build actual slider and camera mount&lt;/input&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;input type=&quot;checkbox&quot;&gt;Calculate stepper motor rotations for full range of movemnt&lt;/input&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;input type=&quot;checkbox&quot;&gt;Reed switches for either end to act as stoppers&lt;/input&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;input type=&quot;checkbox&quot;&gt;Program Arduino for variable shutter speed input, slider speed, and reed stops to limit movement&lt;/input&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;input type=&quot;checkbox&quot;&gt;Power source?&lt;/input&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;input type=&quot;checkbox&quot;&gt;Wire up PCB and build Arduino enclosure&lt;/input&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;input type=&quot;checkbox&quot;&gt;Test&lt;/input&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Stay tuned&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Jan 2016 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
      <link>http://gorilla-studios.com//blog/2016/01/20/slider-project-1.html</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">http://gorilla-studios.com//blog/2016/01/20/slider-project-1.html</guid>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My top 10 images of 2015</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;After dragging my feet for a long time I decided that 2016 would be the year I took the plunge and switched my workflow over to Adobe Lightroom. Inspired by Martin Bailey&#39;s Photography Blogcast, I kicked things off by following a yearly tradition where he goes through and shares his top 10 images from the last calendar year. This is an amazing exercise in how to trim down your body of work to showcase only your very best. I highly recommend listening to the &lt;a target=&quot;blank&quot; href=&quot;http://www.martinbaileyphotography.com/2016/01/04/my-personal-top-ten-photos-for-2015-podcast-504/&quot;&gt;episode where he explains this process in detail&lt;/a&gt;, it&#39;s a must for every photographer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lightroom allows you to set a &#39;target&#39; collection so when you are in grid view you can simply tap the B key and add the selected photo into that collection. I started by filtering my entire library to only show shots in 2015 with a rating of 3 stars or higher. Then, going through with an editors mindset I started filling up my &#39;2015 Candidates&#39; collection. After my first pass I was around 45 photos which wasn&#39;t too bad. I switched over to view the collection and started removing the ones that didn&#39;t wow me. A few passes later I was down to about 20 which is where it starts getting difficult. Martin Bailey talks about editing photos which most people confuse with post-processing. Editing your photos means selecting which ones to display and which ones to shelve. Other photographers stress being ruthless in this process and often use the term &#39;killing your babies&#39;, which doesn&#39;t sit well with me. The main point is not to become emotionally attached to a photo that might not be as strong as you think.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/posts/lightroom.jpg&quot;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Getting organized with Lightroom&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So lets take a look at, in my opinion, my best work of the 2015 calendar year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first shot I selected was actually intended to be a temporary scouting photo to be re-taken over the summer. In early March I took the L to Adams &amp;amp; Wabash, where I quietly setup my tripod on the overpass between the tracks, looking North towards Trump tower. My goal was to get the trains streaking past in both directions, but it was so cold I didn&#39;t stay for very long. This particular exposure was 15 seconds, f/8, at ISO100.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/chicago/over-the-l.jpg&quot;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Adams &amp;amp; Wabash&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In May I took my second trip to London and while I was there I had a small amount of free time to re-capture some images I wasn&#39;t happy with from my first visit. One evening I headed down to the Queen Elizabeth Bridge at sunset and took a series of long exposures of the London Eye over the Thames River. During this shot a tourist boat made its way down river leaving a wonderful light trail along the water. 60 seconds, f/9, ISO50.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/london/london-eye-2015.jpg&quot;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;The London Eye&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Back in Chicago over the summer I picked up a small commission project for some black &amp;amp; white abstract architectural photos for an art dealer in Canada. I spent a few afternoons walking around the Loop and trying some new techniques as I hadn&#39;t really done much abstract work before. My favorite shot from the set was taken from the base of Trump tower in its loading dock on the North side of the building, where very few pedestrians venture. Looking up at a slight angle created almost a layered look from the base, midsection, and main body of the tower. Taken at 1/500th, f/9, ISO100.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/black-white/trump-abstract.jpg&quot;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Trump Tower Chicago&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In August I headed downstate to shoot the Bigfoot Bandcamp where a large number of acts performed, my favorite of which were The Krank Daddies and Reverent Horton Heat. I selected three photos from the evening, starting with probably the most Rock n Roll photo I have taken - Chops McClintock of The Krank Daddies taking a second in the middle of a song to pound a beer. It was a really high energy set, and this frame captures the essence of it in all its glory. 1/250th, f/2.8, ISO2500.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure class=&quot;vertical&quot;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/bfbc/0K6A4393.jpg&quot;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;The Krank Daddies&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Reverend Horton Heat is a band that I had wanted to see for a very long time, so the fact that I got to shoot them at the same time was really exciting for me. It was a smaller festival so being right up against the stage gave me a lot of reach to get the Rev full frame. I usually hate having a mic in front of a singers face, but here it doesn&#39;t bother me so much as you can just tell he&#39;s in the moment singing and playing his big ol&#39; Gretsch guitar. 1/250th, f/2.8, ISO4000.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/bfbc/0K6A4708.jpg&quot;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Reverend Horton Heat&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During concerts I move around as much as possible to cover every angle the best I can. Sometimes being 6&#39;6&quot; is a hinderance when I am trying to be low-key shooting, but I can&#39;t help sticking out like a sore thumb sometimes - here it worked out in my favor. I was side stage towards the end of their set when Jimbo glanced in my direction as I was the only one over there. I raised my camera with the 70-200mm 2.8 on it which makes it really obvious I&#39;m taking your photo. When I did he looked straight down the barrel, threw up the horns, and then went straight back to playing. It was literally a second or two, but I got it, and I knew as soon as I released the shutter that it was probably the best shot of the night. I didn&#39;t even have to review the shot, I just kept on going until they wrapped up. 1/250th, f/2.8, ISO8000.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure class=&quot;vertical&quot;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/bfbc/0K6A4923.jpg&quot;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Jimbo - Reverend Horton Heat&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In November I found myself flying out to Los Angeles for a work event, but I was able to sneak up to Leo Carillo State Beach one evening and shoot a Pacific ocean sunset for the first time in my life. I was only there for maybe an hour and found it really challenging to keep the camera steady in the surf as the sands kept shifting, but I got a few shots I am happy with. I would really love to go back and spend more time there and a few other locations on the coast, but I am glad I got a few shots in during my brief stay. The first shot is of a few very large boulders as the waves slid up and down the beach. To give some perspective, the speck on top of the one closest to center is a seagull. 1.3 seconds, f/6.3, ISO1250.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/catalog/0K6A0772.jpg&quot;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Leo Carillo Beach&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The second shot from that night was not planned at all. When shooting landscapes I usually try to avoid man-made objects and keep them natural as possible, however as I was walking back to the car with soaked jeans I passed a life guard tower silhouetted against the fading sunset. The colors were brilliant so I set up my tripod again and made a few more exposures until the light was completely gone. 30 seconds, f/4, ISO100.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/catalog/0K6A0789.jpg&quot;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Leo Carillo Beach&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally in the middle of December I flew out to New York for a few days, staying in Carol Gardens in Brooklyn, a short walk from Brooklyn Bridge Park, one of my favorite spots. Having never shot a sunrise in Manhattan before I decided to get up at the break of dawn to lug my gear to a familiar spot along the river. With sunsets you usually get at least 30 to 45 minutes of great lighting, but I found with the sunrise I only had about 10. It went from almost pitch black to close to daylight seemingly in the blink of an eye. Thankfully I was set up and framed before the dramatic change in lighting so I got this exposure looking out over the river to the southern tip of Manhattan. 48 seconds, f/8, ISO50.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/catalog/0K6A7702.jpg&quot;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Manhattan skyline from Brooklyn&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My final selection of 2015 is actually a three shot panorama of One World Trade Center taken from North Cove Yacht Harbor along the Hudson River. I had shot nine frames here, but I am still struggling to get the buildings align correctly. The center stack of 3 merged well, although I would like to head over to the New Jersey side of the river and try to get One WTC with a long lens instead of being almost underneath it at 16mm. I still love the results here, the contrast is wonderful and I love how the clouds are moving by at quite a fast pace. 3 exposures of 30 seconds, f/8, ISO50.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure class=&quot;vertical&quot;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/catalog/one-wtc-bw-pano.jpg&quot;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;One World Trade Center&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thanks for reading, and Happy 2016 everyone!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Jan 2016 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
      <link>http://gorilla-studios.com//blog/2016/01/15/best-of-2015.html</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">http://gorilla-studios.com//blog/2016/01/15/best-of-2015.html</guid>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Leo Carillo Beach</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This past weekend I flew out to Los Angeles for a conference, and had a small amount of free time the night before so I drove up the Pacific Coast Highway to Leo Carillo State Beach. Having scouted this location on Google Maps weeks before flying out I had a very good idea of the shots I wanted to get, knowing that at sunset I only had a good hour of what I consider to be perfect light. I didn&#39;t know when I would be back out, so I had to make the most of my time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/posts/0K6A0637.jpg&quot;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;On approach to LAX&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One thing that Google Maps couldn&#39;t quite emphasize is how steep the cliffs leading down to the beach were. I thought it would be pretty easy to get around, so when I arrived I realized that it was actually incredibly steep and difficult to navigate. Despite the challenges I setup quickly and found a spot overlooking a rocky outcropping where a large number of Cormorants were drying off as the sun started to dip down to the horizon. I wanted to capture the motion of the waves breaking over the rocks which was rather challenging while maintaining a proper exposure. In this situation I really wish I had a graduated ND filter, but you do what you can with what you have.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/catalog/0K6A0660.jpg&quot;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Leo Carillo Beach&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I also didn&#39;t want to spend my limited time in one spot so after getting a few exposures I was satisfied with I collapsed my tripod down and made my way to the north section of the beach. It was actually rather tricky getting down as the sun was setting making it difficult to tell what were actual paths and what was just erosion from water run off. Once down on the beach I started photographing the backside of the rocky formation I was shooting from above on the cliff. The cormorants had flown away, but one seagull was perched atop the rocks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/catalog/0K6A0772.jpg&quot;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Leo Carillo Beach&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Continuing north there were a few interesting rocks half buried in the sand like icebergs, poking out and breaking up the water as the waves quickly slid up the beach. I lowered my tripod all the way down and got almost on top of one, being extremely cautious of the incoming tide. Waves were making their way up the beach at a good rate, a few of which soaked my jeans that I had rolled up over my knees. I started opening up the shutter for 2 to 5 seconds a time smoothing out the water as it wrapped around the rocks and receded back.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/catalog/0K6A0758.jpg&quot;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Leo Carillo Beach&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/catalog/0K6A0753.jpg&quot;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Leo Carillo Beach&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/catalog/0K6A0760.jpg&quot;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Leo Carillo Beach&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The sun had gone down completely at this point and light was disappearing fast, so I had to make my way back up to the road before I lost all light and it would be rather dangerous walking around. As I was trekking back to the car I walked past a life guard station silhouetted against the fading sunset, so I hurriedly made a few exposures. With an exposure of around 30 seconds you could still see hints of detail in the tower which I thought gave it a small sense of scale, but I like how its almost completely black.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/catalog/0K6A0789.jpg&quot;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Leo Carillo Beach&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From my first shot to last I was only on the beach for an hour, so you can see how little time I actually had. I could probably spend each night for a week here and just start to get the shots I want - I didn&#39;t even get down to the small cave that was tucked away in the cliffs. On top of that, this is just one of hundreds of beaches surrounding Los Angeles. I&#39;d love to come back out in the future and shoot some more here as well as drive up to Natural Bridges State Park in Santa Cruz. I&#39;m happy I got to come out to California even if just for a brief time and am looking forward to when I can return in the future.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Nov 2015 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
      <link>http://gorilla-studios.com//blog/2015/11/08/leo-carillo.html</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">http://gorilla-studios.com//blog/2015/11/08/leo-carillo.html</guid>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A starry night in DeKalb</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A few months ago I was heading back from downstate IL when my GPS took me a different route than I was used to, and on the way I stumbled across this old weather-stripped barn on one of the backroads in DeKalb, IL. The county is full of them so I am always on the lookout for any that have a lot of character that stood on their own and this one fit the bill nicely. I made a note of it&#39;s location and thought about how I wanted to photograph it at some point. I&#39;ve done quite a few rural photos of barns, especially when I was getting started, however they were all during the day, and due to my inexperience, mostly in the worst light imagineable. I had always wanted to shoot a starscape through the roof of an old barn at another location, but I thought this might be a better opportunity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/posts/google-maps-dekalb.jpg&quot;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Scouting the location beforehand in Google Maps&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Learning from the dissapointment of being in Sedona during a full moon I checked the calendar to see when the next new moon was so it would be as dark as possible, the only variable would be clouds. I checked the weather in the afternoon and everything looked great, so at about 12:30am I packed up my gear and drove out to the farm. As I pulled up I found there was a street light about 20 yards behind the spot I would be shooting from and I realized that this would actually light the barn nicely. I was worried beforehand that it would be a silouhette shot without some kind of fill flash on the barn but after the first exposure I found that it was lit absolutely perfectly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One challenge I always have with landscapes at night is composition - it&#39;s much too dark for a live-preview, and if I wan&#39;t to shoot from close to the ground its really uncomfortable getting down and looking through the viewfinder. Thankfully at 19mm I can just eyeball it and after about 2 or 3 exposures I get locked into the composition I had in mind. I dialed in to a 20 second exposure to ensure the stars didn&#39;t streak but it allows enough time at ISO2000 to get a balanced exposure.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/catalog/0K6A6846.jpg&quot;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;A starry night in DeKalb IL&lt;span&gt;20s, f/6.3, ISO2000&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The light from the street was absolutely perfect, but it did throw off the color temperature a bit which is easy enough to fix in post. The night sky has a very dreamy feeling to it which I love, creating a very meditative photograph. I think I am going to head back in a few weeks during the next new moon to take it to the next level and make my first attempt at star-trails.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Oct 2015 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <link>http://gorilla-studios.com//blog/2015/10/14/starry-night.html</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">http://gorilla-studios.com//blog/2015/10/14/starry-night.html</guid>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The 20 Year Photo</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The first time I picked up an SLR camera was some time in early 1995. To this day I can&#39;t really explain what drew me to photography, but I think it has to do with the intersection between art and technology. I was fascinated at how this bulky metal box stuffed with a mirror, prism, mechanical shutter, and a little strip of 35mm film could produce what I was seeing in National Geographic. During my freshman year in High School I took Intro to Photography which to this day is the extent of my formal education in the field.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I immediately loved it, I was shooting as much as I could while trying not to go broke buying roll after roll of 35mm film. In 1998 my dad purchased a Sony Digital camera that literally used 3.5&quot; floppy discs in the back, which held about 10 photos. Between then and 2003 I used a few different digital cameras but never felt as comfortable as I did with that beat up old Nikon film SLR.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;The path to mastery&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In 2003 I purchased a brand new Canon EOS 10D Digital SLR and I was on top of the world. The problem was that my ambitions were far ahead of my skill level. I was aware of it, but not consciously. I wanted to take amazing photos and be able to share them, and I was getting frustrated at the disconnect between what I had in my head and what was shoing up on the back of the camera. I knew it would take hard work, but I couldn&#39;t grasp how much. At some point I came across this quote by Ira Glass which stopped me in my tracks:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;quote&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;You&#39;ve got to get rid of a lot of crap before you&#39;re going to get anything that&#39;s special.  You don&#39;t want to be making mediocre stuff.  There&#39;s a gap for the first couple years that you&#39;re making stuff. What you&#39;re making isn&#39;t so good. But your taste, the thing that got you into the game, is good enough that you can tell what you&#39;re making is kind of a disappointment to you. A lot of people at that point, they quit. The thing I would say to you with all my heart is that most everybody I know who does interesting, creative work, went through a phase of years where they had really good taste, they could tell what they were making wasn&#39;t as good as they wanted it to be. They knew it fell short. Everybody goes through that. If you&#39;re going through it right now, or if you&#39;re just starting off and you&#39;re entering into that phase, you&#39;ve got to know its totally normal and the most important thing you could do is a lot of work. Do a huge volume of work because it&#39;s only by actually going through a volume of work that you&#39;re actually going to catch up and close that gap.&quot;&lt;br /&gt;
- Ira Glass&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That was exactly where I was. I knew what I wanted to do, I had clear visions in my head of the photos I wanted to take but I wasn&#39;t there yet. I would look at my portfolio and know it was mediocre at best, but that didn&#39;t stop me, I didn&#39;t give up. Being a card-carrying geek I heard that there was going to be a lunar eclipse, so I knew it would be a great opportunity, so I grabbed my tripod &amp;amp; telephoto lens and headed out to see what I could get.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/posts/moon-fail.jpg&quot;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;My first attempt at a lunar eclipse. &lt;span&gt;November 8th, 2003&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was so disappointed with the results I was almost defeated. Everything was blurry, I couldn&#39;t get the exposure balanced correctly, it wasn&#39;t in focus, I had so many problems and why? I just spent a ton of money, this should look like it belongs on the cover of Astronomy Magazine right? I was using the same tools as the pros, but I didn&#39;t know how to get the same results. I was somewhat aware of things I needed to learn, but there was a wealth of information I didn&#39;t know was even out there.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Practice, practice, practice&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I kept pushing myself to try again, learning different techniques, bringing my camera everywhere I went, and challenging myself to get better. Slowly I progressed and over time I started to improve. Sometimes I would take a photograph that would make me stop and say &#39;yes, thats what I envisioned when I pressed the shutter button&#39;. I found the ratio of bad shots to good shots became less and less.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ansel Adams is arguably the greatest landscape photographer of all time, and he said this about his work:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;quote&quot;&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Twelve significant photographs in any one year is a good crop.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I personally feel this is a pretty good target to hit. This may seem like nothing in todays digital age where everyone has an Instagram account with more pictures of their lunch than Adams ever put on film in his lifetime, but I think it holds true when talking about creating art, not just snapping photos.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Reflection&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Periodically I look back to see the progress I have made, I save every shot I take specifically for this reason. I can pull up photos tagged with &#39;moon&#39; and see the quality improving over the years. After a few more attempts, here is a shot of a waxing gibbous moon from 2007.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/posts/moon-intermediate.jpg&quot;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Waxing gibbous moon. &lt;span&gt;March 25th, 2007&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Over the course of four years I had improved remarkably but it was almost impossible to realize in real time. I learned how to focus manually in the dark, how to lock the mirror up to avoid shaking the exposure, how to properly stabilize my tripod, and numerous other techniques that all combined to create a wonderful photograph.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;quote&quot;&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;The master has failed more times than the beginner has even tried. - Stephen McCraine&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the beginning I would probably get 1 good photo from 100 shots. This day I am happy with 1 in 50 to be honest. It&#39;s not just technical mistakes - it can be clipping a subject or bad framing, choosing the wrong viewpoint, shooting at the wrong time of day, or simply missing some detail in the photo. I don&#39;t just take photos, it takes effort to make a photograph.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Although sometimes it takes a bit of luck, and in this case, a &lt;i&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ton&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/i&gt; of it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/portfolio/fly-me-to-the-moon.jpg&quot;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;i&gt;Fly me to the moon&lt;/i&gt;&lt;span&gt;March 18th, 2011&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, most of the time its preparation, knowledge, and execution. When I heard that there would be another lunar eclipse in a week I knew I had an opportunity to take the photo I had wanted to take since I first picked up that old Nikon. I looked back at all my previous astrophotography shots to see what worked so far and what didn&#39;t. I read some materials to refresh myself on the exact techniques, and most importantly I went out the night before to practice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/posts/practice.jpg&quot;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Practice shot, night before the eclipse&lt;span&gt;September 26th, 2015&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not only could I take the photo I wanted to take in 2003, more importantly I could take a stacked progression of the eclipse that wasn&#39;t even a thought back then. This time I was ready. Since I had gone out the night before to practice I had a good starting point, slowly adjusting my exposures over the three hour event. I took my time, I wasn&#39;t rushed or panicked, I was prepared. Here is probably the most difficult shot of the bunch, the eclipse at it&#39;s apex.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/posts/lunar-eclipse-peak.jpg&quot;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Lunar eclipse at its peak. &lt;span&gt;September 27th, 2015&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After selecting a good set of exposures I was able to make a 10 shot progression of (nearly) the entire eclipse. The clouds parted just after I started and rolled in just before it ended, but it was enough of a window to get the majority of it. I sent over the order to the printer last night, so in a few days I should have a few 40&quot; by 10&quot; prints ready to frame, one for myself and a couple to sell. I can&#39;t wait to see them in such a large format.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/posts/lunar-progression-tall.jpg&quot;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;10 shot progression of the lunar eclipse. &lt;span&gt;September 27th, 2015&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;i&gt;&amp;quot;...it took me my entire life.&amp;quot;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;quote&quot;&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Legend has it that Pablo Picasso was sketching in the park when a bold woman approached him.&lt;br /&gt;
  &amp;quot;It’s you — Picasso, the great artist! Oh, you must sketch my portrait! I insist.&amp;quot;&lt;br /&gt;
  So Picasso agreed to sketch her. After studying her for a moment, he used a single pencil stroke to create her portrait. He handed the women his work of art.&lt;br /&gt;
  &amp;quot;It’s perfect!&amp;quot; she gushed. &amp;quot;You managed to capture my essence with one stroke, in one moment. Thank you! How much do I owe you?&amp;quot;&lt;br /&gt;
  &amp;quot;Five thousand dollars,&amp;quot; the artist replied.&lt;br /&gt;
  &amp;quot;But, what?&amp;quot; the woman sputtered. &amp;quot;How could you want so much money for this picture? It only took you a second to draw it!&quot;&lt;br /&gt;
  To which Picasso responded, &amp;quot;Madame, it took me my entire life.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;I don&#39;t feel as I am a master photographer yet, and am in no way comparing myself to Picasso, but I really like that quote. The lunar eclipse progression I took on September 27th 2015 technically only took me fractions of a second for each frame to make, but in reality it took 20 years of hard work, many failures, even more learning, reading, patience, and practice to create.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Oct 2015 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <link>http://gorilla-studios.com//blog/2015/10/01/twenty-years.html</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">http://gorilla-studios.com//blog/2015/10/01/twenty-years.html</guid>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bigfoot Bandcamp</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This weekend I headed down to Cedar Point IL and had a blast photographing the Bigfoot Bandcamp music festival. If you are looking for a truly unique, laid back and intimate atmosphere, this was the place to be. The festival was held in a huge campground with the stage in the center so you could literally hop out of your tent and walk right down to the stage. A huge lineup of unique acts combined with a very laid back environment makes this an event you don&#39;t want to miss. I have it marked on my calendar for next year already. I got down after the show started, but I got to see Jaik Willis, Evacuate The Earth, The Voodoo Fix, The Krank Daddies, and topping the bill was The Reverend Horton Heat. Throw in some fire dancers, hula hoopers, and a burlesque show, its one of the best festivals I have ever been to.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure class=&quot;half-and-half&quot;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/bfbc/0K6A3771.jpg&quot;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/bfbc/0K6A4479.jpg&quot;&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Jaik Willis&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I wasn&#39;t able to get down to the show until early afternoon, but when I arrived Jaik Willis was taking the stage. I was floored when he opened with a solo acoustic cover of Master of Puppets, beatboxing the rhythm section and pushing his acoustic guitar to the edge. An energetic set and a very unique talent, he was a lot of fun to see.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/bfbc/0K6A3814.jpg&quot;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Jaik Willis&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Check out &lt;a href=&quot;/jaik-willis&quot;&gt;all the photos of Jaik here&lt;/a&gt;, and you can find more information about Jaik and where he is going to be on &lt;a href=&quot;http://jaikwillis.com&quot; target=&quot;blank&quot;&gt;his website&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Evacuate The Earth&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Up next was Evacuate The Earth. I love bands that don&#39;t stick to the routine and I knew I was in for something special when I noticed the lead singer with two saxophones, a flute, a bull horn, and her own drum. The bassist had a theremin which needless to say you don&#39;t see very often.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/bfbc/0K6A3878.jpg&quot;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Evacuate The Earth&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can see &lt;a href=&quot;/evacuate-the-earth&quot;&gt;all my photos from their set here&lt;/a&gt; and more information about them on &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.evacuatetheearth.net&quot; target=&quot;blank&quot;&gt;their website&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;The Voodoo Fix&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After a short break The Voodoo Fix stormed onto the stage. They recently moved from LA to Nashville where, from what I saw, they are going to make a huge splash in the local scene and well beyond.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/bfbc/0K6A4252.jpg&quot;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;The Voodoo Fix&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can see &lt;a href=&quot;/the-voodoo-fix&quot;&gt;all my photos from their set here&lt;/a&gt; and more information about them on &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.thevoodoofix.com&quot; target=&quot;blank&quot;&gt;their website&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;The Krank Daddies&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Krank Daddies came on stage and tore it up from the first second of their set. You have to respect any band that roars out a song called &#39;Johnny Cash Kicks Ass&#39;. I had a hard time keeping up with them, but it was a blistering set that left my ears ringing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/bfbc/0K6A4302.jpg&quot;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;The Krank Daddies&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Check out &lt;a href=&quot;/the-krank-daddies&quot;&gt;all my photos from their set here&lt;/a&gt; and more information about them on &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.thekrankdaddies.com&quot; target=&quot;blank&quot;&gt;their website&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Reverend Horton Heat&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What else can anyone say about the Reverend Horton Heat? He&#39;s been rocking since almost before I was born and hasn&#39;t lost a step since. I&#39;ve wanted to see him perform for years which makes it even more special that I got to shoot The Rev, Jimbo, and Paul. A great performance to cap off the night.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/bfbc/0K6A4771.jpg&quot;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Reverend Horton Heat&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;figure class=&quot;half-and-half&quot;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/bfbc/0K6A4711.jpg&quot;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/bfbc/0K6A4923.jpg&quot;&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/bfbc/0K6A4862.jpg&quot;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Reverend Horton Heat&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thanks Rev.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Check out &lt;a href=&quot;/rev-horton-heat&quot;&gt;all the photos from their set here&lt;/a&gt; and find out where they&#39;ll be soon at &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.reverendhortonheat.com&quot; target=&quot;blank&quot;&gt;their website&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Aug 2015 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <link>http://gorilla-studios.com//blog/2015/08/10/bigfoot.html</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">http://gorilla-studios.com//blog/2015/08/10/bigfoot.html</guid>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Morning on the L</title>
      <description>&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/mobile/IMG_2705.jpg&quot;&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This weekend I was in the city and had to take the Orange line of the L down to the South Loop and because I didn&#39;t plan on doing any shooting, my 5D was packed in my camera bag at home. While waiting at the something station in the Loop I noticed the morning light streaming down onto the tracks from between two buildings creating a nice contrast between the shade and sunlight. With a train coming down the tracks at me I got my iPhone 4 out and snapped this photo. Im always nervous shooting with the iPhone because of the shutter lag from when I hit the button but I timed it perfectly so the lead car was in the morning sun. I was frustrated that I didn&#39;t have my DSLR on me but they say the best camera is the one you have with you so I should be happy that at the very least I have a camera in my pocket at all times.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Seeing the result of this shot converted into black &amp;amp; white in Instagram left me pleasantly surprised, I like the level of contrast and sharpness. I still violently disagree with people who claim a smartphone can replace an SLR, but I believe they are good for casual shooting. Since it was about 8am on a Saturday the L was almost empty, so I headed back to the rear car to test out Instagram&#39;s Hyperlapse app. I had tried it once, but it was sitting at my desk or somewhere boring so I wasn&#39;t impressed - I wanted real world results.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Holding the phone steady on the back door of the train I shot a time lapse of the Orange line leaving the Loop heading southbound, letting the camera roll for 2 or 3 minutes. Hyperlapse compresses it down so the final shot was only about 30 seconds at 10x speed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/Qbcdf5676Uk&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was disappointed when I remembered that Instagram limits video to 15 seconds, the entire clip is pretty cool. I&#39;m not sure if the lag in the beginning is due to the limited processing capabilities of the iPhone 4 or something along those lines, I was just irritated it wasn&#39;t as smooth as I had hoped. I was impressed enough to want to take some more time lapses in the future, so we&#39;ll see if its the phone or something I did.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Jun 2015 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <link>http://gorilla-studios.com//photo/2015/06/27/morning-L.html</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">http://gorilla-studios.com//photo/2015/06/27/morning-L.html</guid>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Campton Hills Road</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Over the past few weeks I have been cataloging all my photos on my website in order to dynamically create galleries sorted by category, and in doing so I have dug up quote a few old photographs from my archive. This photo was taken back in 2006 on my trusty old EOS 10D - a 6.1MP DSLR that I bought new in 2003.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Just west of the town I grew up in there was an old knotty tree that just kept catching my attention when I would drive by, so I decided to try to get an interesting photo of it. I made quite a few attempts - some in broad daylight which aren&#39;t anything special, a handful in a snowstorm which I printed out and gave to my parents, and then a number at night including this one.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure class=&quot;vertical&quot;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/catalog/CRW_2285.jpg&quot;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Tree along Campton Hills Road&lt;span&gt;15s, f/4, ISO100&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This was when I was still learning long exposures, and while it&#39;s a good print, I wish I had gotten it during magic hour or closer to sunset. I lost a lot of details in the foreground (including the base of the trunk), and the overall exposure was extremely dark. Lightroom brought it up enough to display online, but at full resolution the sky doesn&#39;t look so good. I love that I got a silhouette of the tree with the leaves blurred by wind, the cars streaking by were completely intentional, but the plane coming into frame from above left was a happy accident.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I had originally edited this as a black and white and let it sit for years, but it never really grabbed me. Looking at it again I realized the color version was much better, the light of the city combined with the very tail end of a warm midwestern sunset create something much more special than a black and white print can do. This is a prime example of why I always keep my original RAW files - there have been quite a few I go back to years later and rescue them from obscurity. Additionally the tree died and was finally cut down sometime around 2012, so I can&#39;t go and re-shoot in this location much to my dismay.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Jun 2015 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <link>http://gorilla-studios.com//photo/2015/06/09/campton-hills.html</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">http://gorilla-studios.com//photo/2015/06/09/campton-hills.html</guid>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>James Thompson Center</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Today on my walk to the train station after work I took a quick detour and randomly stopped into the James Thompson government center on Randolph and Clark in the Loop. It&#39;s the kind of place you could walk by a thousand times and not notice anything about it. I first went in years ago because there is a DMV in the basement, and thats when I realized the interior of the building is this beautiful open space all the way up to the ceiling, a sprawling web of glass and steel. The elevator stacks are exposed in the center, with offices wrapping around in a circle on the outside, and a large hole in the floor looking down to the basement level.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I walked in and poked around a little bit, but there are restricted areas because it is a government building and they can be a bit picky about photographers. I went up to the first floor above the lobby and took some panoramas from floor to ceiling from each side. This is a 5 shot panorama from the left side of the first floor overlooking the lobby and down into the basement.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure class=&quot;vertical&quot;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/chicago/thompson-center.jpg&quot;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;5 shot panorama&lt;span&gt;1/160th, f/8, ISO4000&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I love the blue glass near the entrance, and all the exposed staircases, so many little details that almost get lost in the photo. If you are downtown I recommend you at least stop in and look around for a few minutes.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 May 2015 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <link>http://gorilla-studios.com//photo/2015/05/15/thompson-center.html</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">http://gorilla-studios.com//photo/2015/05/15/thompson-center.html</guid>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
