<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Gorilla-Studios Photography</title>
    <description>Focusing on stunning landscape and high-energy music photography, Gorilla-Studios has been the online home of my portfolio since 2003. I specialize in landscapes, cityscapes and architecture, nature, candid portraiture, headshots, band promos and concert photography.
</description>
    <link>http://gorilla-studios.com/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://gorilla-studios.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Thu, 04 Jan 2018 23:03:59 -0600</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 04 Jan 2018 23:03:59 -0600</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.0.2</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>My top 10 images of 2017</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Another year has come and gone which means again it&#39;s time to look back and choose my best shots from the 2017 calendar year. I&#39;ve done this exercise for the past few years and find it to be a wonderful learning experience as well as extremely rewarding.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To find my best work I have a smart gallery in Lightroom to display any 3 star or higher images taken this calendar year. At the end of the year I start weeding out weaker shots, taking a few passes to get the collection down to the top 15 or so. This year I started with a set of 48 images, which seems about average for me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/posts/2017-finalists.jpg&quot;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Photos in 2016 rated 3+&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As I get closer to the final 10 things start to get tricky. Editing photos, in the context of creating a body of work, not actually adjusting exposure, colors, etc.., means making some hard decisions about what to include and what to leave out. Time usually makes this easier - photos you were in love with right after they were taken don&#39;t seem as exciting, and sometimes others that might not have grabbed your attention stand out now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After much deliberation I finally narrowed it down to my top 10 from the 2017 calendar year. They are presented in chronological order.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My day job is in the Chicago Loop, which gives me some great opportunities to do architecture photography. Whenever I am walking to and from the train station I keep my eyes open, some days taking detours and alternate routes for fun. During one of these walks a building I walk by daily finally caught my eye. At street level it&#39;s just another white office building completely over-shadowed by the Sears Tower across the street. However at the top there is an angled cutaway that allows for some interesting photographs when taken from Adams Street. I took this at 200mm when the sky was flat and slightly overcast. I love this particular perspective, the simplicity of the angles make it look almost like a pyramid, plus the weathering on the corner of the building breaks up the straight lines a bit.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/catalog/0K6A4769.jpg&quot;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;i&gt;200 S. Wacker&lt;/i&gt; - Chicago&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Last year I started creating a series of photographs taken at 16mm straight up of the skyscrapers around the Loop. It is difficult not to have power lines, light poles, or other distractions in frame but the challenge is fun. I had primarily stayed close to Wacker Drive around Monroe but one afternoon I wandered down to Dearborn &amp;amp; Madison where I found a small alley across from the Chase building. Looking up I realized I had stumbled onto something with a lot of potential - another location that you might walk by hundreds of times without noticing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/catalog/0K6A5290.jpg&quot;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;i&gt;Steel Giants IV&lt;/i&gt; - Chicago&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For some reason I find it rather difficult getting these shots, because when I lean back and point the camera straight up I start losing my balance. I have to plant my legs wide open and make sure I&#39;m not too close to traffic, I don&#39;t want to keel over into the street. Despite the difficulties I love the perspective a super-wide angle gets pointing straight up, watching the buildings almost disappear into the sky.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In late July we packed up and we headed out to Connecticut for a much needed break while visiting family. Spending a week in Mystic and the surrounding areas is a great way for me to recharge my batteries and try my hand photographing subjects I simply don&#39;t have the opportunity to capture in Illinois. One of my all time favorite photographers is &lt;a href=&quot;http://vanderwal.com&quot; target=&quot;blank&quot;&gt;Onne Van Der Wal&lt;/a&gt; who has an amazing gallery in Newport Rhode Island, and he shoots boats and other nautical subjects. I always think of him when I&#39;m out on the water with my camera.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first morning there I headed down to Mason&#39;s Island before sunrise only to find everything completely fogged over. Disappointed for about ten seconds, I headed down the dock to see various sail boats just peacefully tied up in the water, almost looking like ghost ships where my disappointment vanished.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/catalog/0K6A7609.jpg&quot;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Foggy morning, Mason&#39;s Island Connecticut&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I sat down and just listened to the fog horns while water lapped at the dock - almost a zen like experience for me. Bouncing between a 50mm prime and the 70-200mm I tried some different perspectives all while making sure I didn&#39;t go off the edge of the dock and in for a drink.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Still wanting a nice colorful sunrise I headed down the next morning when I saw the skies were crystal clear. What a difference 24 hours makes - this next frame is the exact same set of boats from almost the same spot just as the sun was breaking over the trees of Dodge&#39;s Island.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/catalog/0K6A7923.jpg&quot;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Sunrise at Mason&#39;s Island Connecticut&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A small rowboat tied to the dock caught my eye, it&#39;s white paint and lines against the almost black water made for some wonderful contrast, and the wood was the perfect splash of color. I leaned way out over the water and shot this almost straight down, making sure my feet were planted and my camera strap was secure. Even after six months this stands out as one of my all time favorites.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;vertical&quot;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/catalog/0K6A8007.jpg&quot;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;i&gt;Possibility&lt;/i&gt; - Mystic Connecticut&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On my last day I headed down again to see if I could pick up any more shots, and as I walked all the way down the dock I noticed that the horizon was fading perfectly into the sky. If I was more of a sailor I could tell you what kind of boat that is, but it&#39;s been years since I have been out on the water. Regardless I love the simplicity of the near silhouette of the boat, the seagulls flying by, and the cool colors just starting to warm up in the morning sun.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;vertical&quot;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/catalog/0K6A7849.jpg&quot;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Sunrise at Mason&#39;s Island, Connecticut&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In August I headed over to Italian Fest in Lisle to shoot &lt;a href=&quot;http://everettdean.com&quot; target=&quot;blank&quot;&gt;Everett Dean&lt;/a&gt; who always puts on a great show. While I was over on the side stage behind a huge stack of PAs I saw him rear into his Chucky Berry shuffle when I got this shot - really capturing the energy of his performance from a different perspective.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/catalog/0K6A0199.jpg&quot;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Everett Dean&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The September eclipse had been circled on my calendar for a few years, so to say I was excited was a bit of an understatement. I packed all my gear including the tracking mount for my telescope and headed down to Fulton, Missouri which was right on the path of totality. The day was intensely hot and clouds were threatening us all morning but everything stayed clear during the partial phases and most importantly during totality. This shot is a composite of 9 exposures to capture the detail of the corona radiating outwards.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/catalog/0K6A9387.jpg&quot;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Eclipse totality&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It truly was an amazing experience that I still can&#39;t quite describe, but for a full look at the rest of the day, you can read &lt;a href=&quot;/post/2017/08/12/solar-eclipse.html&quot; target=&quot;blanK&quot;&gt;my post about the Eclipse here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;November had me flying out to Los Angeles for the third year in a row, so I decided to take a break and head over to Venice Beach and watch the sunset over the pier. This was another situation that I was able to use &lt;a href=&quot;http://photoephemeris.com&quot; target=&quot;blank&quot;&gt;The Photographer&#39;s Ephemeris&lt;/a&gt; to plot out exactly where I needed to be and when to catch the sun directly behind the pier. I recommend keeping those eclipse glasses handy because it makes shooting directly at the sun much more comfortable lining up the shot if you have to make small adjustments. Looking directly at the sun at anytime can damage your eyes, not just during the  eclipse.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Running up and down the beach a bit trying different angles I took this shot as I was knee deep in the surf dodging waves again. Knowing I only had about twenty minutes of sun I went from 16mm wide open all the way through to 200mm covering a lot of perspectives, but I think this frame at 35mm was my favorite. I like the waves crashing in as the sun started peeking out from below the pier deck.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/catalog/0K6A2849.jpg&quot;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Venice Beach Pier sunset&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My final shot was taken towards the end of September when I woke up extra early to take the train into the city, catching the sun as it rose behind Cloud Gate in Millennium Park. All the other photographers there that early were shooting form the other side to catch the warm sun on the buildings, but I knew I had a good chance of a sunburst coming from underneath the sculpture on this side. I was flat on my stomach shooting inches off the ground at 16mm wide open to capture this frame. Hoping to get some motion in the clouds I had stopped down to f/16 and opened the shutter for a second or two, and while I didn&#39;t get the clouds moving, a runner stopped to stretch and look around a bit, adding a nice sense of scale.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/catalog/0K6A1996.jpg&quot;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Cloud Gate at sunrise&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It wasn&#39;t as active a year as I had hoped but I still got some exciting work done. Im looking forward to the new year and all the opportunities to come in the next 12 months. A new large format printer is on the way right now and I have my first exhibition coming up in March, so it&#39;s going to be a busy start to 2018. Happy New Year everyone!&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 31 Dec 2017 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://gorilla-studios.com/post/2017/12/31/best-of-2017.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://gorilla-studios.com/post/2017/12/31/best-of-2017.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>post</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Venice Beach Pier</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Once a year I head out to Los Angeles for work, and if possible I take an evening to take the camera out somewhere new. In 2015 I drove up to &lt;a href=&quot;/blog/2015/11/08/leo-carillo.html&quot; target=&quot;blank&quot;&gt;Leo Carillo Beach&lt;/a&gt;, last year I went for a photo walk around downtown, and this year I planned on heading down to Venice Beach to watch the sunset at the pier.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On my flight in I woke up just as we were coming over the mountains surrounding Los Angeles, and was able to snap this quick shot from my iPhone. I love the layers of mountains and cool colors. I wanted to get a shot like this when I was in Oregon but never had the chance to hike up Saddle Mountain while I was there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/posts/IMG_6512.jpg&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As always I was on a tight schedule, so I arrived about a half hour before sunset. Walking down the beach I watched the surfers, swimmers, and people playing in the water, all while getting my feet wet. Most people were wrapping up for the day and I took this photo of a surfer coming out of the water while trying to find angles to shoot from.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/catalog/0K6A2736.jpg&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks to &lt;a href=&quot;http://photoephemeris.com/&quot; target=&quot;blank&quot;&gt;The Photographer&#39;s Ephemeris&lt;/a&gt; I knew exactly where and when the sun would be setting, and without fail I had the spot I wanted to shoot from picked out before I even stepped foot in California. It worked perfectly, and I was lined up and ready to go with plenty of time. I wanted to get the pier in silhouette with the waves crashing up the beach as the sun set directly behind it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/catalog/0K6A2888.jpg&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Combined with the difficulty of shooting straight into the sun behind the pier, I also was calf deep in the waves, having to jump up a few times to avoid getting completely soaked. It was worth the effort as you can see in the next shot, with the waves flooding in just inches below the lens.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/catalog/0K6A2849.jpg&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While jumping in and out of the water I was running all over the beach to get as many angles as I could. As the sun was at the horizon line I swapped over to my 70-200 2.8 to get some close ups of it dissappearing with the people on top of the pier running and fishing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/catalog/0K6A2978.jpg&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I kept the 70-200 2.8 on at 70mm until the sun completely disappeared behind the horizon.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/catalog/0K6A3017.jpg&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Just a sliver left...&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One thing people don&#39;t realize about sunsets is that it&#39;s not over when the sun completely sets. About ten minutes afterwards you get some truly amazing colors painting the sky. I had switched back to my 16-35mm and attached it to my tripod. Knowing that the surf pulls sand from underneath the feet I firmly pushed the tripod down an inch or two and waited for a few waves to break before shooting some long exposures. At f/16 I was exposing for 10 seconds each which was tricky with the water, but watching the ebb and flow of the waves I captured this without any shaking.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/catalog/0K6A3181.jpg&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After packing up my gear I took a long walk up the beach back to Santa Monica and headed back to the hotel. Sure, I was only out for about an hour overall, but it was worth the trek down to the coast. On my flight back to Chicago I glanced out the window to see another sunset, but this time over Iowa. I snapped a few photos and then called it a trip. Till next time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/posts/0K6A3200.jpg&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Iowa at dusk&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 28 Oct 2017 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://gorilla-studios.com/post/2017/10/28/los-angeles.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://gorilla-studios.com/post/2017/10/28/los-angeles.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>post</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The Solar Eclipse</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;The North American Solar Eclipse has been on my calendar for about two years, so now that it&#39;s past I am incredibly relieved everything went smoothly. The long build up allowed me to be as ready as I could be, however nothing could have prepared me for actually &lt;i&gt;experiencing&lt;/i&gt; it first hand. I had mapped out where we were going to be, even made my own &lt;a href=&quot;/post/2017/01/08/preparation.html&quot;&gt;solar filter&lt;/a&gt; months ago, I was ready.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I planned to have my 5DMkIII setup with a 600-1000mm lens on my Celestron CGEM mount. At 1000mm the sun almost fills the frame so I would back it down to 600mm giving me room to capture the flares, which if that was all that I got, I would call a success.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A secondary 6D would sit on a standard tripod with my 16-35mm wide open. I realized about a month out that the path of the eclipse wasn&#39;t so much of an arc, but more of a gentle horizontal curve. With the sun at 60&amp;deg; up it was going to be very hard to get both the horizon and eclipse path in frame without doing some sort of composite shot. That was going to be a tough one to crack.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;The Problem&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The one thing I couldn&#39;t control was of course the weather. Things were looking good about 5 days out, but Saturday afternoon all of that changed. Multiple sites were reporting thunderstorms and clouds on Monday afternoon. A lot of people in my astronomy club threw in the towel and said they would stay home, but a few others were still committed. I was on the fence so I spent  most of Sunday afternoon checking forecasts and planning alternate spots for my best chance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I decided to head down to Fulton, Missouri as planned to meet up with everyone since the next eclipse won&#39;t be happening until 2024 I figured why waste the opportunity. To avoid any traffic I left late Sunday night, camping overnight a few miles away, arriving early Monday morning. At first light things were looking pretty good with minimal cloud coverage at 7am, and those were clearing out pretty fast.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/posts/morning-eclipse.jpg&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Monday morning&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We specifically chose Fulton since it was relatively small compared to Columbia to the West and St. Louis to the East - we wanted to be off the beaten path. I was the first to arrive at Little Dixie Conservation Area and was the only observer there for a while. Once people started coming in after 8:30 or so we started getting our gear setup.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/posts/IMG_5752.jpg&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Setting up our gear&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/posts/eclipse-setup.jpg&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;5D MkIII with the 600-1000mm on a Celestron CGEM mount&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/posts/eclipse-wide.jpg&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;6D with a 16-35mm wide open&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My main concern was getting a good sharp focus on the sun since the 600-1000mm lens was 100% manual. Pointing at something that bright makes it very uncomfortable looking through the eyepiece so I took some test shots to get everything set long before the partial phases started. On my first test shot I realized that I could see a small number of sun spots on the surface so I was in focus and ready to go. I taped down the focus ring to avoid bumping it out of place when removing the filter for totality.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/posts/0K6A9083.jpg&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Focus test - note the three sunspots&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After getting both cameras set I went to get my CGEM mount tracking the sun so I wouldn&#39;t have to mess with it during the eclipse, only to run into problems getting it tracking properly. I ran through the motions a number of times but just couldn&#39;t get it going, Since it was so hot and I was frustrated I scrapped that idea and would just manually guide the camera through the eclipse.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once everything was setup and ready we walked around a bit to meet and chat with everyone who came down to view the eclipse, letting some curious people look through our scopes, and just generally soaking in the experience. We talked to a couple of young PHD students from MIT and UW Madison who were studying particle physics, one gentleman came all the way down from Ontario, another group was from Aurora and worked with my old boss oddly enough, and there were a large number of people from all over the country.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/posts/mark.jpg&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Mark sharing his wisdom&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/posts/IMG_5754.jpg&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;A few people were really excited to be there&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The partial phase started at about 11:36am but totality wasn&#39;t until 1:15, so we were in for a long morning of observation. The later it got more and more clouds rolled in, but thankfully we were getting windows of clear sky to shoot through.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/posts/0K6A9126.jpg&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;The partial phase begins&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As the eclipse progressed it didn&#39;t get noticeably darker, however the temperatures went from almost unbearably hot to comfortable in the hour leading up to totality. More and more cars were coming in but it was never anywhere near busy. Everyone was getting very excited. Our group was probably the most experienced so we were shouting out the countdown as it happened to let everyone know, as well as answering all kinds of questions from the curious people walking around.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/posts/midway.jpg&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Midway through&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/posts/0K6A9212.jpg&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Nearing totality&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Just before totality I ran over to the 6D and switched it from one minute intervals to shoot every 10 seconds instead. What I didn&#39;t notice is that one of the kids running around must have kicked or accidentally  moved the tripod so it skewed the camera, throwing off my planned final wide shot. It wasn&#39;t a huge deal as the camera had a hard time adjusting the exposure settings in Aperture Priority mode. At the very least it did get a few frames during totality of us looking up during the moment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;vertical&quot;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/posts/IMG_9695.jpg&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Totality - you can see me in the lower right of the frame just watching for a minute&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Totality was an amazing experience, and I can&#39;t properly articulate it at this point. It got extremely dark and the birds stopped chirping, everyone started cheering and clapping, and fireworks were going off in the distance. I had to stop taking photos to just stand up and take in the eclipse with my own eyes - what an amazing sight. Of course with a two minute window I didn&#39;t have a ton of time. I was bracketing my exposures a full stop on either side to capture as much as I could.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/catalog/totality.jpg&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Nine shot stack of Totality&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The cheering continued until totality had commenced when we shouted &quot;GLASSES BACK ON!&quot; as we didn&#39;t want anyone burning their eyes out. There was another round of cheers and excitement due to it being the first eclipse for a lot of people there. I was surprised that afterwards a lot of people piled into their cars and left. I continued to shoot the second partial phase between the clouds, and breathed a big sigh of relief knowing that at the very least I got the shot I wanted.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/catalog/solar-eclipse-progression.jpg&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Progression&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once everything was said and done we packed up and headed out, thankfully avoiding the massive traffic delays that everyone was afraid of. I am glad I got to travel down and shoot the eclipse in its entirety and am already planning a large family trip out east for the 2024 eclipse. I hope everyone had a safe and enjoyable eclipse, save those glasses!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 12 Aug 2017 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://gorilla-studios.com/post/2017/08/12/solar-eclipse.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://gorilla-studios.com/post/2017/08/12/solar-eclipse.html</guid>
        
        <category>astrophotography</category>
        
        
        <category>post</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>New Telescope Mount</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;My Celestron Ultima 11&quot; Schmidt Cassegrain telescope was originally built in 1995, and while the optical tube was in great shape, the original fork mount was getting pretty out-dated. It was difficult to assemble and almost unmanageable by one person alone. On top of that, it only had a simple clock drive for star tracking. While thats fine for basic viewing, its woefully inadequate for astrophotography. It was definitely time for an upgrade.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I chose to get a new Celestron CGEM computerized german equatorial mount. This would replace the old and heavy bolted on forks for a lightweight dovetail bar that simply clamped into the mount. I triple checked that I would be able to switch from the fork to a dovetail, made a list of everything I would need, and placed my order. Adorama shipped the order surprisingly quickly and before long I had a huge pile of boxes in my living room.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/posts/the-pile.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;The UPS man came&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;CGEM Mount, Tripod, Dovetail, and a PowerTank&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The boxes look pretty bad but that was exaggerated by the sleet coming down while going from the the truck into the house. Thankfully it all was packed extremely well and made the trip without any damage.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I opened up the CGEM box first, and my immediate impression was that it&#39;s extremely substantial and well built. Pictures don&#39;t do this thing justice - I firmly believe that if left outside during a nuclear attack it would remain intact. Considering it needs to hold the OTA plus camera gear and any accessories it is a &lt;i&gt;crucial&lt;/i&gt; part of any astrophotography setup.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/posts/unboxing.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Celestron CGEM Computerized Mount&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Unboxing the CGEM&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After getting the tripod and mount together I unpacked the new dovetail bar and got down to removing the optical tube from the original fork mount it was on. This was surprisingly easy as it is simply attached with four bolts at the base of the tube. I had to be very careful removing the original mount without scratching the coating on the optical tube - luckily it came out with only a few nicks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now that the tube was off the original mount I also removed the accessory bar and finder scope so I could give everything a good cleaning before assembly. Attaching the new dovetail bar provided me with the only &#39;gotcha&#39; moment of the entire process. It seems new Celestron OTAs use different thread sizes for the forward and aft mounting bolts, so two of the four supplied bolts wouldn&#39;t fit. A quick trip to the hardware store and I was back in business.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/posts/dovetail.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;CGEM Dovetail Bar&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;The dovetail bar that bolts to the OTA&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The original mounting bolts were long enough that without the mount they would screw down far enough to make contact with the mirror itself. Not good, so I&#39;ll need another trip to the hardware store for some shorter ones. You can see bolts sticking out of the back of the tube in the photo below.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure class=&quot;vertical&quot;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/posts/entire-mount.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Celestron CGEM Computerized Mount&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;The CGEM Computerized Mount&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Standing at 6&#39;6&quot; tall I am very pleased with the eyepiece height when the tripod is fully extended. While I don&#39;t plan on doing much viewing myself it is nice to have things up at my height.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I re-mounted the finder scope and balanced the entire assembly using the 17lb and 11lb counter-weights. With everything setup the new equatorial mount is smooth as silk, I am thoroughly impressed. Unlocking the clutches I could move the telescope around with one finger and no slack in any direction.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/posts/cgem.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Celestron CGEM Computerized Mount&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;The CGEM Computerized Mount&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Next I have to get the telescope out in the field on a clear night for a good practice session. I have to dial in the polar alignment which will be easier than before but still essential, as well as explore using the hand controller and Go To features. I&#39;m very excited and checking the weather daily, but it being March will have to be patient.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I plan on sharing my journey as I learn more about astrophotography, so I will be posting more frequently as it warms up - stay tuned.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 11 Mar 2017 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://gorilla-studios.com/post/2017/03/11/celestron-cgem.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://gorilla-studios.com/post/2017/03/11/celestron-cgem.html</guid>
        
        <category>astrophotography</category>
        
        
        <category>post</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Schmidt Cassegrain Maintenance</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;After impatiently waiting a month for clear skies I finally got my &#39;new&#39; Celestron Ultima 11&quot; Schmidt Cassegrain out for a test run. I couldn&#39;t get tack sharp focus so I knew a collimation was in order and looking closely at the corrector plate I found some mold or mildew had built up on the inside of the glass. This was going to be a challenge but if I wanted amazing photos out of it I had to get it cleaned and properly aligned.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/posts/test-run.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Early morning test run&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Early morning test run&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Watching a few videos online and reading quite a few forum threads, I decided to use a mixture of 60% Isopropyl Alcohol and 40% distilled water, with sterile cotton to dampen, clean, and dry the plate. I gathered my supplies, thoroughly cleaned my workspace, and got down to business.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/posts/supplies.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Supplies for cleaning the telescope&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Gathering my supplies&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I needed to mark the position of both the retaining ring and the plate itself to ensure when reassembling everything went back to exactly where it was before. The easiest way to do this was to place two pieces of tape and mark them, slice them evenly during disassembly, then line them back up when putting the plate and ring back in. This was much more important for the corrector since it could go in at any angle, at least the ring was limited to it&#39;s screw holes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/posts/mark-it.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Marking the position of the retaining ring and corrector plate&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Marking the position of the retaining ring and corrector plate&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I removed the retaining ring and marked the plate the same way, with one additional mark on the glass incase the tape came off. Once it was out I took a close look at the primary mirror and found it to be in great shape - I didn&#39;t want to have to touch that, so I gave it a few puffs of compressed air and then sealed the tube while I went to work cleaning the corrector.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The secondary mirror also looked perfect, so I started gently dabbing the corrector with distilled water and cotton swabs. Once it was thoroughly soaked I started dabbing with the cleaning solution, slowly spinning it as I worked my way around a few times, swapping out the cotton every so often (they are cheap, use a lot of them to avoid moving dirt around). Another round of dabbing with distilled water and I finally started dragging the swabs outward towards the edge, putting no pressure on them other than the weight of the swab itself, still slowly spinning after each swipe.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/posts/dabbing.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Cleaning the corrector plate&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Cleaning the corrector plate&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I would pick up the assembly and closely inspect it every so often to ensure things were going smoothly. It looked a hundred times better after one pass on each side, but I did another full water/solution/water cycle on both sides of the glass again. Once that was completed it was looking amazing. A few puffs of compressed air removed any cotton debris, a quick round with the camel hair brush, and it looked perfect.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/posts/plate-cleaning.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Cleaning the corrector plate&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Cleaning the corrector plate&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since I had the scope open and didn&#39;t want to have to do this again any time soon I took another look up close under the lights to make sure I got everything off. It still looked great, so I began reassembly. I gently slipped the plate back into the tube and lined it up with the tape marks, then tilted the scope upwards a little bit removing the chance of it falling out before I got the ring in. I removed the tape pieces and quickly did a mini cleaning where they were, even though it would be completely covered by the ring, I wanted everything as clean as it could be. Then I remounted the retainer ring and screwed it back in place, slowly working opposite screws until everything was back in place.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/posts/before-after.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Corrector plate, before and after&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;The corrector plate before and after.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Honestly I was very nervous about the whole process, but being prepared with all the supplies needed, a good clean workspace with great lighting, and a written down and rehearsed plan made things go extremely well. Once everything was back in I tried to replicate the &#39;before&#39; photo but the glass was so clean my iPhone couldn&#39;t focus on it. I&#39;d say that was a job well done.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Next up is a new Celestron CGEM computerized mount to replace the simple clock driven fork mount, another good collimation, and I should be in really great shape.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 24 Feb 2017 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://gorilla-studios.com/post/2017/02/24/celestron-maintenance.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://gorilla-studios.com/post/2017/02/24/celestron-maintenance.html</guid>
        
        <category>astrophotography</category>
        
        
        <category>post</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Preparing for the Solar Eclipse</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;On August 21st of this year there will be a full solar eclipse passing over the central United States, with the center linel cutting through southern Illinois. Since this will only be a few hours south of me, I will be driving down and photographing the event. The last one I can recall was in the early 90&#39;s and I was in middle school, so I am quite looking forward to seeing this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/posts/eclipse-path.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;The path of the solar eclipse&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can&#39;t shoot the sun without heavy filters on your camera so I ordered a black polymer filter sheet from &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.thousandoaksoptical.com/solar.html&quot; target=&quot;blank&quot; alt=&quot;Thousand Oaks Optical solar filters and accessories&quot;&gt;Thousand Oaks Optical&lt;/a&gt; to use with my 600-1000mm lens. A lot of sites recommend you just rubber band the sheet over the end of the lens but I wanted a nicer (and re-useable) solution than that. I have a 100mm square filter holder for my regular ND filters, so I decided to put together some kind of insert for the sheet to slip inside my holder.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My ND filters are 100mm squares and only 1 or 2mm thick, so the challenge is to make something rigid enough to &#39;frame&#39; the solar filter yet thin enough to slip into the holder. I poked around with a few different kinds of cardboard but everything was too thick or too flimsy until while getting breakfast the other day I grabbed a box of Cheerios and realized the cardboard was absolutely perfect. Rigid and thin, I could cut two pieces out and using an exacto knife cut a window for the filter.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/posts/IMG_3656.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Roughing out the filter holder&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The edges didn&#39;t have to be perfect since they were outside the field of view plus this will probably be proof of concept until I can find a better material. I cut down the solar filter sheet and taped it into the frame, then taped the two frames together.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/posts/IMG_3657.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Filter sheet inside the frame&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The sheet is delicate and even though I was careful I somehow scratched the front of it. Not a big deal, the sheet itself was only a few bucks. I put everything together and mounted it in the filter holder attached to my lens making sure the silver side is facing the sun.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/posts/IMG_3667.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Mounted on the lens&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The solar filter is so dark that the sun is the &lt;i&gt;only&lt;/i&gt; thing you can see when its mounted so getting the camera aligned with the sun and focused is a bit of a trick without burning out my left eye. I found that when I squint while shooting with my right eye behind the camera my left eye is still kind of open, enough to where if I am pointing at the sun its very uncomfortable. I slid my hat down over my left eye and kept the right behind the camera so I was safe. Focusing was tricky, but I got dialed in and started making exposures. To my surprise I had to bump my ISO to 800 while shooting 1/250th of a second but I figure I can probably drop my shutter speed a bit when it&#39;s on the tripod. I will probably grab a blanket or some kind of hood on my next test run so I can use live view to get even sharper focus.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/posts/0K6A2771.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;First test of the solar filter&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Next up is to search for a better material to use as a filter frame, however if I don&#39;t find anything I know that using this simple method works just fine. I&#39;d also like to try using a hood over the tripod so I can focus better without getting blinded in the process. Remember you have to be very careful while viewing or photographing the sun, as even a second or so of direct contact can damage your eyes or equipment. I&#39;ll post some more updates as I make progress.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 08 Jan 2017 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://gorilla-studios.com/post/2017/01/08/preparation.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://gorilla-studios.com/post/2017/01/08/preparation.html</guid>
        
        <category>astrophotography</category>
        
        
        <category>post</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>My top 10 images of 2016</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I am continuing my tradition of taking the end of the year to review my photographs over the last 365 days and create a selection of 10 images that represent my best work over that time period. This year was mostly focused on family and work so I didn&#39;t get the chance to shoot as much as possible, but I was able to get some time in Chicago, Portland, and London which I am very grateful for.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To find my best work I have a smart gallery in Lightroom set to this calendar year + anything thats rated 3 stars or above. At the end of the year I start weeding out weaker shots, taking a few passes to get the collection down to the top 15 or so. This year I started with a set of 56 images, which seems about average for me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/posts/2016-finalists.jpg&quot;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Photos in 2016 rated 3+&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After a few passes I narrowed it down to my 10 strongest. Lets take a look at what I chose, presented chronologically.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since I work about two blocks from the Sears Tower and its between my office and the train station, I find myself constantly snapping photos and getting different looks at the building. In March when it started warming up a bit I wanted to see what kind of details I could get in the glass bottom viewing platforms using my 70-200 f/2.8. You can&#39;t get directly underneath and shoot upwards since there is a large atrium on the west side of the building, so I tried an angle I hadn&#39;t seen before. I walked over to the corner of Adams &amp;amp; Wacker Drive, almost completely around the to the side of the building, where I could barely see the west face of the building. From that angle the boxes were very pronounced outwards, combined with the &#39;shoulders&#39; of the building making some interesting lines. A deep blue cloudless sky turned into a wonderful dark spotlight when converted to black and white.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/catalog/0K6A0939.jpg&quot;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the end of March I found myself out in London on business, and while I didn&#39;t have much time I was able to sneak out for a late night shoot along the Thames where I took this photo of Millennium Bridge and St. Paul&#39;s cathedral. I love the mixture of colors reflecting in the river in contrast to the almost purple night sky.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/catalog/0K6A1416.jpg&quot;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In May I headed out west to Portland Oregon, and while I was there I ventured out to Cannon Beach. An iconic beach instantly recognizable to anyone who has seen &lt;i&gt;The Goonies&lt;/i&gt;, Haystack Rock is a beautiful rock formation over 200 feet tall jutting out of the Pacific coast. I spent two nights shooting sunsets from various spots around the beach, both in and out of the water. My favorite shot was taken at sunset as the tide was creeping in and I could barely feel my toes. The waves breaking over the large rock in the center of the frame combined with how the rip tide washed out the foreground make this one of the best landscapes I have taken in some time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/catalog/0K6A3261.jpg&quot;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another location in Portland I visited was Multnomah Falls just outside Portland. After a serious rain shower cleaned out the tourists I had a few minutes before it filled back up again. Making sure I had my rain gear covering my camera, I got my 16-35 f/4 setup on the tripod and started exposing frames around 1 to 2 seconds, trying to smooth the rushing water as much as possible without over-exposing the highlights. The dull gray sky wasn&#39;t adding anything so I cropped in-camera to just below the horizon above, and just below the base of the falls. This was the first time shooting at 16mm that I wish I had a bit more range on the low end, as I couldn&#39;t get as much of the lake below as I would like.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure class=&quot;vertical&quot;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/catalog/0K6A3635.jpg&quot;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Back in Chicago, again shooting the Sears Tower, this time it was more of a learning exercise. I picked up some stackable ND filters so I wanted some practice making exposures with an ND16 (or more) sitting in front of the lens. I was able to open the shutter for 30 seconds at f/16, which on a windy day created the wonderful cloud movement that I was hoping for. After importing these into Lightroom I sat on them for a few months not paying them another thought. It wasn&#39;t until I started diving deeper into Lightroom&#39;s black and white conversion tools that I went back and took a closer look, which I am very glad I did.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure class=&quot;vertical&quot;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/catalog/0K6A8841.jpg&quot;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Combining my ND filters with a straight up composition I used for some commission work earlier in the year I took some more black and white photos of various skyscrapers in the Loop. This next frame was taken on Wacker Drive and Monroe of the Deloitte building, a newer building in the skyline. Some minor sharpening with a little burning of some shadows, but otherwise this was almost straight out of the camera. I was surprised how much contrast I had gotten from the pylon at the bottom of the frame with the ceiling of the ground floor. Another piece for my architectural portfolio.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/catalog/0K6A8852.jpg&quot;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During a brief trip to Los Angeles I was able to get out for one evening and was extremely lucky to make this photograph. I had digitally scouted quite a few areas around the city having only been there once before, finally deciding to shoot the Walt Disney Concert Hall after shooting the sunset from another location. I walked around a bit finally deciding to shoot from this angle. I fired off a test exposure, and made a few adjustments. In the middle of this exposure a police officer rode up telling me that there were no tripods allowed and I had to either shoot handheld or leave the premises. I heard the shutter click while I was talking to him so I quietly hit the remote one last time before he rode off, but I had to pack up my gear and leave which I was rather cross about. I could (well should have) taken some exposures from across the street but I was tired and hungry so I packed it in and headed back to the hotel. Looking back at the three shots I got I was delighted that the older couple taking a cell phone shot of the building stayed still for just the right amount of time. You can tell that they are all dressed up, the gentleman was wearing a very nice hat and suit, the woman in a wonderful dress. Contrasted against the angular and sharp building it made for a very nice overall composition. I am irritated that I couldn&#39;t spend more time on the property, but I do like what I was able to get.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/catalog/0K6A9996.jpg&quot;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My final three exposures were all taken in one day, almost on a whim. It had been a few years since I have shot in blizzard conditions and it&#39;s not something I particularly enjoy, but I can&#39;t argue with the results as some of my favorite landscapes are in the snow. Chicago was forecasted to get about a foot of snow over two days, so I thought I might be able to get something, but didn&#39;t have anything particular in mind. My wife sent me out to run some errands right as the storm hit which as it turns out was perfect. I grabbed my camera bag &lt;i&gt;just in case&lt;/i&gt;, but as I got about 2 blocks from home I realized that conditions were absolutely magical for some landscape work. Knowing I didn&#39;t have much time I headed over to Leroy Oakes Forest Preserve which is only a few minutes from my house. Typically it is over-run with portrait photographers doing family shoots, but when the weather gets foul they all disappear. Pulling in my first thought was to shoot a scene I had taken back in 2013, a row of trees leading off into the distance. It wasn&#39;t snowing as heavily back then so I was hoping for something softer and more washed out, which is exactly what I got. Struggling to keep the rain cover on while still accessing the camera I reviewed my first few shots - I knew I was on to something. A slight color temperature adjustment and some sharpening was all that was needed. The rest was mother nature.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/catalog/0K6A1968.jpg&quot;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Turning around and trudging through calf deep snow drifts I looked up to see what, in the summertime is a rather ugly clump of trees, but was now turned into a magnificent scene just fading off into the snowstorm. Every distraction was already taken out of the frame by the blanket of snow on the ground and even more coming down.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/catalog/0K6A1975.jpg&quot;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I kept trying different angles as I made my way closer and closer to the &#39;front&#39; of the outcropping, finally getting what has to be one of my all time favorite shots. The snow was coming down so heavy that everything beyond about 20 or 30 feet was completely washed out. Grabbing a few more frames I headed back to the car, resolving to come back the next time we got socked with snow, which of course we haven&#39;t had a single flurry since.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/catalog/0K6A1986.jpg&quot;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Looking at the timestamps from my last shoot I spent exactly 13 minutes from first frame to last. It was unexpected, rushed, improvised, and wonderfully magical. It was a great way to re-energize me heading into the new year. For most of my landscape work I like to sit on it for a week or so, then if it still catches my eye I make the best frame my desktop to see how it holds up after repeated viewings. If it can survive that I know I am on to something, and the last two shots I keep flip flopping on which I like more. They are holding up a month later, and I think are really going to stand out as some of my best work. Not bad for 13 minutes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Ready for 2017&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I like doing this exercise to keep me excited and get me going more during the colder months. I definitely don&#39;t get out as much when it&#39;s cold and miserable outside, but a little end of the year retrospective always helps the winter blues. Here&#39;s to 2017!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 31 Dec 2016 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://gorilla-studios.com/post/2016/12/31/best-of-2016.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://gorilla-studios.com/post/2016/12/31/best-of-2016.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>post</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>My Lightroom workflow</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I finally made the jump this fall and switched my photography workflow to Lightroom 5 full-time. Since at least 2003 I was using Bridge + Photoshop which I knew was not the most efficient way to do it, but it was comfortable and I was fast with it. When I first checked out Lightroom a few years ago I couldn&#39;t quite figure out the way to edit my most recent photos on the go while keeping the bulk of my library at home on my archive drives. After some more thinking, and some inspiration from Martin Bailey, I resolved all my issues and took the plunge.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/posts/lightroom-flow.jpg&quot;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Adobe Lightroom 5&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My photo catalog is quickly racing towards 2TB and while it&#39;s certainly not as large as some professionals, it&#39;s still big enough to cause headaches. I can&#39;t fit my catalog on my laptop, and smart previews just weren&#39;t going to cut it. After a little reading and testing I setup a workflow where I could have my cake and eat it too. There is a folder on my laptop called &#39;To Vault&#39; (The Vault is the name of my archive drive). I import all new photos into that folder, using a simple &lt;code&gt;YYYY-MM-DD - Subject&lt;/code&gt; folder structure, then open Lightroom and synchronize the folder which imports them into the catalog. Once I am finished editing the photos locally, I then use the Lightroom interface to physically move the source files to The Vault, which is duplicated to another off-site hard drive monthly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I decided to use Lightroom because I was sick of dealing with maintaining both the source catalog alongside a &#39;final edits&#39; collection which took up even more space. Lightroom is non-destructive meaning it saves all your &#39;edits&#39; in simple xml data files which it then applies to the RAW files when you open them in develop mode, that way the source RAW file isn&#39;t touched and the edits are only a few kb of data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Organization&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My rating system, while completely arbitrary, has served me well. Three stars is my baseline for anything that has the potential to be added to my portfolio, four stars for gallery images, and five stars are for my master portfolio - a set of 18-20 photos that showcase my best work. One and two stars are for family photos and client shoots which stay private excepting for their respective subjects. Using this structure allows me to setup smart galleries where I can quickly find my best work from a given time frame, or other constraint.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have a number of smart collections to keep things organized. A catch folder of anything rated higher than 1 in the last 30 days lets me review and edit my &#39;approved&#39; shots over the last month, meaning my last few photo shoots. I also have smart collections for anything rated 3+ for each calendar year which allows me to review and curate a set of best photos from each year. Additionally I like to go back and see if I missed anything, so I use a &#39;Review&#39; collection - setting it as the target collection I can go back and look over photos, tapping &#39;B&#39; to add them quickly so I can take a closer look later.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/posts/2016-finalists.jpg&quot;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;All photos from 2016 rated 3+&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Editing&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Editing photos is much faster than using Photoshop. All the adjustments needed are right at your fingertips and are  specifically designed for photo editing. For most photos all I usually do is set a lens correction, and make some minor tweaks such as exposure adjustments or spot removal. If I have to do any deep cloning or healing I will sometimes export to Photoshop, but that is only because I am still learning how cloning and healing work in Lightroom. A wonderful feature that I use every time is Before &amp;amp; After review pane. You can view both the original and edited views a few different ways to see how much you have changed - definitely not possible in Photoshop.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/posts/lightroom-comparison.jpg&quot;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Developing and comparing to the original&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once I am done editing a photo I can simply go back to grid view. I don&#39;t worry about exporting or saving an edited version unless I need to post on social media or deliver to a client. This keeps me from filling up drive after drive with the original RAW files AND edited versions of each. On export I can embed copyright information and watermarks, as well as constrain the image size by the long edge (very handy).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Overall impressions&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am sincerely impressed with Lightroom and wish I had made the jump sooner. I know I could upgrade to Creative Cloud for a monthly fee, but I don&#39;t like the idea of not being able to use it once I stop paying. Lightroom 5 has all the features I need for my workflow, and while there are a few neat tools in Creative Cloud, there is nothing that makes me want to upgrade any time soon. If you have any questions about how I import, organize, edit, or export my work feel free to &lt;a href=&quot;/about&quot;&gt;contact me&lt;/a&gt;, I&#39;d love to chat.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 10 Dec 2016 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://gorilla-studios.com/post/2016/12/10/lightroom.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://gorilla-studios.com/post/2016/12/10/lightroom.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>post</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Leroy Oakes Forest Preserve</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Northern Illinois got it&#39;s first snow of the season when a few inches came down just before lunch yesterday. I hadn&#39;t taken the camera out for a while so I decided to head over to Leroy Oakes Forest Preserve here in St. Charles to see if I could capture some of the magic. It&#39;s a wonderful park just west of the city and while it&#39;s a hot spot for portrait photographers, I discovered years ago that when it&#39;s blanketed in snow there are some perfect spots for minimalist landscapes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I pulled in and sure enough there were a few families brave enough to be doing portrait sessions in the blustery snow. Just past the two barns where most of the portraits are taken is a small one room schoolhouse, Sholes School. Local grade-schoolers get to spend the day there in period costume learning about what it was like living here in Illinois back in the 1800&#39;s - which I myself was lucky enough to do back in second grade.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Paired with my 16-35mm f/4, I stuffed my camera into a rain cover and jumped out of the car to see what I could get as the snow started coming down even harder. No one else was brave enough to face the deepening snow here, so the immediate area was untouched. I captured this frame from underneath a large tree on the walkway leading up to the school building itself.&lt;p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/posts/0K6A1952.jpg&quot;&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is a white fence around the schoolhouse could use some repairs, but I think it adds to the overall charm of the property. In the next shot I was at 16mm so I stood only a few inches from the post in the foreground, the lens distortion made for an interesting composition. I had tried this exact shot years ago at 19mm and just wasn&#39;t happy, but this time around I am really pleased with the results that the extra 3mm gives me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/posts/0K6A1960.jpg&quot;&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another shot I had taken years ago that I was hoping to re-visit was one of a row of trees near the entrance of the park. An access road since removed caused this set of trees to line up straight as an arrow, disappearing into the snowy horizon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/posts/0K6A1968.jpg&quot;&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Just on the other side of the main road stand another two trees leaning towards each other almost as if they are about to hug. I made this photo as the snow continued to pick up its pace, making it very difficult to see what I was doing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/posts/0K6A2009.jpg&quot;&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Visibility was dropping so I decided to turn around and trudge back to the car to see what I had gotten. Fortunately as I turned I realized that the very large bank of trees that normally I would completely ignore were naturally just fading away into the horizon, disappearing into the swirling snow. Captured almost entirely in camera this next photo was only sharpened a touch, thats all. I love how everything just fades out of frame without any after effects.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/catalog/0K6A1995.jpg&quot;&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I kept getting even closer as I tried a few different perspectives, finally taking what is my favorite shot from the day. This was from the very end of the row, while making sure the surrounding trees still faded into the snow.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/catalog/0K6A1986.jpg&quot;&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I love taking minimalist landscapes and while snowstorms are difficult to shoot in, they create some wonderful results. Normally I don&#39;t wish for a lot of snow during the winter, but after yesterday&#39;s outing I am going to be keeping my eye on the weather reports hoping for some big storms.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 05 Dec 2016 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://gorilla-studios.com/post/2016/12/05/leroy-oakes.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://gorilla-studios.com/post/2016/12/05/leroy-oakes.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>post</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Star Trails - A Success</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Last month I went out and performed a test run for shooting star trails. It was a wonderful learning experience and despite the full moon along with the clouds rolling in halfway through I felt the end result was a great start.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/posts/star-trails-1.jpg&quot;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Star trails test run&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Taking a few reminder notes I checked the calendar for the next new moon and then kept a close eye on the weather report. When it finally cleared up I grabbed my gear and headed out to a small spot near Kaneville, IL where it looked to be fairly dark with minimal light pollution. Again I knew I wanted Polaris to be close to center of the frame so the stars would spiral around it. It&#39;s been a while since I&#39;ve spotted constellations manually so I decided to use &lt;a href=&quot;https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/skyview-free-explore-universe/id413936865?mt=8&quot; target=&quot;blank&quot;&gt;Skyview Free&lt;/a&gt; to verify I was on target. I decided to try a vertical shot this time, looking over a small lake in the foreground with a tree breaking up the horizon to add some interest. I set my intervalometer for continuous 30 second exposures, grabbed my chair and settled in for an hour and a half of waiting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure class=&quot;vertical&quot;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/catalog/star-trails-2s.jpg&quot;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Star trails second run&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I loved how the sky turned out, Polaris was exactly where I wanted, but I wasn&#39;t in love with the composition. I didn&#39;t get enough reflection in the water as I wanted, and the horizon line was just too cluttered with the tree not standing out how I had imagined it. I chalked it up to another learning experience and started looking at the weather report again.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A week later things were looking good. I had again scoured Google Maps looking for remote locations in the area with a large tree next to a field I could face north while shooting. I had found what looked to be exactly what I wanted out near Maple Park, IL.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/posts/star-trails-location.jpg&quot;&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The next clear night I drove out to my spot and instantly knew I was going to get something special. I couldn&#39;t seem to get a good focus dialed in so I wound up backing my car up and turning on the headlights while pointing at the tree which did the trick. After verifying everything was set I sat down for another hour and a half session, shooting 120 frames for the final stack.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/posts/lightroom-trails.jpg&quot;&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Using Lightroom I adjusted my exposure settings and applied them to all 120 frames and exported them to JPGs. The next step was to remove all the planes streaking by since I didn&#39;t want them in the final print. Thankfully being pretty far out in the suburbs there wasn&#39;t too many frames I had to fix. I had to stack them a few times to catch all the planes, but when I was finished I was extremely pleased I went through the trouble.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/catalog/star-trails-3.jpg&quot;&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The final result was almost exactly what I had in my mind before I even made my first exposure, which is always extremely satisfying as a photographer. An hour and a half made some nice long trails farther outside Polaris, but next time I think I would like to try two or three hours to see how far I can push it. I am definitely in love with this type of astrophotography, and am looking for more opportunities to shoot star trails in different locations as well as during some upcoming meteor showers.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 23 Sep 2016 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://gorilla-studios.com/post/2016/09/23/star-trails-2.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://gorilla-studios.com/post/2016/09/23/star-trails-2.html</guid>
        
        <category>astrophotography</category>
        
        
        <category>post</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
