<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Gorilla-Studios Photography</title>
    <description>Write an awesome description for your new site here. You can edit this line in _config.yml. It will appear in your document head meta (for Google search results) and in your feed.xml site description.
</description>
    <link>http://gorilla-studios.com/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://gorilla-studios.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
      <item>
        <title>Bigfoot Bandcamp</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;This weekend I headed down to Cedar Point IL and had a blast photographing the Bigfoot Bandcamp music festival. If you are looking for a truly unique, laid back and intimate atmosphere, this was the place to be. The festival was held in a huge campground with the stage in the center so you could literally hop out of your tent and walk right down to the stage. A huge lineup of unique acts combined with a very laid back environment makes this an event you don&#39;t want to miss. I have it marked on my calendar for next year already. I got down after the show started, but I got to see Jaik Willis, Evacuate The Earth, The Voodoo Fix, The Krank Daddies, and topping the bill was The Reverend Horton Heat. Throw in some fire dancers, hula hoopers, and a burlesque show, its one of the best festivals I have ever been to.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure class=&quot;half-and-half&quot;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/bfbc/0K6A3771.jpg&quot;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/bfbc/0K6A4479.jpg&quot;&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Jaik Willis&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I wasn&#39;t able to get down to the show until early afternoon, but when I arrived Jaik Willis was taking the stage. I was floored when he opened with a solo acoustic cover of Master of Puppets, beatboxing the rhythm section and pushing his acoustic guitar to the edge. An energetic set and a very unique talent, he was a lot of fun to see.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/bfbc/0K6A3814.jpg&quot;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Jaik Willis&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Check out &lt;a href=&quot;/jaik-willis&quot;&gt;all the photos of Jaik here&lt;/a&gt;, and you can find more information about Jaik and where he is going to be on &lt;a href=&quot;http://jaikwillis.com&quot; target=&quot;blank&quot;&gt;his website&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Evacuate The Earth&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Up next was Evacuate The Earth. I love bands that don&#39;t stick to the routine and I knew I was in for something special when I noticed the lead singer with two saxophones, a flute, a bull horn, and her own drum. The bassist had a theremin which needless to say you don&#39;t see very often.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/bfbc/0K6A3878.jpg&quot;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Evacuate The Earth&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can see &lt;a href=&quot;/evacuate-the-earth&quot;&gt;all my photos from their set here&lt;/a&gt; and more information about them on &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.evacuatetheearth.net&quot; target=&quot;blank&quot;&gt;their website&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;The Voodoo Fix&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After a short break The Voodoo Fix stormed onto the stage. They recently moved from LA to Nashville where, from what I saw, they are going to make a huge splash in the local scene and well beyond.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/bfbc/0K6A4252.jpg&quot;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;The Voodoo Fix&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can see &lt;a href=&quot;/the-voodoo-fix&quot;&gt;all my photos from their set here&lt;/a&gt; and more information about them on &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.thevoodoofix.com&quot; target=&quot;blank&quot;&gt;their website&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;The Krank Daddies&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Krank Daddies came on stage and tore it up from the first second of their set. You have to respect any band that roars out a song called &#39;Johnny Cash Kicks Ass&#39;. I had a hard time keeping up with them, but it was a blistering set that left my ears ringing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/bfbc/0K6A4302.jpg&quot;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;The Krank Daddies&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Check out &lt;a href=&quot;/the-krank-daddies&quot;&gt;all my photos from their set here&lt;/a&gt; and more information about them on &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.thekrankdaddies.com&quot; target=&quot;blank&quot;&gt;their website&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Reverend Horton Heat&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What else can anyone say about the Reverend Horton Heat? He&#39;s been rocking since almost before I was born and hasn&#39;t lost a step since. I&#39;ve wanted to see him perform for years which makes it even more special that I got to shoot The Rev, Jimbo, and Paul. A great performance to cap off the night.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/bfbc/0K6A4771.jpg&quot;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Reverend Horton Heat&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;figure class=&quot;half-and-half&quot;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/bfbc/0K6A4711.jpg&quot;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/bfbc/0K6A4923.jpg&quot;&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/bfbc/0K6A4862.jpg&quot;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Reverend Horton Heat&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thanks Rev.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Check out &lt;a href=&quot;/rev-horton-heat&quot;&gt;all the photos from their set here&lt;/a&gt; and find out where they&#39;ll be soon at &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.reverendhortonheat.com&quot; target=&quot;blank&quot;&gt;their website&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 10 Aug 2015 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://gorilla-studios.com/blog/2015/08/10/bigfoot.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://gorilla-studios.com/blog/2015/08/10/bigfoot.html</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Morning on the L</title>
        <description>&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/mobile/IMG_2705.jpg&quot;&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This weekend I was in the city and had to take the Orange line of the L down to the South Loop and because I didn&#39;t plan on doing any shooting, my 5D was packed in my camera bag at home. While waiting at the something station in the Loop I noticed the morning light streaming down onto the tracks from between two buildings creating a nice contrast between the shade and sunlight. With a train coming down the tracks at me I got my iPhone 4 out and snapped this photo. Im always nervous shooting with the iPhone because of the shutter lag from when I hit the button but I timed it perfectly so the lead car was in the morning sun. I was frustrated that I didn&#39;t have my DSLR on me but they say the best camera is the one you have with you so I should be happy that at the very least I have a camera in my pocket at all times.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Seeing the result of this shot converted into black &amp;amp; white in Instagram left me pleasantly surprised, I like the level of contrast and sharpness. I still violently disagree with people who claim a smartphone can replace an SLR, but I believe they are good for casual shooting. Since it was about 8am on a Saturday the L was almost empty, so I headed back to the rear car to test out Instagram&#39;s Hyperlapse app. I had tried it once, but it was sitting at my desk or somewhere boring so I wasn&#39;t impressed - I wanted real world results.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Holding the phone steady on the back door of the train I shot a time lapse of the Orange line leaving the Loop heading southbound, letting the camera roll for 2 or 3 minutes. Hyperlapse compresses it down so the final shot was only about 30 seconds at 10x speed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/Qbcdf5676Uk&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was disappointed when I remembered that Instagram limits video to 15 seconds, the entire clip is pretty cool. I&#39;m not sure if the lag in the beginning is due to the limited processing capabilities of the iPhone 4 or something along those lines, I was just irritated it wasn&#39;t as smooth as I had hoped. I was impressed enough to want to take some more time lapses in the future, so we&#39;ll see if its the phone or something I did.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 27 Jun 2015 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://gorilla-studios.com/photo/2015/06/27/morning-L.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://gorilla-studios.com/photo/2015/06/27/morning-L.html</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Campton Hills Road</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Over the past few weeks I have been cataloging all my photos on my website in order to dynamically create galleries sorted by category, and in doing so I have dug up quote a few old photographs from my archive. This photo was taken back in 2006 on my trusty old EOS 10D - a 6.1MP DSLR that I bought new in 2003.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Just west of the town I grew up in there was an old knotty tree that just kept catching my attention when I would drive by, so I decided to try to get an interesting photo of it. I made quite a few attempts - some in broad daylight which aren&#39;t anything special, a handful in a snowstorm which I printed out and gave to my parents, and then a number at night including this one.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure class=&quot;vertical&quot;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/catalog/CRW_2285.jpg&quot;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Tree along Campton Hills Road&lt;span&gt;15s, f/4, ISO100&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This was when I was still learning long exposures, and while it&#39;s a good print, I wish I had gotten it during magic hour or closer to sunset. I lost a lot of details in the foreground (including the base of the trunk), and the overall exposure was extremely dark. Lightroom brought it up enough to display online, but at full resolution the sky doesn&#39;t look so good. I love that I got a silhouette of the tree with the leaves blurred by wind, the cars streaking by were completely intentional, but the plane coming into frame from above left was a happy accident.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I had originally edited this as a black and white and let it sit for years, but it never really grabbed me. Looking at it again I realized the color version was much better, the light of the city combined with the very tail end of a warm midwestern sunset create something much more special than a black and white print can do. This is a prime example of why I always keep my original RAW files - there have been quite a few I go back to years later and rescue them from obscurity. Additionally the tree died and was finally cut down sometime around 2012, so I can&#39;t go and re-shoot in this location much to my dismay.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 09 Jun 2015 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://gorilla-studios.com/photo/2015/06/09/campton-hills.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://gorilla-studios.com/photo/2015/06/09/campton-hills.html</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>James Thompson Center</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Today on my walk to the train station after work I took a quick detour and randomly stopped into the James Thompson government center on Randolph and Clark in the Loop. It&#39;s the kind of place you could walk by a thousand times and not notice anything about it. I first went in years ago because there is a DMV in the basement, and thats when I realized the interior of the building is this beautiful open space all the way up to the ceiling, a sprawling web of glass and steel. The elevator stacks are exposed in the center, with offices wrapping around in a circle on the outside, and a large hole in the floor looking down to the basement level.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I walked in and poked around a little bit, but there are restricted areas because it is a government building and they can be a bit picky about photographers. I went up to the first floor above the lobby and took some panoramas from floor to ceiling from each side. This is a 5 shot panorama from the left side of the first floor overlooking the lobby and down into the basement.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure class=&quot;vertical&quot;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/chicago/thompson-center.jpg&quot;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;5 shot panorama&lt;span&gt;1/160th, f/8, ISO4000&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I love the blue glass near the entrance, and all the exposed staircases, so many little details that almost get lost in the photo. If you are downtown I recommend you at least stop in and look around for a few minutes.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 15 May 2015 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://gorilla-studios.com/photo/2015/05/15/thompson-center.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://gorilla-studios.com/photo/2015/05/15/thompson-center.html</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Natural Light Portrait</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;In most situations nothing beats natural light. This morning I was playing with my daughter in front of our large picture window when I noticed the light fall-off on the side of her face as she gazed outside. I knew just looking at her if I used a high shutter speed I could drop the background to a solid black even though the room was fully lit. It&#39;s actually a gloomy day outside which is perfect - clouds create the perfect diffuser, softening the light and removing all the harsh shadows that are present on a sunny day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/portraits/alison-seven-months.jpg&quot;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Natural portrait&lt;span&gt;1/250th, f/4, ISO8000&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I propped her up between my knees as she braced herself on the back of the couch. Leaning back I snapped a few photos, as she looked around. Composition was a little difficult because just to the left of the frame are the white window blinds which completely throws off the image. I cropped them out in camera, while keeping her to the right side. After a few test shots I landed on 1/250th of a second which was enough to drop the background completely black. I bumped the shadows just a touch to make it a bit more dramatic, adjusted the color temperature, sharpened up her eye and that was it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For adult portraits and other situations I do like using off-camera flash, but for simple, up close headshots and portraits, I still absolutely love natural light. During the summer I try to shoot during the early morning and evening to avoid harsh light, however when its cloudy thats the perfect time to shoot all day long. So don&#39;t be dissapointed on gloomy days, grab your camera and make something special.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 22 Apr 2015 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://gorilla-studios.com/photo/2015/04/22/natural-light.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://gorilla-studios.com/photo/2015/04/22/natural-light.html</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Wabash Ave</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;While downtown I don&#39;t typically ride the L, and when I do it&#39;s usually work related so I am heading to client offices. Late last year I happened to get off of the brown line at Wabash &amp;amp; Adams where there is an overpass looking straight up Wabash with a clear view of Trump Tower. At the time I didn&#39;t have my camera on me, but I made a mental note to head back at some point with my gear to see what I could get.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&#39;s the beginning of March and the Chicago weather is still very poor so I decided to only take a few quick shots to see what I could get when the weather gets nicer. I quickly setup my tripod at the center of the overpass between platforms, looking north up Wabash. As the trains rumbled by the overpass would shake quite a bit, but I was surprised to find it didn&#39;t affect any shots. This exposure was taken for 15 seconds, f/8 at ISO100.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/chicago/over-the-l.jpg&quot;&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Timing the shots was particularly tricky - I wanted to get trains going in both directions, but being pressed for time I didn&#39;t have any luck in the 15 minutes I was there. Overall I like the shot with the one train streaking into the station, but I want to go back in the spring or summer when there isn&#39;t snow on the platform roofs and the sky isn&#39;t so overcast and dull.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 04 Mar 2015 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://gorilla-studios.com/photo/2015/03/04/over-the-l.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://gorilla-studios.com/photo/2015/03/04/over-the-l.html</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Selective Sharpening</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;This month has been exclusively shooting portraits of my daughter as we play in the morning, so my portrait editing skills have been getting better and better lately. Here is a sharpening technique that I have been working on recently. For most of my landscape work I just do a simple Unsharp Mask applied to the entire frame which isn&#39;t the best technique since it isn&#39;t that flexible..&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In our example here we have a portait of Alison, zoomed in half way to get a good feel for whats happening. First I duplicate the background layer, then go to Filter &amp;gt; Other &amp;gt; High Pass.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/sharp/step1.jpg&quot;&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The layer will turn a dark grey with the edges of your subject are visible. I adjust the slider until the eyes are reaslly standing out a bit, but not too much. If you do go too high you can always adjust later, thats the great thing about this technique is its non-destructive and easily adjustable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/sharp/high-pass.jpg&quot;&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Change the layer from Normal to Overlay. While holding Option click create layer mask. By holding Option it will fill the layer mask with black. On a layer mask black is transparent, showing the layer below, while white makes it opaque, showing the layer sharpened with our High Pass filter.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/sharp/overlay.jpg&quot;&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With the sharpened layer transparent, we can use our paint brush to selectively sharpen only what we want. Make sure you have the black layer mask selected:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/sharp/select-mask.jpg&quot;&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Select a soft paint brush and make sure its white. Paint over the eyes and you can see the sharp layer coming through. You can see here I painted over her left eye - you can see how sharp it is compared to her right.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/sharp/mask.jpg&quot;&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I use this to paint over the eyes, nose, and lips, sometimes the ears and chin as well depending on the photo. Once you have painted over the areas you want sharp, then you can adjust the opacity of the layer to make sure its not too much.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By doing it this way we only sharpen what we want, and the rest of the photo is smooth - this is even better with photos taken at really wide apertures.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/sharp/final.jpg&quot;&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you&#39;d like to see this technique in action here&#39;s a quick screencast:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/SndYnCRfWpE&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 07 Feb 2015 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://gorilla-studios.com/tutorial/2015/02/07/selective-sharpening.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://gorilla-studios.com/tutorial/2015/02/07/selective-sharpening.html</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Sedona</title>
        <description>&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/sedona/1.jpg&quot;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;span&gt;1/500th, f/8, ISO100&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In early December we flew out to visit family down in Sedona, Arizona, where I have never actually been before. I have heard lots of great things about the landscape out there, especially the rock formations and valleys surrounding Sedona proper. We would only be there for a few days, but I wanted to try to get out at least a few times to shoot, not knowing when I would be back. I rented a brand new Canon 16-35 2.8 MkII specifically to capture some landscapes and hopefully starscapes. The first shot was taken on our way down to Phoenix, somewhere out over southern Colorado I believe. Being from Illinois it was amazing seeing such beautiful mountain ranges.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We landed in Phoenix and hopped a quick flight up to Flagstaff, then driving down to Sedona. The first day the weather was not cooperating at all, it was very overcast, chilly, and a little drizzly here and there. Our first stop was Midglee Bridge Park, just north of Sedona on the &#39;Y&#39;. Its a beautiful park with tons of footpaths and a very large steel bridge over the canyon supporting the road above. Even though it was so cloudy I knew I could probably get some nice black and whites, so I took quite a few photos as I tried to soak in the amazing scenery.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/sedona/3.jpg&quot;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;span&gt;1/320th, f/5.6, ISO100&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All the rock formations and ranges have names from what I gather, I&#39;ll have to do some research to find them all. The paths around the park went from flat and even to downright dangerous, even I had a tricky time navigating some. After about ten minutes there I felt a longing to just quit my job and come out to shoot landscapes for the next year or two. Thankfully my wife was there to snap me back to reality.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/sedona/4.jpg&quot;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;span&gt;1/500th, f/5.6, ISO100&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We found a large number of aloe plans scattered throughout the park and I was surprised at how large they were, probably a good two feet in diameter with these razor sharp leaves fanned out in all directions. I had never seen anything like it before.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/sedona/2.jpg&quot;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Aloe Plant&lt;span&gt;1/160th, f/3.5, ISO100&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Passing down below Midglee Bridge to the south side of the park there is a ledge looking out over Oak Creek and Wilson Canyon. There is a small path that heads back off to the east with a wonderful view of Steamboat Rock. Thankfully about 15 minutes into my hike the clouds started to part a bit, allowing the sun to shine down on Steamboat enough to get a few shots in.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/sedona/6.jpg&quot;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Midglee Bridge&lt;span&gt;1/250th, f/8, ISO100&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/sedona/5.jpg&quot;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;span&gt;1/640th, f/5.6, ISO100&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/sedona/7.jpg&quot;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Midglee Bridge Park&lt;span&gt;1/50th, f/9, ISO100&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Just up the road from Midglee Bridge Park is another one you can very easily miss, Grasshopper Point. It&#39;s almost a hidden turn off, and you wind your way down to the bottom of the canyon. We went down during the day to explore, but it was misty and very overcast. We met a family who were hiking down to the Oak Creek to go fishing. After exploring a while we headed back to the hotel for dinner and family time. The number one shot on my wishlist was a starscape with the rock formations in the foreground, so when it cleared up that night I headed back to Grasshopper Point, but to my dismay it was a full moon - the absolute worst time to shoot stars. Since there is very little light pollution the moon lit everything up to where an exposure over 15 seconds looked almost like daytime. I took a few shots while I was down there, but was heartbroken that I didn&#39;t get many more stars than I usually get in the Chicago suburbs. On the upside I guess its a great excuse to book a trip back when its a new moon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/sedona/11.jpg&quot;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Grasshopper Park&lt;span&gt;15s, f/8, ISO2500&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The next morning I got up early to go catch the sunrise from Amitabha Stupa and Peace Park, a small park at the base of Chimney Rock. I got up to the park and hiked around for a while before the sun started cresting over the surrounding rock formations, finding some great locations to shoot from. The weather was a complete 180&amp;deg; from the day before - it was a crystal clear blue sky and a very comfortable temperature hovering in the mid-50&#39;s. I have never shot mountainscapes before so I really had to remember pouring over Ansel Adams books when I was younger, and try to capture a tiny sliver of the magic he was able to. I found an interesting patch of cactus to put in the foreground of some early shots as the sun painted the rock face with very warm light.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/sedona/8.jpg&quot;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;span&gt;1/100th, f/8, ISO100&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The park is located at the base of Chimney Rock to the west, panning around to Coffeepot Rock on the east edge of the formation. The morning was almost a scramble to get as many shots as I could as the lighting was perfect, and I had so much area to cover. Here is Chimney Rock right at sunrise, I love how the warm morning light really brings out how red it really is, contrasted against the deep blue sky.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/sedona/9.jpg&quot;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Chimney Rock&lt;span&gt;1/125th, f/8, ISO100&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Even at 16mm there was no way to get everything in one frame, or even two. Thankfully I have been practicing shooting panoramas the month before, so took a few minutes to visualize a few large panoramas. This next shot was a four frame panorama panning from west to east.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/sedona/10.jpg&quot;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;span&gt;4 shot panorama&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On some of the conversions Photoshop got rather confused by the deep blue skys and attempted to merge them together with interesting results - the sky would skew up another 3000 pixels in the center of the stitching. I got a few other panoramas, but none better than the &lt;a href=&quot;/photo52/2014/12/09/photo52-week49.html&quot;&gt;nine shot panorama of the entire formation that morning&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I genuinely wish I had a few weeks to just camp out and shoot landscapes, but alas I only had a few hours to spend in and around Sedona. It is one of the most beautiful locaitions I have ever seen and really hope to get back some day.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 19 Dec 2014 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://gorilla-studios.com/travelogue/2014/12/19/sedona-traveloge.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://gorilla-studios.com/travelogue/2014/12/19/sedona-traveloge.html</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Week 49 - Sedona Panorama</title>
        <description>&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/p52/49.jpg&quot;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Sedona Arizona panorama&lt;span&gt;9 shot panorama&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This past weekend was spent down in Sedona Arizona, just a quick trip down to see family and get some quick photos. I had never been down before so I wasn&#39;t sure exactly what to expect, but I was almost overwhelmed with the beauty and sheer size of some of the rock formations around town. The weather was pretty poor on day one, so it was spent mostly scouting for spots to shoot at when it did clear up. Day two was forecasted to me much nicer and clear all day so I packed up my gear and headed out to The Amitabha Stupa and Peace Park before the sun came up. Its nestled at the base of a few large rock formations, and out of the way enough where I was the only one there all morning.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Even at 16mm I didn&#39;t have enough range to get everything I wanted, so I decided to shoot some panoramas, this time taking at least 6-10 shots for each final shot. I hiked up into the park a bit and found myself at a wonderful location just as the sun started creeping down the rockface. From what I understand Chimney Rock is off to the left, while Coffeepot Rock is on the right side. This particular photo is a composite of nine photos at about 20mm each, taken at sunrise. The final resolution is 23,132 x 7,193, which works out to a whopping 166MP, clocking in around 1GB.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I had to adjust each photo before compositing because the exposure level was thrown off during panning due to the sun being very close to the right-most frame. Once they were all correctly exposed and color-balanced I ran them through Photoshop&#39;s Photomerge feature to combine them into one gargantuan file. From there I edited out a spot that was on the lens which showed up nine times, as well as a high-pass layer mask sharpening to make sure the sky stayed smooth while the rocks were as sharp as they could be.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Getting nine exposures down into one large panorama is pretty tricky but I am getting much better. I hope to take what I have learned and use it for a 15-20 exposure panorama of the city skyline, but I have never stacked them both horizontally and vertically. We&#39;ll see how that goes.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 09 Dec 2014 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://gorilla-studios.com/photo52/2014/12/09/photo52-week49.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://gorilla-studios.com/photo52/2014/12/09/photo52-week49.html</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Week 48 - Family Portrait Shoot</title>
        <description>&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/p52/48.jpg&quot;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Candid portrait&lt;span&gt;1/125th, f/5, ISO100&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For our last week on the east coast my wife wanted to do a quick family portrait session for our Christmas cards, needless to say I couldn&#39;t say no. We headed down to Mason&#39;s Island where I captured &lt;a href=&quot;/photo52/2014/11/16/photo52-week46.html&quot;&gt;the sunset for Week 46&lt;/a&gt;. Shooting a family portrait is always a challenge, but adding the fact I had to be in the photo was a real pain.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We did a few poses on the steps of the clubhouse, and got some really good shots, but it was overcast and starting to drizzle so we went under the porch to pack up my gear and get ready to go. Right before I put the camera away I noticed the soft light coming from camera left lighting up our little one&#39;s face, and the fact she was all smiles made me take a few candid photos as my wife was playing with her. I have found recently that anything below 1/125th or 1/150th is too slow for infant photography. I wrongly assumed they didn&#39;t move that much, and they don&#39;t, but when they move their heads the whip them around causing quite a few shots to be motion blurred. This one however was absolutely great as she smiled looking out over the ocean.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have been putting a lot of effort back into the editing process lately, and I tried a few things I don&#39;t usually do here. I tried a different selective sharpening technique using a high-pass filter and opacity mask, combined with a gradient map for the black and white conversion. Adding a touch of vingetting and this is one of my favorite photos of my wife and baby. I absolutely love shooting candid portraits, they are almost always leaps and bounds better than posed photos.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 02 Dec 2014 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://gorilla-studios.com/photo52/2014/12/02/photo52-week48.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://gorilla-studios.com/photo52/2014/12/02/photo52-week48.html</guid>
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
