<?xml version="1.0"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Gorilla-Studios</title>
    <link>http://gorilla-studios.com</link>
    <atom:link href="http://www.gorilla-studios.com/rss.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Gorilla-Studios Photography &amp; Design</description>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <pubDate>Fri, 16 May 2014 10:36:52 -0500</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 16 May 2014 10:36:52 -0500</lastBuildDate>

    
    <item>
      <title>Canon 70-300mm IS L</title>
      <link>http://www.gorilla-studios.com/2014/04/24/canon-70-300-L</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Apr 2014 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <author>chris@gorilla-studios.com (Chris Peak)</author>
      <guid>http://www.gorilla-studios.com/2014/04/24/canon-70-300-L</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I was lucky enough to get my hands on a Canon 70-300mm IS L lens to play around with, and I had to share my initial impressions. I took a quick trip down to Navy Pier to play around with it and see how it handles in the field. The lens is all metal, so it is incredibly sturdy weighing in above 2 pounds. On a Black Rapid strap I didn&#39;t feel much fatigue letting it hang at my side, but shooting with it certainly gave my arms a good workout. While I wasn&#39;t blown over by the AF performance I was taken aback at how sharp the images came right out of the camera. I wanted to share two specific photos.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/seagull.jpg&quot;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Cawing Seagull&lt;span&gt;1/160, f/8.0, ISO125&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This noisy guy was hovering around the few tourists, trying to get scraps of food from wherever he could find it. I snapped this photo at 300mm (this is a 100% crop). I couldn&#39;t believe the detail on the birds beak, incredibly sharp.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/seagull-2.jpg&quot;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Seagull Portrait&lt;span&gt;1/160, f/6.3, ISO100&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here was another portrait shot of a seagull that was perched on a railing, again shot at 300mm. The texture around the eye was what makes this photo pop. Incredible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have the lens for another few days so I want to run it through its paces some more, and when I do I&#39;ll share some more photos.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Spring on Lake Michigan</title>
      <link>http://www.gorilla-studios.com/2014/04/23/spring-on-lake-michigan</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Apr 2014 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <author>chris@gorilla-studios.com (Chris Peak)</author>
      <guid>http://www.gorilla-studios.com/2014/04/23/spring-on-lake-michigan</guid>
      <description>&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/lighthouse-spring.jpg&quot;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Chicago Harbor Light&lt;span&gt;1/250, f/5.0, ISO100&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Exposure Triangle</title>
      <link>http://www.gorilla-studios.com/2014/03/06/photo101-getting-out-of-auto</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Mar 2014 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
      <author>chris@gorilla-studios.com (Chris Peak)</author>
      <guid>http://www.gorilla-studios.com/2014/03/06/photo101-getting-out-of-auto</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This past Friday I gave a 5 minute lightning talk at my work about the basics of photography and how you can get out of Auto mode. Instead of sharing the slides I want to expand on the talk I gave and write something more substantial. With entry level DSLRs becoming very affordable these days lots of amateur photographers are entering the market having never touched a film SLR, and generally have a very rough understanding of camera fundamentals.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are three basic settings on the camera that are crucial to every photograph - photographers commonly refer to this as the Exposure Triangle. Every photograph is a balance of three settings - &lt;strong&gt;ISO, Aperture, &amp;amp; Shutter Speed&lt;/strong&gt; - and I want to talk about each one and how they affect each other.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;ISO&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Simply put, ISO is how sensitive the camera&#39;s sensor is to light. If you&#39;re old enough to remember buying film you might recall that it had an ISO rating between 50 to about 1600 give or take. With modern DSLRs it can range from 50 to 100,000+. Having the camera on a low ISO setting, say 100, will produce crisp noise-free images, but it will not be very sensitive to light. Setting the camera to a high ISO, say 25,600, will make it much more sensitive to light allowing faster shutter speeds, the images will have noticeable noise.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/iso-example.jpg&quot;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;(left)ISO 50 - (right)ISO 25,600&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here are two examples from real world shooting. On the left is a photo I took of a Great Blue Heron grooming itself one morning. I was shooting directly into the sun (not recommended at all) so I needed to drop my ISO down to 50 and raise my shutter speed to 1/4000th so I wouldn&#39;t blow out the image. The example is cropped but the original is sharp and almost completely noise free. On the right is a photo I took while shooting the Everly Hillbillies in concert. It was very dark and the drummer was poorly lit so I needed to raise my ISO to 25,600 to get enough light while opening the shutter for 1/200th of a second and you&#39;ll notice the image is extremely noisy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Aperture&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Think of Aperture like the iris of your eye - it is simply the adjustable size of the lens opening. This controls how much light comes through the lens to the sensor, as well as affecting depth of field. One thing students get caught up on is the terminology of how aperture is measured, in f stops. High apertures are when the lens allows the most light through, and conversely low apertures let the least light through. The confusing part is that high apertures are smaller numbers, and low apertures are high numbers. Lets take a look at two examples.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/aperture-example.jpg&quot;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;(left)High Aperture f/2.8 - (right)Low Aperture f/16&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the left is a Macro image taken at a very high aperture - f/2.8. For this shot the lens opening was as wide as it could go, allowing as much light as possible into the camera. This also created an extremely shallow depth of field (extremely exaggerated since it is a macro shot). The right image was taken at a very low aperture, f/16, letting very little light into the camera but getting almost everything in focus, from a few feet in front of the camera all the way to the horizon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Shutter Speed&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is probably the easiest to understand and causes so many headaches for inexperienced photographers. Shutter speed is simply how long the cameras sensor is exposed to the light coming in through the lens. When you press the shutter button the mirror allowing you to see through the lens from the eyepiece springs upward and the shutter curtain snaps open and then closed almost instantly. Shutter speed is measured in fractions of a second, usually between 1/4000th of a second, down to multiple second (or minute) exposures.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/shutter-example.jpg&quot;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;(left)Slow shutter 1/4th - (right)High shutter 1/2000th&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Slow shutter speeds usually cause blurry and shaky images if not done properly. However if you use a tripod (or an very steady hand) you can create some interesting effects when slowing the shutter speed down. On the left is a shot of a London double decker bus passing in front of Elizabeth Tower. Using a monopod I slowed my shutter down to a quarter of a second to make sure the bus was blurred out, yet it was fast enough to hold steady so the tower itself was still sharp. In order to freeze motion you need a higher shutter speed. On the right is a shot of birds flying into my parents bird bath. They were flitting about extremely quickly so I had to set the camera to 1/2000th of a second in order to even come close to freezing the motion. You can see they were so fast that the wings were still blurred out even at that speed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A good rule of thumb for shutter speed while hand held is it should never be slower than the focal length. I.e at 50mm lens should not be hand held for exposures under 1/50th, 200mm no less than 1/200th.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;How the triangle works&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Each setting impacts the other two so finding a balance between the three is critical to any exposure. If an exposure is too dark you can try to slow your shutter speed down, increase your ISO, or open up your aperture. If you want a longer depth of field you need to close down your aperture, but increase your shutter speed or ISO to compensate. If you don&#39;t understand how each side of the triangle works and how it impacts the others then practice until you do. This is the foundation of photography and having a working understanding of them is of the utmost importance. We&#39;ll dive deeper into all three in later posts, but until then, keep practicing!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Week 8 - Chicago By Train</title>
      <link>http://www.gorilla-studios.com/2014/02/24/photo52-week8</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Feb 2014 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
      <author>chris@gorilla-studios.com (Chris Peak)</author>
      <guid>http://www.gorilla-studios.com/2014/02/24/photo52-week8</guid>
      <description>&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/p52/08.jpg&quot;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;February 24th - Chicago By Train&lt;span&gt;1/100, f/16, ISO100&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have been taking a series of photos during my morning commute into the city from the train, and this weeks entry is my favorite from the past few days. While very similar to Week 1, this time I decided to slow my shutter speed down to introduce some motion blur in the foreground while keeping the subject and background sharp. After pulling the photo into Lightroom it looks like I panned from left to right to keep the water tower in frame, dragging the exposure a bit - the consequence of this is that the water tower is sharp, the foreground is extremely blurred, and the background is just barely blurred. This panning technique is used by photographers to keep very fast moving subjects in focus while blurring out the background, emphasizing motion.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Week 7 - Snowy Bean</title>
      <link>http://www.gorilla-studios.com/2014/02/17/photo52-week7</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Feb 2014 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
      <author>chris@gorilla-studios.com (Chris Peak)</author>
      <guid>http://www.gorilla-studios.com/2014/02/17/photo52-week7</guid>
      <description>&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/p52/07.jpg&quot;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;February 17th - The Bean&lt;span&gt;1/250, f/5, ISO160&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I love to take photos nobody else has or would, which means putting myself through some uncomfortable situations at times. When another 5-8 inches of snow was forecast I saw a great opportunity to capture something unique while most sane people were bundled up at home. Leaving work and heading down to Millenium Park I got blasted in the face with snow no matter which direction I walked making me almost throw in the towel a few times. Since I don&#39;t have a weather cover I had to keep my camera tucked up underneath my coat while not shooting to keep the camera relatively dry and the lens clear. I quickly pulled the camera out when I found these two people were the only ones having fun underneath the sculpture, snapping this exposure as the woman reached out to touch it. I really love the sense of scale - the silhouette effect really adds to the sense of how large the sculpture really is.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Week 6 - Bald Eagle</title>
      <link>http://www.gorilla-studios.com/2014/02/09/photo52-week6</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Feb 2014 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
      <author>chris@gorilla-studios.com (Chris Peak)</author>
      <guid>http://www.gorilla-studios.com/2014/02/09/photo52-week6</guid>
      <description>&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/p52/06.jpg&quot;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;February 9th - Juvenile Bald Eagle&lt;span&gt;1/2000, f/6, ISO2000&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My trek in week 6 was spent along the frozen banks of the Fox River in Montgomery, IL. Bald Eagles have made a reappearance along the Fox in recent years, coming to town in January and February feeding along the exposed areas of the river. Although we were close, shooting with the Canon 100-400mm lens was tough. I could have easily used another 200mm to get in tighter. During the morning the adult eagles were few and far between although flew overhead a few times, it was mostly the juveniles out feeding.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Week 5 - Pritzker Pavilion</title>
      <link>http://www.gorilla-studios.com/2014/01/29/photo52-week5</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Jan 2014 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
      <author>chris@gorilla-studios.com (Chris Peak)</author>
      <guid>http://www.gorilla-studios.com/2014/01/29/photo52-week5</guid>
      <description>&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/p52/05.jpg&quot;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;January 29th - Pritzker Pavilion&lt;span&gt;10s, f/9, ISO50&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another chilly evening in Chicago, but this time I went down to Millenium Park. While there are ropes around Pritzker Pavilion I didn&#39;t feel too bad stepping over since there were already tracks through the snow and the security guard by the Bean seemed pretty engrossed in his smartphone. I jogged out to the center of the field and snapped a few shots trying to frame the bandshell, Aon Tower and the overhead beams as carefully as I could. I love the colors and how sharp this photo turned out. Worth getting a boot-full of snow.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Week 4 - Wrigley Building</title>
      <link>http://www.gorilla-studios.com/2014/01/24/photo52-week4</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Jan 2014 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
      <author>chris@gorilla-studios.com (Chris Peak)</author>
      <guid>http://www.gorilla-studios.com/2014/01/24/photo52-week4</guid>
      <description>&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/p52/04.jpg&quot;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;January 24th - Wrigley Building&lt;span&gt;13s, f/10, ISO50&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While trying to determine my next lens purchase I decided to rent Canon&#39;s 17-40mm f/4 wide-angle zoom lens this week to test it out in the field. I went for an extremely cold walk along the Chicago River and around Michigan Ave getting a feel how it performs. It did great wide open at 17mm and was tack sharp at f/10 with no noticeable issues. I would love to try something in the neighborhood of 14mm, but this is a great general purpose wide-angle. This was my favorite from the walk this week - the river was frozen over and the lights were just starting to come on as the sun disappeared behind the camera. Its tough shooting so wide because of the vertical distortion from the buildings, but if you keep that in mind while shooting you can give yourself some room to fix in post.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reach For The Sky</title>
      <link>http://www.gorilla-studios.com/2014/01/17/reach</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2014 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
      <author>chris@gorilla-studios.com (Chris Peak)</author>
      <guid>http://www.gorilla-studios.com/2014/01/17/reach</guid>
      <description>&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/reach-for-the-sky.jpg&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;figcaption class=&#39;light full&#39;&gt;Sears Tower&lt;span&gt;60s, f/6.3, ISO100&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Week 3 - Picasso</title>
      <link>http://www.gorilla-studios.com/2014/01/15/photo52-week3</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2014 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
      <author>chris@gorilla-studios.com (Chris Peak)</author>
      <guid>http://www.gorilla-studios.com/2014/01/15/photo52-week3</guid>
      <description>&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/p52/03.jpg&quot;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption class=&#39;vertical&#39;&gt;January 15th - Picasso&lt;span&gt;15s, f/13, ISO100&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Week 3 was the coldest photo I think I have taken in a long time due to the fact that we  are in the middle of another cold snap in Chicago. Despite the weather I layered up and ventured out for a walk through the city after work. At first I tried taking some long exposures on two bridges over the Chicago river but the vehicle traffic was shaking the camera too much so I moved on. After winding my way around the Loop I came to the Daley Center and found a group of bikers at the base of the Picasso sculpture  meeting up for a very chilly evening ride. They weren&#39;t in any hurry despite how cold it was so I took some longer exposures to get the bikes stationary while the riders were walking around talking to one another. They didn&#39;t seem to mind being photographed at all so I kept getting closer, at one point a few of them waved at the camera. This is one of the last exposures I got as they were getting ready to ride off into the night. I liked this particular frame because the bikes are in different states of opacity due to the movement.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Week 2 - Sears Tower</title>
      <link>http://www.gorilla-studios.com/2014/01/13/photo52-week2</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2014 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
      <author>chris@gorilla-studios.com (Chris Peak)</author>
      <guid>http://www.gorilla-studios.com/2014/01/13/photo52-week2</guid>
      <description>&lt;figure&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/images/p52/02.jpg&quot;&gt;
&lt;figcaption&gt;January 13th - Sears Tower&lt;span&gt;60s, f/20, ISO100&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This week I ventured out after work to one of my all time favorite Chicago subjects, The Sears Tower. I love how every angle presents a different look at the tower allowing you to keep going back for something different every time. For this particular photo I went to the top of the parking deck just across the street to the east where the 5th floor gives un-interrupted access away from all of the pedestrian traffic below. This was taken at 19mm which still was not enough to get everything, but I like how it turned out. The clouds were flying by at quite a clip, so a 60 second exposure smoothed them out. In color the sky was a brilliant pink with the yellow lights of the building dominating the exposure, but I prefer the high-contrast black and white here.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>XKCD - Photos</title>
      <link>http://www.gorilla-studios.com/2014/01/08/xkcd</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2014 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
      <author>chris@gorilla-studios.com (Chris Peak)</author>
      <guid>http://www.gorilla-studios.com/2014/01/08/xkcd</guid>
      <description>&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/xkcd.jpg&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://xkcd.com/1314/&quot;&gt;Perfect post from XKCD&lt;/a&gt; about people taking photos. I completely agree, with the exception being concerts - I cannot stand people with cell phones taking photos at concerts.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sears Tower Sunburst</title>
      <link>http://www.gorilla-studios.com/2014/01/07/sears-tower-sunburst</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2014 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
      <author>chris@gorilla-studios.com (Chris Peak)</author>
      <guid>http://www.gorilla-studios.com/2014/01/07/sears-tower-sunburst</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As previously mentioned I have recently been taking a few photos every morning during my commute into the city trying to get a certain shot which I haven&#39;t posted until now. The window to get the shot was literally around 1 or 2 seconds long, so I had to be very careful with my timing. As the UPW train starts its wide turn into the loop the sun passes right behind the Sears Tower, giving me very little time to get the shot - about 1 frame with the sun on the south side, a few while its directly behind, and once on the north side.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first two days I tried from the upstairs seats but was shooting through a tinted window - while this worked for a few shots, specifically my &lt;a href=&quot;2014/01/02/photo-of-the-month/&quot;&gt;December Photo of the Month&lt;/a&gt;, for this particular instance it just wasn&#39;t working. On the third day I went downstairs into the vestibule in the center of the car where the windows don&#39;t have any tint and are generally cleaner for some reason. I ended up with this version which I am very happy with.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/chicago/sunburst.jpg&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;figcaption class=&#39;light full&#39;&gt;Sears Tower Sunburst&lt;span&gt;55mm, f/6.3, ISO100&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was able to get the sun just as it was dissapearing behind the tower with minimal effects from the sun. Some earlier shots looked like something out of Star Trek with a ton of lens flaring, but I really perfer the subdued version with just the beams. Without the window tint the sky was a beautiful rich almost baby blue, and the sun cast a slight yellow on the steam arising from the various buildings in the skyline. It could be cropped a little tighter but I do like the silhouetted buildings adding a bit of interest in the foreground.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://www.gorilla-studios.com/2014/01/05/photo365-review</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jan 2014 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
      <author>chris@gorilla-studios.com (Chris Peak)</author>
      <guid>http://www.gorilla-studios.com/2014/01/05/photo365-review</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Here are my 12 &#39;Photo of the Month&#39; selections for my Photo365 Challenge in 2013. Looking back at the selections I realize only February and August were roughly planned shots taken when I specifically went out for a shoot, otherwise they were all improvised. It was a perfect split 6 color and 6 black &amp;amp; white, and to my surprise 7 of them were vertical, with only 5 horizontal shots. I had a lot of fun shooting all year and am looking forward to the next batch.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/pom_january.jpg&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;January Photo of the Month - Snowy Chicago&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/pom_february.jpg&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;figcaption class=&#39;vertical&#39;&gt;February Photo of the Month - Waterfall Glen&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#39;/images/pod/81_full.jpg&#39; /&gt;
  &lt;figcaption class=&#39;vertical&#39;&gt;March Photo of the Month - Union Station&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#39;/images/pod/118_full.jpg&#39; /&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;April Photo of the Month - Flooded Geneva&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#39;/images/pod/150_full.jpg&#39; /&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;May Photo of the Month - Rialto Theatre, Joliet, IL&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#39;/images/pod/161_full.jpg&#39; /&gt;
  &lt;figcaption class=&#39;vertical&#39;&gt;June Photo of the Month - Anchor &amp;amp; Hope Oyster Chef&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#39;/images/pod/200_full.jpg&#39; /&gt;
  &lt;figcaption class=&#39;vertical&#39;&gt;July Photo of the Month - Strange Angles&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#39;/images/pod/220_full.jpg&#39; /&gt;
  &lt;figcaption class=&#39;vertical&#39;&gt;August Photo of the Month - Rick Uppling, Cadillac Cassanovas&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#39;/images/pod/258_full.jpg&#39; /&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;September Photo of the Month - Autum Leaf&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#39;/images/pod/303_full.jpg&#39; /&gt;
  &lt;figcaption class=&#39;vertical&#39;&gt;October Photo of the Month - Connor Portrait&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#39;/images/pod/312_full.jpg&#39; /&gt;
  &lt;figcaption class=&#39;vertical&#39;&gt;November Photo of the Month - Chicago Sunset from Aon Center&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#39;/images/pod/352_full.jpg&#39; /&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;December Photo of the Month - Train Signal&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Week 1 - Watertower</title>
      <link>http://www.gorilla-studios.com/2014/01/03/photo52-watertower</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jan 2014 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
      <author>chris@gorilla-studios.com (Chris Peak)</author>
      <guid>http://www.gorilla-studios.com/2014/01/03/photo52-watertower</guid>
      <description>&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/p52/01.jpg&quot;&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;January 3rd - Forest Park Watertower&lt;span&gt;1/1000, f/5.6, ISO100&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Week 1 was a continuation of my series of silhouette shots I was getting from my train ride into the city every morning. My primary goal was the Sears Tower shot I had been working on, but I took this photo as we were passing through Forest Park. It doesn&#39;t have the sun bursting out like the others, and the blue tint of the train window really made this photo work.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://www.gorilla-studios.com/2014/01/02/photo-of-the-month</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2014 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
      <author>chris@gorilla-studios.com (Chris Peak)</author>
      <guid>http://www.gorilla-studios.com/2014/01/02/photo-of-the-month</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;My final Photo of the Month was a shot that inspired a small collection of photos that I will post soon. I was riding the Metra and decided to keep my camera out to see if I could find anything creative that was right under my nose every morning. I take the Union Pacific West line which heads directly east into the city and early in the morning the sun is particularly low in the sky allowing for some really creative shots. I snapped this one as the sun was directly behind a crossing signal, creating a really striking silhouette.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#39;/images/pod/352_full.jpg&#39; /&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;December Photo of the Month - Train Signal&lt;span&gt;100mm, 1/640s, f/6.3, ISO100&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I typically hate shooting through the Metra windows because they are scratched, dirty, and usually tinted some really awful 1970s orange or green. Although I found having the sun right behind my subject exaggerated the green tint creating an extremely saturated background to the completely solid black foreground.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the same trip in I got a shot of the sun passing behind the Sears Tower, along with a handful of other photos, but none quite as striking as this one. I made three more attempts of the Sears shot (as well as one attempt with my iPhone for a fun comparison), which I will post along with the others soon.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hello 2014!</title>
      <link>http://www.gorilla-studios.com/2014/01/01/hello-2014</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2014 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
      <author>chris@gorilla-studios.com (Chris Peak)</author>
      <guid>http://www.gorilla-studios.com/2014/01/01/hello-2014</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;What a busy year it&#39;s been and yet I know for certain that 2014 will be even busier. In 2013 I got to travel a bit - London for a week and San Fransisco for a few days, I finished my &lt;a href=&quot;photo365.html&quot;&gt;Photo365 Challenge&lt;/a&gt;, invested in some new equipment including a Canon 6D, spent a lot of time reading books &amp;amp; blogs and listening to photo podcasts, completely rewrote and launched the lastest version of the website, and most importantly hopefully have grown as a photographer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Photo365&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The biggest project this year was my Photo365 challenge - the goal of which was to have my camera on me at all times and make myself take at least one photo per day all year long. The motivation was part journalistic, part learning but mostly pushing myself to stick with it and keep practicing. Surprisingly I didn&#39;t struggle until maybe October or November when I really had to focus to get something. It became harder to find something unique to photograph - commuting downtown every day and going through my usual routine made it difficult to branch out - hence the myriad of train related photographs. I took different routes to and from the train station but I was still in the city during the day and in my apartment at night. The weekends were a lot easier, but there were a lot of nights around 10 or 11 when I realized I didn&#39;t take anything that day and had to scramble.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Overall I am very pleased with how the project turned out. Having my camera on me every day allowed me to take some great photos that I normally would have missed but on the other side when I wasn&#39;t feeling very creative or was busy I had some absolute duds. I decided to be honest and put the bad ones up as well so I could see my progress throughout the project, the benefit being when I saw them mixed in I would remember why they didn&#39;t work or what went wrong. I also wanted to do as little post-processing as possible so the gallery stays honest to what was captured in camera.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Looking Ahead&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To say that 2014 will be the biggest year of my life is a bit of an understatement. I will be moving to London in a few months for at least one year, there are a lot of things brewing for Gorilla-Studios.com, and even more things in my personal life. At my day job personal quarterly goals are set so we can track our progress as craftsmen and I would like to apply this principal to this part of my life as well - I highly recommend this to anyone, especially this time of year. These are the four areas I will be focusing on this year in terms of my photography:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Photo730 / Photo52&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So I have one photo per day over the last year, but I would like to continue this. I want to mix it up a bit - I will be continuing the photo per day, but I plan on using my iPhone to document this year. This doesn&#39;t mean I am putting down my 6D though - I now plan to go out once a week to take more focused photos that might make their way into my portfolio. I think I&#39;ll get higher quality work by slowing down a bit, planning a little more, and being able to take time to capture what I want.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Expanding Gorilla-Studios&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Gorilla-Studios technically turned 10 this year. I originally launched the site on December 12th, 2003 and thankfully don&#39;t have any screenshots or archives of it because I&#39;m sure it was horrid. It has grown over the years, been torn down and re-written multiple times as I continued to grow as a photographer and web designer, finally becoming what it is today. However all this work will not cease - I have plenty of ideas for growing the site coming in 2014. Plenty to announce, but now is not the time!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;London&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The major shift in my life is that my wife and I are packing up and moving to London in just a few months. To say this is a great opportunity as a photographer is the understatement of the century. I spent a week in London back in May, but most of my time was consumed with a conference for work. Now that I have the opportunity to reside there for at least a year I am salivating at the chances I will have to expand my portfolio and meet some great new people. I want to focus more on street photography and learn more about telling a story with one photo, I have always admired photographers who have more of a journalistic approach. I will also share my experiences as an American photographer living overseas - it&#39;s a perspective that I haven&#39;t seen before so I plan on writing about it quite extensively. More details in the next few weeks about my plans.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Learning&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Above all else I want to keep pushing myself as a photographer, learning new techniques, ideas, and perspectives. I am making the jump to Adobe Lightroom after 10+ years of a Photoshop-based workflow so this will be an interesting transition. I also plan to focus more on Travel and Street photography considering we will be in Europe all year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I plan on keeping tabs on my goals every quarter to see how I am doing so I can make changes as needed. I can&#39;t wait to see what 2014 brings, and hope everyone has an exciting year as I will.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Light Pollution</title>
      <link>http://www.gorilla-studios.com/2013/12/20/light-pollution</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2013 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
      <author>chris@gorilla-studios.com (Chris Peak)</author>
      <guid>http://www.gorilla-studios.com/2013/12/20/light-pollution</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Do you live in a urban area or close to a city and have too much light pollution for good night photography? I love long exposures of star trails and night skies, but since I live near Chicago it&#39;s next to impossible to view stars let alone take any photos. Previously I would look at Google Maps to plot where I might drive to by looking for sparse areas, but even then its a guess as to how much light pollution there is in the area.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Luckily I found a tool called &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.blue-marble.de/nightlights/2012&quot;&gt;Blue Marble&lt;/a&gt; which overlays nighttime satellite images onto Google Maps allowing you to plot where the best spots for stargazing would be.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#39;/images/light-pollution.jpg&#39; /&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As you can see above, Chicago and its surrounding counties are completely worthless. To find a suitable spot I have to drive at least a few hours, and for spectacular night skies I think Nebraska is the closest location. Check out where you live and find the best spot near you to haul out your photo gear and or telescope.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why I Don't Machine Gun</title>
      <link>http://www.gorilla-studios.com/2013/12/10/why-i-dont-machine-gun</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Dec 2013 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
      <author>chris@gorilla-studios.com (Chris Peak)</author>
      <guid>http://www.gorilla-studios.com/2013/12/10/why-i-dont-machine-gun</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Over the weekend read an article on some random photo site about bad habits photographers make. I won&#39;t cite the article because when I went back to find it, it popped up word for word on 3 different sites so I have no idea who actually wrote it (thats a rant for another day). Anyway, one of the points was &#39;Luck Shooting&#39;, or spraying and praying as some photographers call it. It really got me thinking about how I shoot concerts and candid photography. So much of what I do relies on anticipating the perfect moment to capture, not just hammering the shutter button and hoping I get something useable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A good photographer gets a sense of whats about to happen, your gut starts telling you to wait for the best possible moment, you just start knowing whats going to happen. In psychology getting to this point can be likened to the final stage of the &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Four_stages_of_competence&quot;&gt;Four Stages of Competence&lt;/a&gt;. At first you don&#39;t recognize the deficit of knowledge regarding a skill or task, then realize that you don&#39;t know how to perform said task, moving into knowing but having to actively think about performing it, finally the task is performed without thinking - having become an expert.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It took me a long time to hone this skill. I first realized it was something I needed to work on when I would shoot candid photos and people would look really strange when they were talking or performing a physical activity. I progressed as a photographer and a few years later I was taking photos at a picnic of coworkers playing kickball, where I found myself talking through the motions, actively thinking about how they were going to wind up for the pitch, how their body would move, where the ball might go, etc. Now after shooting countless portraits, concerts, and talks I am to the point where I don&#39;t even think about it actively - at talks I wait for the speaker to gesticulate energetically and smile instead of capturing a boring photo of them at a podium mid-sentence. Portraits and headshots I always take a few frames before telling a joke so I can capture the best photo of the shoot right as their laughing is subsiding yet they are still smiling ear to ear. At concerts I am watching the bassist haul his guitar up on his knee as he shouts out to the crowd to my left I know he is going to look back my way in a second or two, his head quickly pivots and I snap two frames.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#39;/images/music/bass.jpg&#39; /&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Anticipate your shot, feel whats coming next&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I honed this skill over years behind the lens. I listen to the beat of the drummer and feel when the big crescendo of the song is coming. Sometimes, especially with children, it has to be a split second decision as something magical happens. I try to talk to speakers before they go on to see if they will be entertaining or more reserved.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of my all time favorite photos was taken so quickly but I knew instantly what I had got. My friends and I were out taking photos of the Bean in Millenium Park one fall evening. I was shooting some longer exposures to get a touch of motion blur to accentuate how busy the park was as the sun was starting to set. Out of nowhere a wedding party appeared just outside of the frame to my right - suddenly the bride and groom stepped into frame as the photographer was gathering everyone. There was a quick kiss but she was completely behind him. Had I started spraying at that moment I would have been looking down at the camera and missed what happened next. The groom took her hand and just as I locked focus on him he raised his arm with hers. I knew he was going to spin her, but she was still behind him. I paused a split second and as their arms completed the motion she twirled out from behind. I opened the shutter exactly once and I knew instantly that he was in focus but since I was dragging the shutter she was going to blur a bit capturing the spin perfectly. As soon as his hands were coming down the entire wedding party entered the scene completely blocking the happy couple. The window was less than a few seconds. I anticipated the shot, took it at the right moment and got exactly what I wanted.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#39;/images/portfolio/dance.jpg&#39; /&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;I had one chance and the window was less than 2 seconds&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Machine gunning photos is bad photography with so many downsides. Your memory card is going to fill up really fast with crap images and while you are looking through the last ten you rattled off I guarantee you are missing the next great shot. If you are in a quiet environment like a wedding or conference where that shutter cranking away is going to distract and annoy a lot of people. If you practice and actively think about the shots you are going to take it is going to improve your photography. When you have to grind through actively thinking about timing, lighting, framing, and exposure, you will know it through and through and it will become second nature. You are going to stop firing off 10 photos then looking down to see if you got something. You&#39;ll pop off a shot or two and just know you got something great, and let me tell you, thats a great feeling.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://www.gorilla-studios.com/2013/12/01/photo-of-the-month</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2013 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
      <author>chris@gorilla-studios.com (Chris Peak)</author>
      <guid>http://www.gorilla-studios.com/2013/12/01/photo-of-the-month</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;My favorite photo from November was taken from the 80th floor of the Aeon Center in downtown Chicago. I am lucky enough to shoot my company&#39;s yearly software craftsmanship conference and this year provided some spectacular sunsets. I was wrapping up at the end of the first day and packing my gear when I saw a few people going to the west side of the building and pulling out their phones. I hurriedly got my tripod out and was able to snap some longer exposures right as the sun was dipping below the horizon. The photo was an 8 second exposure at f/16.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#39;/images/pod/312_full.jpg&#39; /&gt;
  &lt;figcaption class=&#39;vertical&#39;&gt;November Photo of the Month - Chicago sunset&lt;span&gt;19mm, 1/200th, f/16, ISO100&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The picture looks fantastic and I got a lot of positive feedback on it from various places, but I am still disappointed that the window was rather dirty. At larger sizes you can see streaking and image distortion around the Sears Tower which I hope I can lessen or remove in Photoshop, but that will be a lot of work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I can&#39;t believe I only have a month left for the Photo365 challenge. I&#39;ve kept with it the best I can, but its been getting difficult to post every day. I still have my camera on me, but as it gets colder its getting much more difficult to get out over lunch or take a longer walk after work to get some good images. I just have to brave the cold for another few weeks and I will have hit my goal! Time to keep shooting.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Time Lapse From Aeon Center</title>
      <link>http://www.gorilla-studios.com/2013/11/15/first-time-lapse</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Nov 2013 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
      <author>chris@gorilla-studios.com (Chris Peak)</author>
      <guid>http://www.gorilla-studios.com/2013/11/15/first-time-lapse</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Every year my company hosts the &lt;a href=&quot;http://scna.softwarecraftsmanship.org&quot;&gt;Software Craftsmanship North America conference&lt;/a&gt;, a gathering of professionals in the software industry, located atop the Aeon Center in downtown Chicago. I am lucky enough to be the primary photographer for the two-day event which means I get the chance to soak in the fantastic views from the 80th floor when I am not running around shooting the conference. Since the event is held mid-November each day ends with superlative views of the sun setting over the Chicago skyline. The first night I was able to setup my tripod and get some great still frames like the one below, but I realized this would be the perfect opportunity to make a stunning time-lapse. Only problem is I have never done one.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#39;/images/aeon-sunset.jpg&#39; /&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Sunset from the 80th Floor, Aeon Center, Chicago &lt;span&gt;19mm, 8s, f/16, ISO100&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The basics of time-lapse photography is taking photos at set intervals and stitching them together afterwards to create the a video of stills, the standard rate being 30 frames per second of video. I had a cable release, but it was analog so I couldn&#39;t set it to fire at specific intervals - I would have to shoot tethered to the computer. To do so you must install Canon&#39;s EOS Utility Software, which *requires* your disc that came with the camera (I&#39;ll rant about the inability to download directly from Canon). The utility allows you to control the camera over USB through the computer - allowing live view, focus controls, basic camera functions, as well as continuous interval shooting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My goal was a longer video, of about 30 seconds, and at 30 frames per second I was going to need to capture 900 photos. I set it to shoot every second, dumping the photos to an external HD attached to my laptop so I wouldn&#39;t fill up the cameras SD card. Since I was shooting the sun going down I set the camera to Aperture Priority Mode, dialing it in to f/16. I assumed that since the lighting was going to shift a great deal the camera could recognize that and adjust the shutter speed accordingly. Everything looked great, so I started the series and went about my business.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I would poke my head in every few minutes to make sure everything was going well, and for the first 10-15 minutes everything looked great. I had wanted to catch the sun going down, disappearing, then the city lights coming on as magic hour set in. Unfortunately about 5 minutes after sunset I started looking at some of the exposures and noticed that the ISO was maxed out to 12500 and they were looking terrible. The camera thought it was supposed to be a normally light daylight shot, and therefore started cranking the ISO to get as much light as possible - this was the exact opposite of what I wanted. I had hopped that it would start taking longer and longer exposures, leaving the sky dark and bringing the city lights up as they turned on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#39;youtube&#39;&gt;
  &lt;iframe width=&quot;520&quot; height=&quot;415&quot; src=&quot;//www.youtube.com/embed/9sZw3pE0lDE?vq=hd720&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I knew I wasn&#39;t going to get exactly what I wanted, but I hoped at least the first portion would be usable. I found a good point to stop at just after the sun dips below the horizon. I batch converted the RAWs into JPGs so I could compile them into a movie. To make the actual movie I found a free utility called &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.dayofthenewdan.com/projects/time-lapse-assembler-1/&quot;&gt;Time Lapse Assembler&lt;/a&gt;. You can choose your target frame-rate, codec to encode with and a few other options. Once the processing finished I got about 11 seconds of okay footage. Its a bit darker than I had hoped for, but overall I&#39;ll call it a success. Even though I didn&#39;t get the whole lapse I wanted it was a great learning experience. I think my next attempt I will bump the intervals to every 5 seconds and play with the exposure compensation to see what happens. I won&#39;t get another chance to shoot from Aeon again until next November, but I will definitely be ready by then.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://www.gorilla-studios.com/2013/11/03/photo-of-the-month</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Nov 2013 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <author>chris@gorilla-studios.com (Chris Peak)</author>
      <guid>http://www.gorilla-studios.com/2013/11/03/photo-of-the-month</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;My Photo of the Month from October was a quick headshot for my co-worker Connor who completed his residency to become a Craftsman at 8th Light. I take all the bio photos for our website, so I am lucky enough to get everyone in front of my camera when they come on board. I love doing natural light portraits but they can be tricky in our office - which is a mix of fluorescent and incandescent bulbs combined with very tall windows that let natural sunlight pour in at certain points during the day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since these are small photos for our website I can&#39;t dedicate much time to them, the shoots are usually no more than a few minutes a piece. Connor was very comfortable in front of the camera which made things really easy. It was mid-morning so the light was coming in from the windows to camera left. I also lined him underneath a hanging light to create some highlighting from above which added a nice detail to the top of his head. We have a gorgeous chalk wall that Stephanie spent a lot of time on which, when blurred out creates a fun texture behind the subject. The arrow in the right of the frame adds a little cheekiness pointing back at Connor, business portraits don&#39;t always have to be straight laced. The mix of natural light and an incandescent bulb overhead makes for a little more editing to balance out the color temperature but overall I love the lighting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#39;/images/pod/303_full.jpg&#39; /&gt;
  &lt;figcaption class=&#39;vertical&#39;&gt;October Photo of the Month - Connor M Portrait &lt;span&gt;50mm, 1/125th, f/3.5, ISO100&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My Canon 50mm 1.8 is my go-to lens for portraits since it is tack-sharp around 2.8 or 3.5. It allows me to shoot at a comfortable distance from the subject, but a bonus is that when I want to fill the frame I can take a few steps forward and say &#39;..and now to make you a bit more uncomfortable&#39; which usually always solicits a good smile and laugh. When getting your subject to laugh be sure to snap right after the initial &#39;burst&#39;, the best frames are just as the laugh is dying down to a good smile. I always try some serious shots and some basic posed smiling, but the best ones are always the candid laugh. Thanks for being a good sport Connor!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nine Months With The Kata Bag</title>
      <link>http://www.gorilla-studios.com/2013/10/28/nine-months-of-kata</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Oct 2013 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <author>chris@gorilla-studios.com (Chris Peak)</author>
      <guid>http://www.gorilla-studios.com/2013/10/28/nine-months-of-kata</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It has been over nine months since I bought my &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.kata-bags.us/3n1-33-dl-for-dslr-w-long-range-zoom-lens-5-6-lenses-flash-ktdl-3n1-33&quot;&gt;Kata 3N1-33 Sling Backpack&lt;/a&gt; so lets take a look at the bag and how it&#39;s held up through daily usage so far...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/images/kata.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Kata 3N1-33 Sling Backpack&quot; /&gt;
&lt;figcaption&gt;Kata 3N1-33 Sling Backpack&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Initially I made the purchase because I need to carry a laptop every day for work and am still in the thick of my &lt;a href=&quot;/photo365.html&quot;&gt;Photo 365 Challenge&lt;/a&gt;. The main compartment of the bag is comprised of a number of velcro sided dividers that can be configured to fit whatever gear you may have. I can easily fit my EOS 6D and with battery grip paired with a 70-200 2.8 in the center, with room for 4 or 5 lenses. My typical daily setup consists of 3 lenses, my filters, and a Canon 430EX flash (with diffuser). I sacrifice a lens slot to accomodate the grip side of the SLR body, otherwise its just a bit too tight for my comfort.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/images/kata-inside.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Kata 3N1-33 Sling Backpack&quot; /&gt;
&lt;figcaption&gt;Inside the main section of the Kata 3N1-33&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Above is the bag laying on its back, photographed from above. The bottom &#39;row&#39; sits at the very bottom of the pack. The compartment is zippered to allow access from either right or left sides. I have my 50mm Macro lens, my filters and filter holder, and my small 50mm 1.8 tucked in the corner. Directly across from the body on the left side of the bag is my old zoom lens. The top row consists of my 430EX Flash with room for its diffuser, as well as another slot for a lens. The very last lens spot has been inverted to make room for the grip side of the SLR body. The lens sections are very deep and really meant for professional grade glass. Kit and small body lenses tend to wander around the bag if you&#39;re not careful. For example the 50mm 1.8 is a tiny lens, and if I don&#39;t stuff the Kata rain cover (included with the bag) with it, it will usually jump out of its slot which makes me very nervous. I have never had problems with anything falling out of the bag when opening, and the whole thing is generously padded so it holds up to daily use with ease. Its been with me to work every day as well as my London and San Francisco trips.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&#39;s an extremely rugged bag meant for heavy outdoor use. Kata proudly advertises its versatility as both a regular backpack and a sling bag. The straps can unclip and clip back to either side, allowing you to sling it over either shoulder. I don&#39;t use it as a sling bag, but having it over one shoulder allows me to simply swing it around my front giving me full access to the main portion of the bag for quick lens changes or accessing other gear without putting the bag down. It came with an additional rain cover which has kept my gear nice and dry while commuting during the rainy Chicago spring (and fall) this year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/images/kata-top.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Kata 3N1-33 Sling Backpack&quot; /&gt;
&lt;figcaption&gt;Inside the top section of the Kata 3N1-33&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The top of the bag has plenty of general storage for extra gear, as well as a zippered pouch which I keep my wired remote, my wireless flash triggers, extra memory cards, and other small items. The open area is perfectly sized for my lunch and a bottle of water (I doubt they had that in mind, but it&#39;s a great perk. You can also see the slot for the laptop which will easily accommodate laptops up to 17 inches.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The bag is very comfortable even fully loaded. The straps are wide and very well padded, and there are two great handle straps on either side of the top of the bag. Im not sure if it&#39;s their purpose, but I slide two tripod legs through them to hang it off one side. My only two complaints are very minor which speaks volumes to the quality of the bag. One is the small strap that keeps the laptop from sliding out of the sleeve - I find myself closing the top of the bag and getting the zipper hung up on it, having to flip it back into the bag before closing the top (I admit its a minor annoyance). The other is the fact that the left shoulder strap is black on both sides while the right is white on the underside. This is meant as a visual clue for the sling feature - the tabs where the straps click in on the bottom of the bag are the same way but on opposite sides, letting you know you can click the left strap to the right side (white to white), and vice-versa. My problem is that over nine months of daily use the white part of the strap has turned an ugly dark grey.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Overall the bag is still almost new, with no wear on it whatsoever. I feel very secure carrying my gear and laptop in the bag and rarely have any fears of damaging equipment. I would highly recommend this bag to anyone who is looking for a high-quality SLR/Laptop (or just SLR) bag. Check out &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.kata-bags.us&quot;&gt;Kata Bags&lt;/a&gt; for their full range of products as well as &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.kata-bags.us/Media+Center/Watch+Videos/?cat1=marketing+videos&quot;&gt;videos of their bags in use&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://www.gorilla-studios.com/2013/10/03/photo-of-the-month</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Oct 2013 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <author>chris@gorilla-studios.com (Chris Peak)</author>
      <guid>http://www.gorilla-studios.com/2013/10/03/photo-of-the-month</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;My Photo of the Month from September was a macro shot I snapped one morning on the way to the train station. I have been so busy with work and other things on my plate its been very difficult to keep up, but I have stuck with the 365 challenge so far. Even though I have been running around like mad, I love this shot I grabbed in only a minute or two during my commute. The leaves in late September are just starting to turn in the Chicagoland area and this particular one caught my eye as it laid on the ground. I love the brilliance of the color combined with the texture, I had to fill the entire frame with it, which was not particularly hard because this leaf was about the size of my hand!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#39;/images/pod/258_full.jpg&#39; /&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;September Photo of the Month - An Autumn Leaf - Macro&lt;span&gt;1/125th, f/4, ISO100&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now that its early October the leaves are really starting to turn, its a fantastic month for landscape photography, so grab your gear and get outside!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hofner Guitars Used My Photo</title>
      <link>http://www.gorilla-studios.com/2013/09/10/hofner</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Sep 2013 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <author>chris@gorilla-studios.com (Chris Peak)</author>
      <guid>http://www.gorilla-studios.com/2013/09/10/hofner</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Over the weekend I got to shoot Just Enuff playing the Monee Fall Festival, and had a great time. I provided the band with the best photos from the day which they used on their site and their Facebook page. Monday morning I got a few messages from various people saying that Hofner Bass was using my photo as their cover photo on their Facebook page. Sure enough when I pulled up the page, there&#39;s one of my photos, cropped to hell right on the bass guitar that Mike was playing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#39;/images/hofner.jpg&#39; /&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Hofner Guitars Facebook Page&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now I have had a few days to reflect on it and im still just not sure to feel about this. I know a lot of photographers would be livid about having their worked ripped off and not being attributed, but on the other side its a Facebook cover photo that it seems they change daily. I&#39;m bummed that nobody contacted me before, or since, but thats just the way it is. My wife tried plugging my work in the comments, and from what I understand they would plug me if I sent them more work, so thats always an option. Overall I think I&#39;m mainly dissapointed I didn&#39;t get a higher quality shot of the bass itself. I usually snap some close-ups of the instruments but they are usually kind of boring. I&#39;ll certainly keep this experience in the back of my head next time around so I can reach out to the instrument companies and maybe pick up some work.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://www.gorilla-studios.com/2013/09/03/photo-of-the-month</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Sep 2013 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <author>chris@gorilla-studios.com (Chris Peak)</author>
      <guid>http://www.gorilla-studios.com/2013/09/03/photo-of-the-month</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;My favorite photo in August came from Cruise Nights in downtown Westmont, IL. &lt;a href=&quot;http://cadillaccasanovas.com&quot;&gt;The Cadillac Cassanovas&lt;/a&gt; are a great three piece rockabilly band from the Chicagoland area who put on a great show who I was lucky enough back in May to shoot at the Arcada in St. Charles. So when I saw that they were playing not far from me, I knew I had to grab the camera and head over to see them. This particular shot serves as an example of sticking to it and not leaving until the show is over, your cards or full, or your batteries are dead. The event was in front of a really ugly brick building with a really distracting banner behind them and people walking all over, needless to say it wasn&#39;t the greatest venue to shoot at. Their first set was probably around 7, and in broad daylight. Really hard light, poor shooting conditions, and super hot so I wasn&#39;t really happy with too many shots. I got a few but overall nothing compared to the Arcada show. During the break between sets I walked around checking out the cool cars and cooling off a little bit, and almost decided to go home. Thankfully I didn&#39;t.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was lucky enough to meet the guys backstage at the Arcada show so I really try to do my best to get some great images for them, but I just wasn&#39;t feeling it that night. However, I decided to stick with it and see what I could get in the second set. As the sun started going down their stage lights started to take over as the primary light source. Using a faster shutter speed I started blackening out the background which was full of distractions. This particular photo is a portrait of the Cassanovas bass player Rick Uppling. Rick is a great musician and always fun to photograph since he&#39;s usually jumping around, standing on his huge upright bass, or just generally hamming it up for the audience. The stage lights were to his left creating a great backlight that highlighted the edges of his face, creating a wonderful edge silhouette. While shooting I was careful not to cut off the headstock of his bass, as well as try to get both hands in shot. Framing can be tricky when photographing musicians in concert, especially guitarists and bassists.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#39;/images/pod/220_full.jpg&#39; /&gt;
  &lt;figcaption class=&#39;vertical&#39;&gt;August Photo of the Month - Rick Uppling of the Cadillac Cassanovas&lt;span&gt;1/200th, f/5.6, ISO2500&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Their stage lighting setup was casting a bunch of different color all over the place, so the color version of this photo was really strange looking. I ran it through Silver Efex Pro to convert it to black &amp;amp; white and thats when the photo really jumped. My only critique is that I caught the lead signer &amp;amp; guitarist Carl&#39;s headstock poking into the left side of frame. Overall I love this portrait and am really thankful that I stuck with it that night. Be sure to check their &lt;a href=&quot;http://cadillaccasanovas.com&quot;&gt;website&lt;/a&gt; to see when the Cassanovas will be rocking near you.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://www.gorilla-studios.com/2013/08/30/retiring-the-10D</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Aug 2013 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <author>chris@gorilla-studios.com (Chris Peak)</author>
      <guid>http://www.gorilla-studios.com/2013/08/30/retiring-the-10D</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Back in June I finally retired my first digital SLR - an extremely trustworthy Canon EOS 10D which I purchased brand-new in the summer of 2003. Despite being so old, I continued to shoot with the 6.3MP crop-sensor DSLR when most people were scrambling to trade in their 5DMkII&#39;s for new Mark III&#39;s. I knew that camera like the back of my hand, through and through. It served for years as a shining example of why you don&#39;t need to rush out to buy the latest gear to get great images. I looked it up and realized that when I purchased it, Canon&#39;s line-up of DSLR&#39;s consisted of the 1D and 10D - thats it. Most of my favorite portfolio shots came from that camera, and I bet if you look at my &lt;a href=&quot;/portfolio.html&quot;&gt;galleries&lt;/a&gt; you couldn&#39;t pick out which ones were shot with that 6.3MP 10D, my new 20.2MP 6D, or the 5DMkIII I was lucky enough to take on vacation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I really don&#39;t like reading reviews of brand new camera gear or technology, I prefer to wait until it&#39;s been used in the real world for some time before I start forming an opinion on it. For example when I worked in the IT industry a few years ago the first round of solid-state hard drives were starting to hit the market - reviews were proclaiming that they were the second coming! They reported that the drives were fast and more importantly extremely durable. While this holds true to most new drives these days, the first generation drives from multiple manufacturers started failing pretty spectacularly about 6 months into real-world usage. Personally I don&#39;t care how amazing a camera performs right out of the box, how sharp a lens is from the factory. Show it to me a year or two down the road when its been used for weddings every weekend, or out on a photo trip to Africa, is it still as good?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Okay, so why am I up on my soapbox this time? I just never see reviews for gear thats been used in the field, so thats what I would like to start doing. Sure, taking a look back on an extremely worn camera thats 10 years old doesn&#39;t really provide much value other than to speak volumes about the brand, but in a month or two I plan on writing a post about how my Kata SLR/Laptop bag has held up being hauled around day to day as well as travelling around the world with me. But for now, lets see how 10 years of wear and tear took its toll on one of Canons earlier digital SLRs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#39;/images/10d-retire.jpg&#39; /&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Canon EOS 10D&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After 10 years of abuse the camera is still in decent shape. The only functional problem with it was that the primary shutter button was starting to flake out, which for normal landscapes is not a big deal, but when you are trying to track a Great Blue Heron in flight you need it to work 100% of the time. I can&#39;t even guess how many exposures the shutter had on it, but it was probably significant. The only issue I had with the shutter was an ERR99 once back in 2006, but never it happened again. Towards the end the camera would lock up every now and then, requiring me to pull the batteries and put them back in.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At sometime in 2010 one of the arms on the eye cup that keep it in place snapped so it wouldn&#39;t stay on. Other than that, its got some scratches and wear marks but thats it. It&#39;s held up like a tank, and most of the damage is purely cosmetic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#39;/images/10d-retire3.jpg&#39; /&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Canon EOS 10D&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This camera just shows the quality the Canon brand delivers. Ten years is a very long time for any piece of equipment, let alone something as high-precision as an SLR. It&#39;s been at my side while sloshing around rivers, knee deep in snow, sudden downpours, freezing nights, and hot summer days. I love this camera, and while I&#39;m sad it&#39;s going up on the shelf, I am excited to see what kind of adventures my new EOS 6D will have with me.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://www.gorilla-studios.com/2013/08/28/nik-software</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Aug 2013 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <author>chris@gorilla-studios.com (Chris Peak)</author>
      <guid>http://www.gorilla-studios.com/2013/08/28/nik-software</guid>
      <description>&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#39;/images/silverfx2.jpg&#39; /&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Silver Efex Pro 2 by Google.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have spent the past two weeks playing around with &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.niksoftware.com/nikcollection/usa/intro.html&quot;&gt;The Nik Collection&lt;/a&gt; by Google, which is comprised of Silver Efex Pro 2, Dfine 2, Viveza 2, HDR Efex Pro 2, Color Efex Pro 4, and Sharpener Pro 3. They are a set of tools to provide you with a wider array of options when it comes to color correction, black and white conversion, noise reduction and more.  The main reason for downloading the free trial was to play around with Silver Efex which comes highly recommended from a few pro photographers I follow. I wasn&#39;t expecting miracles from the software, but I was hoping to be impressed enough to purchase the package and integrate it into my workflow, which I am always looking to improve.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Downloading was a breeze and installation was as simple as any application on the Mac, so there were no issues there. When you open up an image in Photoshop you get a fairly jarring popup window with links to launch each of the programs in the package. I would have liked to see Google integrate the visuals better for Photoshop somehow, but I may just be nitpicking.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A few weeks ago I took a photo at sundown of the Chicago skyline from just north of the city right on Lake Michigan. The original had a wonderful mix of purples and oranges, combined with the white and yellow lights from the city itself. I thought this would be the perfect candidate for a black &amp;amp; white conversion, so it became my first test subject. I pulled it up in Photoshop and launched Silver Efex.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Silver Efex Pro 2&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#39;/images/silver-efex-full.jpg&#39; /&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Silver Efex Pro 2 Application Window.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was initially surprised by the number of pre-set filter options but as I quickly surfed through them my level of excitement diminished. I would say a good half of them were unusable with the default settings, but the other half presented some interesting options. I am more of a traditionalist when it comes to editing so I shy away from super highly edited or stylized photos (which is also why I am starting to lose faith in the HDR-fest known as 500px.com). Im sure the filters I immediately dismissed could be adjusted to provide useable results since there is a large number of settings available. Also my sample size of trying three photos is woefully inadequate to establish a good sense of how the program can perform under different circumstances. On the bright-side I am very happy with how fine-grained the settings can get giving pixel-obsessed photographers a fresh new playground they can run wild in.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#39;/images/silver-options.jpg&#39; /&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Silver Efex Pro 2 Options Panel.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here is part of the options window for Silver Efex. The number of settings is truly impressive. You can adjust brightness by highlights, mid-tones, and shadows, there are multiple contrast options, structure, tonality, color filters, grain, sensitivity, the list goes on and on. I think I could spend a month or two learning just Silver Efex and not know everything available to me. A cursory search online and I found multiple resources for tutorials and guides to help you get the most out of the software, so documentation and help are certainly not lacking.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Color Efex Pro 4&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#39;/images/color-efex.jpg&#39; /&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Color Efex Pro 4 Application Window.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Color Efex Pro 4 was extremely similar to Silver Efex so I am not going to try not to repeat myself. Some great options right out of the box, but some looked over the top and silly (my opinion of a lot of Instagram photos as well). Again, the options are fantastic and you can tweak a photo to your hearts desire. Before I took the photo I used with Silver Efex, I snapped this one of a man just enjoying the late afternoon on Lake Michigan. The original photo itself was a bit lack luster. I loved the composition, but the colors were washed out and it just felt dull compared to how wonderful it looked from behind the lens. Color Efex let me bring out the sky and lake a little more and gave the image a little more punch. It&#39;s not an award winner by any means, but I am pleased that I was able to use the software to enhance an otherwise throw-away photo and make it something at the very least I can enjoy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The options for Color Efex are just as robust as Silver Efex. They do change depending on which filter you have selected, but again the options are extremely fine-grained giving you almost limitless flexibility for color-balancing and color-adjustments.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Sharpener Pro and Dfine 2&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I haven&#39;t had the chance to play around with either of these yet, but I am looking forward to running them through their paces before my trial runs out. Sharpener Pro claims to &#39;bring out hidden details consistently&#39;, while Dfine is a noise reduction program &#39;tailored to your camera&#39;. I am naturally skeptical but very open-minded, so I will share my thoughts when I take a deeper dive into the other half of the collection.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Initial Impression&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Overall I am very pleased with the Nik Collection so far, and when I have a bit more spending cash will plop down the $149 to purchase the entire suite. Google seems to have hit a sweet spot where out of the box you can get some great results without much fiddling, yet the rabbit hole is there so more advanced users can dive down and explore as much as they want. I wish I had more than 15 days for the demo, but even just using it for two weeks I feel that $149 is a good price for what you get. When I make the purchase and learn more I will be sharing more thoughts, so be sure to stay tuned.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://www.gorilla-studios.com/2013/08/11/schooner-lynx</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Aug 2013 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <author>chris@gorilla-studios.com (Chris Peak)</author>
      <guid>http://www.gorilla-studios.com/2013/08/11/schooner-lynx</guid>
      <description>&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#39;/images/lynx.jpg&#39; /&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;The schooner Lynx on Lake Michigan.&lt;span class=&#39;alt&#39;&gt;1/6000, f/5.6, ISO100&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After posting shots from my visit to the Tall Ships exhibit at Navy Pier last week I was contacted by the Captain of the Privateer Lynx regarding the photo I took of it rounding the Chicago Harbor Light in the rain. She is a schooner from New Hampshire that was constructed by Rockport Marine in Rockport Maine and launched on July 28th, 2001. Here is a another photo of this beautiful ship out on Lake Michigan. For more information please visit the ship&#39;s website at &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.privateerlynx.com/&quot;&gt;www.privateerlynx.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; 
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Parade Of Sails</title>
      <link>http://www.gorilla-studios.com/2013/08/07/parade-of-sails</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Aug 2013 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <author>chris@gorilla-studios.com (Chris Peak)</author>
      <guid>http://www.gorilla-studios.com/2013/08/07/parade-of-sails</guid>
      <description>&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#39;/images/rainy-sails.jpg&#39; /&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;The Parade Of Sail encounters a sudden downpour, from Navy Pier Chicago.&lt;span class=&#39;alt&#39;&gt;1/320, f/5.6, ISO100&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A sudden downpour came in during the parade of sails in Chicago, but that didn&#39;t ruin our day. More photos to come.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update:&lt;/strong&gt; I was contacted by the Captain of this beautiful ship and learned she is the Privateer Lynx from New Hampshire. Upon further investigation the ship on her port side is the Madeline, and the ship dissapearing behind the lighthouse is the Friends Good Will.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Photo Of The Month</title>
      <link>http://www.gorilla-studios.com/2013/08/01/photo-of-the-month</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2013 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <author>chris@gorilla-studios.com (Chris Peak)</author>
      <guid>http://www.gorilla-studios.com/2013/08/01/photo-of-the-month</guid>
      <description>&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/pod/200_full.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;No straight lines, building in Chicago&quot;/&gt;
  &lt;figcaption class=&#39;vertical&#39;&gt;July&#39;s photo of the month - an apartment building&#39;s strange angles, Chicago.&lt;span class=&#39;alt&#39;&gt;1/200th, f/4, ISO200&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My favorite shot this month was certainly a departure from what I normally like. This was taken on a lunch break while walking around soaking up some sun. I snapped this photo of an apartment building on Adams St. and instantly noticed that from that particular angle no lines were straight up and down. The brick columns were askew, the street lights att odd angles, all creating a strange scene guiding your attention all over the place. I normally like all my photos at perfect 90 degree angles and try my best to correct for the Keystone Effect when shooting skyscrapers (very common living in Chicago) so to say this was outside of my comfort zone is a bit of an understatement.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>London Travelogue</title>
      <link>http://www.gorilla-studios.com/2013/07/21/london</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Jul 2013 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <author>chris@gorilla-studios.com (Chris Peak)</author>
      <guid>http://www.gorilla-studios.com/2013/07/21/london</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Back in May I was lucky enough to fly out to London to attend the Future of Web Design conference and while I was there I had some free time to explore with my camera. I flew out of Chicago on Friday afternoon, arriving very early on Saturday morning. I was delighted to find that after an eight hour flight it was a breeze figuring out my way into the city. I dropped my luggage off at the hotel because I couldn&#39;t check in until later, took my camera gear and headed out. Finding your way around is pretty tricky because roads in London change names every few blocks, thankfully I am pretty good at directions and figured out my way with only a few hiccups. An unplanned nap at Starbucks recharged my batteries (many thanks to the staff for letting me rest!), and I found my way down to the Tower of London and Tower Bridge. I scouted out both sides of the river and just soaked in the scenery for at least an hour or two waiting for the sun to start going down before taking photos.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/london-travelogue/tower-bridge.jpg&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;A rainy sunset at Tower Bridge, London&lt;span&gt;5&quot;, f/22, ISO100&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are two beautiful parks on either side of the river, so I was torn on which to shoot from. This first shot was a 30 second exposure at f/16 with an ND filter, taken on the north side of the Thames with the Tower of London just behind my back. I was hoping to get more lights and have the river a bit more glassy, but the weather was getting pretty poor and a few shots after this it started dumping rain and blowing wind pretty hard. My umbrella lasted a few minutes so I scrambled to pack my gear and seek shelter.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/london-travelogue/bishopsgate-a10.jpg&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;After the rain, Bishopsgate Road, London&lt;span&gt;5&quot;, f/13, ISO100&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After watching it rain for ten minutes under the base of the bridge a Policeman shooed us away since the park was closing so I ran for the nearest tube station. I was completely soaked but my gear was in good shape - my Kata bag came with a rain cover which kept everything nice and dry. I wish I could say the same about me. Once the storm front rolled through I made my way up Bishopsgate Road towards my hotel. I snapped another long exposure just to capture the vibrancy and color of the city after the rain.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/london-travelogue/leddenhall-market.jpg&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Leadenhall Market, Bishopsgate Road, London&lt;span&gt;0.5s, f/6.3, ISO200&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While walking back to the hotel I stumbled across Leadenhall Market which is a beautiful open-air market filled with small shops specializing in wine, cheese, chocolate and more. I stopped a few more times over the weekend but unfortunately it was closed every time. I took some shots Saturday night before retiring back to the hotel but this particular photo was taken the next morning. It was a bit difficult balancing the sunlight from the skylights and the lamps overhead, but a half-second exposure at f/6.3, ISO 200 seemed to do the trick. I loved the feel of the shops with all the flags overhead and the cobblestone walkway and the skylights overhead, I just wish I could have seen it full of people.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/london-travelogue/westminster.jpg&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Westminster Abbey, London&lt;span&gt;1/200th, f/10, ISO200&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sunday morning after stopping at Leadenhall Market I made my way by tube down to Westminster and Buckingham Palace. I was surprised at how densely packed the tourists were clustered around each of the landmarks. Being from Chicago and always being slightly annoyed by them I tried my best to stay away from the crowds. I wanted photos that were distinctly my own, and not the typical tourist shots I have seen a million times before. The morning was gloomy to say the least, but thats not always bad when it comes to photography. I circled Westminster Abbey once looking at the beautiful architecture before deciding where to shoot from. There was a small park adjacent to the main bell towers that everyone seemed to be ignoring. Making my way over I took this photo, which I didn&#39;t have a lot of hope fore since it was so flat in color. It wasn&#39;t until I converted it to black and white that the contrast made it really pop.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/london-travelogue/westminster-doors.jpg&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;figcaption class=&#39;vertical&#39;&gt;Westminster Abbey architectural details, London&lt;span&gt;1/90th, f/8, ISO100&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I could probably spend a week just shooting the Abbey itself but I only had 2 days to cover as much of the city as I could. Before leaving I wanted to get at least some of the stunning details of Westminster itself. Here is a shot from the back of the Abbey, the entire building is covered in ornate decoration, this was above one of the back entrances. The main statue is probably four feet tall, the rows of figures above it maybe ten inches each. I can only imagine how long it took to craft just this entrance alone, let alone the entire building.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/london-travelogue/guard.jpg&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;figcaption class=&#39;vertical&#39;&gt;A palace guard marching down Birdcage Walk near Buckingham Palace&lt;span&gt;1/90th, f/5.6, ISO200&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After the Abbey I walked over to Buckingham Palace which was a tourist nightmare. I snapped a few photos but was disappointed that the palace guards were probably 50 yards behind the wrought iron gates so we couldn&#39;t get close. I had read that you could get close and personal with them at the Palace of St. James but I couldn&#39;t find them. A walk around Hyde Park and back around I heard marching music and a lot of commotion headed my way. I headed in the direction of the music and was pleasantly surprised to come across a small parade. A large contingent of Palace Guards in their bearskin helmets came marching by followed closely by a large number of thoroughly british gentlemen in bowler hats, three-piece suits, and black umbrellas. If I had seen it on TV my first thought is that it was some Monty Python sketch, but sure enough, there they were. Im still not sure what the parade was about and for some reason it didn&#39;t occur to me to ask anyone. I liked this exposure because while playing around with the settings as they walked by, I slowed the shutter down just a hair to capture some motion blur. The guards arms are starting to blur and there is a hair of movement on his medals, but his head was steady. What a fun sight it was.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/london-travelogue/elizabeth-tower.jpg&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;figcaption class=&#39;vertical&#39;&gt;A double decker passes by Elizabeth Tower, London&lt;span&gt;0.5&quot;, f/20, ISO100&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Monday was spent at the conference, but afterwards I made my way back to Westminster. My goal that night was to shoot the London Eye and Elizabeth Tower - most people incorrectly call &#39;Big Ben&#39;, which is the name of the bell inside the tower itself. Like I said before I try not to take typical tourst photos, but I did want to catch a double decker bus at some point. Monday evening was the best weather I had seen since arriving, the sun was starting to sink, basking the tower in beautiful golds and purples, making for some elegant looking shots. I was taking some longer exposures along the Victoria Embankment when a big red bus came rumbling down the street. I snapped this one just as it went by, one of my favorites from the trip. The tower is framed nicely with the Union Jack fluttering to its side, the double decker bus is just recognizable as it streaks by.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/london-travelogue/bagpiper.jpg&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;A scottish solider plays the bagpipes on Westminster Bridge over the river Thames&lt;span&gt;1/60th, f/4.5, ISO100&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The sun sank lower into the sky so I made my way over to the bridge to set up for another angle. I was delighted to find a Scottish Bagpiper playing for donations, the note in his case saying he was a former soldier asking for 1 pound if you take photos. I snapped some photos and watched him play, then flipped him a 2 pound coin and thanked him.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/london-travelogue/elizabeth-tower-2.jpg&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Traffic streaks over Westminster Bridge by Elizabeth Tower, London&lt;span&gt;8&quot;, f/18, ISO100&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As golden hour set in a ton of photographers started setting up along the bridge over the Thames, all pointed at the tower. I was mildly disappointed to find that the closest corner of the building didn&#39;t have any lights on, creating a very large dark section. Beggars can&#39;t be choosers so I kept shooting, capturing this photo. Timing was key here as traffic wasn&#39;t that heavy - I had to time my exposures to start after the stoplight turned green allowing the backed up traffic to move towards me instead of sitting and waiting. I took a number of photos from this vantage point, but I picked this one because of the reflection from a bus created an interesting set of light trails on the left side of the frame. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/london-travelogue/london-eye.jpg&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Sunset at the London Eye on the Thames River&lt;span&gt;25&quot;, f/20, ISO100&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I always say when a group of photographers are looking one way, always at least take a look behind them to see what they are missing, and sure enough thats what I did to capture my favorite image of the trip. Turning around I found the disappearing sun casting a deep blue and purple sky over the Thames river and London Eye. A 30 second exposure blurred out boat traffic on the river and grabbed just enough motion on the ferris wheel. The hotel to the right of the Eye had illuminations that changed colors every minute or so, cycling between blues, yellows, purples, and greens, all adding to the mixture of colors in this scene. The fine details of the exposure are lost here on the screen, but I can&#39;t wait to see this one in large format print soon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Overall the few days I had to explore London went as well as they could have. I got some beautiful shots despite the weather and can&#39;t wait for my next trip out. I may post another travelogue, but if you want to see some more shots from the trip, check out my &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/media/set/?set=a.197839947031736.1073741833.175762829239448&amp;type=3&quot;&gt;Facebook gallery&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New England Gallery</title>
      <link>http://www.gorilla-studios.com/2013/07/07/new-england</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Jul 2013 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <author>chris@gorilla-studios.com (Chris Peak)</author>
      <guid>http://www.gorilla-studios.com/2013/07/07/new-england</guid>
      <description>&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#39;/images/new-england/newport-sundown.jpg&#39; /&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Newport Bridge over Narragansett Bay, Newport RI&lt;span&gt;1/200th, f/5.0, ISO400&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here is a &lt;a href=&quot;/new-england.html&quot;&gt;collection of photographs from New England&lt;/a&gt; taken in and around Mystic, CT and Newport, RI. I absolutely love New England, and try to visit every year. Enjoy some of my personal shots from my last few trips.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Photo Of The Month</title>
      <link>http://www.gorilla-studios.com/2013/07/01/photo-of-the-month</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2013 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <author>chris@gorilla-studios.com (Chris Peak)</author>
      <guid>http://www.gorilla-studios.com/2013/07/01/photo-of-the-month</guid>
      <description>&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/pod/161_full.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Line cook shucking oysters, Anchor and Hope, San Francisco&quot;/&gt;
  &lt;figcaption class=&#39;vertical&#39;&gt;A line chef shucks oysters at Anchor &amp;amp; Hope Restaurant, San Francisco&lt;span&gt;1/80th, f/5, ISO400&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My personal favorite from June was taken while I was out in California for a few days on a business trip. We had stopped into Anchor &amp;amp; Hope in downtown San Francisco, an amazing seafood restaurant. While waiting for lunch to be served a line cook was shucking oysters behind the main counter. The sun shone in through the skylights and lit him like a spotlight. I wish I had more time to capture the shot, or maybe a wider lens, but I still enjoyed how it came out. I love the decor - with the fun painted fish on the walls and the interesting lamps jutting out, the counter littered with dishes, everything combined to create a visually interesting scene.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Flying Isn't All That Bad</title>
      <link>http://www.gorilla-studios.com/2013/06/12/flying-not-all-bad</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Jun 2013 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <author>chris@gorilla-studios.com (Chris Peak)</author>
      <guid>http://www.gorilla-studios.com/2013/06/12/flying-not-all-bad</guid>
      <description>&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#39;/images/flying.jpg&#39; /&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;The sunset and approaching storm front over Iowa&lt;span&gt;1/30th, f/3.5, ISO400&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Despite a detour to Iowa for an hour or so and wave off on final approach both due to a massive storm over Chicago, I couldn&#39;t complain about my view at sunset.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hello San Francisco</title>
      <link>http://www.gorilla-studios.com/2013/06/11/hello-san-fran</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Jun 2013 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <author>chris@gorilla-studios.com (Chris Peak)</author>
      <guid>http://www.gorilla-studios.com/2013/06/11/hello-san-fran</guid>
      <description>&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#39;/images/bay-bridge.jpg&#39; /&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;A panorama of the San Fransisco Bay, underneath the Bay Bridge&lt;span&gt;1/640th, f/14, ISO400&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hello San Francisco! I am in town for a quick business trip and was able to sneak down to the bay for a few minutes today. While I am only here for essentially a few hours I can say it is a beautiful city and I would love to come back and take some time with my camera. Unfortunately I won&#39;t be able to head up to the Golden Gate Bridge which is on my photography bucket-list. I snapped this quick panorama of the Bay Bridge on the east side of the city after a fantastic lunch at &lt;a href=&quot;http://anchorandhopesf.com&quot;&gt;Anchor &amp;amp; Hope&lt;/a&gt; which I highly recommend.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Photo Of The Month</title>
      <link>http://www.gorilla-studios.com/2013/06/09/photo-of-the-month</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Jun 2013 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <author>chris@gorilla-studios.com (Chris Peak)</author>
      <guid>http://www.gorilla-studios.com/2013/06/09/photo-of-the-month</guid>
      <description>&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#39;/images/pod/150_full.jpg&#39; /&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;The Rialto Theatre, Joliet, IL&lt;span&gt;1/320th, f/8, ISO100&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My favorite photo taken in May has to be this black and white I took of the Rialto Theatre in Joliet, IL. My brother-in-law was getting married and asked me to take photos of the rehearsal and morning of, which I was more than happy to do. The Rialto is a grand old theatre in the heart of downtown and was a beautiful location to get married. I arrived a little early and decided to grab a few photos of the marquee and signage just to be thorough. During my edits I wasn&#39;t exactly thrilled with the outside shots, but when I converted this photo to black and white it really popped. The dark blue sky with a scattering of clouds provide great contrast next along with the bright white &#39;Rialto&#39; lettering. It just proves that even if you aren&#39;t excited when you make the exposure, always be open to pleasant surprises.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>130 Years Of The Brooklyn Bridge</title>
      <link>http://www.gorilla-studios.com/2013/05/26/brooklyn-bridge</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 May 2013 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <author>chris@gorilla-studios.com (Chris Peak)</author>
      <guid>http://www.gorilla-studios.com/2013/05/26/brooklyn-bridge</guid>
      <description>&lt;img src=&#39;/images/brooklyn-bridge.jpg&#39; /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://ny.curbed.com/archives/2013/05/22/130_years_of_brooklyn_bridge_photos_decade_by_decade.php&quot;&gt;Curbed.com posted a gallery&lt;/a&gt; of one of my favorite architectural icons, The Brooklyn Bridge. Opened in 1883, the gallery has some fantastic photos decade by decade up to the 2000&#39;s. Side note, if you are looking for a good book, check out &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.amazon.com/The-Great-Bridge-Building-Brooklyn/dp/1451683235/ref=sr_1_1?ie=UTF8&amp;qid=1369620166&amp;sr=8-1&amp;keywords=the+great+bridge&quot;The Great Bridge&quot;&gt;The Great Bridge&lt;/a&gt; by David McCullough, which coincidentally I just finished - it&#39;s a great read.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tower Bridge</title>
      <link>http://www.gorilla-studios.com/2013/05/11/tower-bridge</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 May 2013 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <author>chris@gorilla-studios.com (Chris Peak)</author>
      <guid>http://www.gorilla-studios.com/2013/05/11/tower-bridge</guid>
      <description>&lt;img src=&#39;/images/tower-bridge.jpg&#39; /&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gorilla Studios Heads To London</title>
      <link>http://www.gorilla-studios.com/2013/05/10/london</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 May 2013 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <author>chris@gorilla-studios.com (Chris Peak)</author>
      <guid>http://www.gorilla-studios.com/2013/05/10/london</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In just a few hours I&#39;ll be hopping a plane and headed to London for the &lt;a href=&#39;http://futureofwebdesign.com/london-2013/&#39;&gt;Future of Web Design Conference&lt;/a&gt;. I will be in England for a week, coming back next Thursday, so there won&#39;t be many updates on the site, but keep an eye on my &lt;a href=&#39;http://twitter.com/gorilla_studios/&#39;&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#39;http://gorilla-studios.tumblr.com&#39;&gt;Tumblr&lt;/a&gt; feeds for quick updates and photos if I have time. I plan on taking most of of my free time and shooting as much as I can, sleep be damned. See you next week!&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Concert Photography Basics</title>
      <link>http://www.gorilla-studios.com/2013/05/07/concert-photography</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 May 2013 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <author>chris@gorilla-studios.com (Chris Peak)</author>
      <guid>http://www.gorilla-studios.com/2013/05/07/concert-photography</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I love when I get the chance to photograph bands in action, so here&#39;s a few things I have learned to keep in mind if you want to be successful in music photography.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;1. Know your gear&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This may seem obvious, but know your gear. &lt;i&gt;Really know your gear&lt;/i&gt;. If you are fiddling with AF settings or looking at an exposure I guarantee you are going to miss shots. The faster you are at switching settings on the fly the more shots you are going to make. Good bands are high energy and you have to keep up - it&#39;s your job to make them look awesome and you can&#39;t do that if your stuck messing with your camera. Take time to really learn your Auto-Focus system. Can you change AF points quickly without taking the camera away from your face? Have you played around with your cameras AF shortcuts? These are things you need to know if you want to keep up with an energetic front-man who is diving all over the stage.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Get your exposure dialed in with a few shots then focus on the show. I check exposure every now and then if I feel the lighting may have changed enough to impact exposure, but on the whole I am not checking my shots throughout a set. This comes from years of learning my camera and being able to change most functions blind-folded.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/images/cadillac-bass.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;The Cadillac Casanovas rocking the Arcada in St. Charles&quot;/&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;2. Don&#39;t Machine Gun It&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Keep calm, don&#39;t run and gun it. I like to really listen to the music - when you start feeling the beat you can start to predict what some of the band members are going to do. Is the drummer building up tension? Is the bassist going to do some acrobatic trick at the crescendo? Feeling the music, staying cool, and taking your time will lead to some great photographs. If you have the chance talk to the band beforehand, get a feel for what kind of show they like to put on. Good bands love to show off for us photographers, a lot of times you&#39;ll get guys hamming it up for the camera, be ready for it, they don&#39;t wait for you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;3. Keep Track Of Your Shots&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Be sure to get every band member if possible, don&#39;t spend time on the lead singer or one person in particular. Finishing a set with 1000 photos of the lead singer and 5 of the drummer is not going to look good when you are trying to show your results to them, or other bands. Variety is key.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;4. Composition&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is another skill that is honed over time. Watch your composition like a hawk. Don&#39;t clip the guitarists headstock. Make sure the mic isn&#39;t covering too much of a singers face. Keep an eye on the background lights. Know your surroundings. It&#39;s little details that can make or break a photo.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&#39;/images/everly-hillbillies.jpg&#39; alt=&#39;The Everly Hillbillies at the Arcada Theatre in St. Charles&#39; /&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;5. Prepare&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Get to know the band your shooting, if at all possible. I like talking to them before a show to get to know their personalities. Get their set list and keep it in the back of your head so you know when their time is almost up. A lot of bands will kick it up a notch on the last song, so be ready.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Save yourself the headache and avoid any future hearing loss problems by getting a nice set of earplugs. If you love shooting shows you are hopefully going to do it a lot, and keep doing it. Protect your hearing and wear earplugs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Also Be sure to stretch before the show and if you can drink plenty of water during. Shooting concerts can be very physically demanding, so make sure you take care of yourself first. When I shoot shows I am stretching, bending, reaching, and crouching to get shots, and if I don&#39;t take time before the show to get limber then I pay for it the next day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Last but not least, be ready and able to switch out gear on the fly. Its going to be dark, its going to be loud, and its going to be hectic. This is one reason I HATE SD Cards with a passion, they are very easy to drop or mishandle.  Practice changing lenses and memory cards quickly and cleanly. Know where your gear is and have it ready.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Above all else, have fun!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Photo Of The Month</title>
      <link>http://www.gorilla-studios.com/2013/05/05/photo-of-the-month</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 May 2013 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <author>chris@gorilla-studios.com (Chris Peak)</author>
      <guid>http://www.gorilla-studios.com/2013/05/05/photo-of-the-month</guid>
      <description>&lt;img src=&quot;/images/pod/118_full.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Flooding at Island Park in Geneva, IL&quot;/&gt;
&lt;p&gt;April&#39;s photo of the month was taken in the flood waters at Island Park in Geneva, IL. After the storms rolled through in the middle of the month most of the major rivers and creeks flooded severely. Since travel was hazardous I waited for the initial surge to subside before exploring - even a week later a lot of areas were still underwater. Island Park is located on the Fox River in downtown Geneva, and most of the inside of the park was still under a foot or two of water as I sloshed my way through. Very carefully I made my way into the park and setup my tripod almost dead center looking north back towards downtown which you can see in the top left. Since it was close to noon with a bright blue sky the park was very well lit. I stacked three ND filters and closed the aperture down to f/22. That combination allowed me to open the shutter for around 4 seconds, smoothing out the water. I found that unless I used my hands as a hood the first ND filter would reflect the branding from the front of the lens back into the exposure.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;Water and camera gear don&#39;t mix, so needless to say when you are shooting in or around water be extremely careful. I didn&#39;t have any issues with gear, the heart-attack of the day came from nature itself. It appeared some large fish were trapped inside of the park as the waters had receded enough to cut off access to the river, but was still deep enough for them to swim and every so often flopping out of the water. While taking photos I was in the middle of one shot when a large fish brushed my leg, jumped up out of the water, and then swam off very quickly. To be honest I let out a choice word or two and tried to get pulse back down to double digits. Be careful out there!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Quick Tip</title>
      <link>http://www.gorilla-studios.com/2013/04/20/cable-organization</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Apr 2013 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <author>chris@gorilla-studios.com (Chris Peak)</author>
      <guid>http://www.gorilla-studios.com/2013/04/20/cable-organization</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Here&#39;s a quick and free tip for cable organization - take those toilet paper tubes that you usually throw away and use them to keep your camera bag cables from tangling up. I always carry a USB sync cable and a wired shutter release remote in my bag and they used to get tangled up with each other or I would have to fidget with twist ties. Now I simply wind the cable on itself and slip it into the tube, and toss it into the bag.  Once the tubes get a little folded and worn they actually flatten a bit and hug the cables even more. Simple.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/images/toilet-paper-tubes.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Using toilet paper tubes as cable organizers&quot;/&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chicago Lakefront</title>
      <link>http://www.gorilla-studios.com/2013/04/12/chicago-lakefront</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Apr 2013 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <author>chris@gorilla-studios.com (Chris Peak)</author>
      <guid>http://www.gorilla-studios.com/2013/04/12/chicago-lakefront</guid>
      <description>&lt;img src=&quot;/images/chicago-lakefront.jpg&quot; /&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Geneva Sundown</title>
      <link>http://www.gorilla-studios.com/2013/04/09/geneva-sundown</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Apr 2013 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <author>chris@gorilla-studios.com (Chris Peak)</author>
      <guid>http://www.gorilla-studios.com/2013/04/09/geneva-sundown</guid>
      <description>&lt;img src=&quot;/images/geneva-sundown.jpg&quot; /&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Photo Of The Month</title>
      <link>http://www.gorilla-studios.com/2013/04/01/photo-of-the-month</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2013 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <author>chris@gorilla-studios.com (Chris Peak)</author>
      <guid>http://www.gorilla-studios.com/2013/04/01/photo-of-the-month</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;My favorite photo for March has to be a very quick shot from Union Station in Chicago. I was a little early for my train so I decided to go up to one of the balconies overlooking the main hall. I had intended to slow my shutter down enough to capture some of the motion from everyone hurrying in and out of the hall but I did not have my tripod. Attempts to use the railing while shooting around 1/10th or 1/8th were unsuccessful, but this shot at f/4.5, ISO 100 for 1/20th was sharp and had no camera shake. Overall I love the photo - in particular the one woman in the foreground seems to stand out to me. I was interrupted when a bride and her photographers came up to the balcony for some shots, however I was more than happy to get out of their way.  I will eventually go back with my tripod and get some long exposures but for now I am happy with this one.&lt;/p&gt;  
&lt;img src=&quot;/images/pod/81_full.jpg&quot; /&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Photo Of The Month</title>
      <link>http://www.gorilla-studios.com/2013/03/02/photo-of-the-month</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Mar 2013 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
      <author>chris@gorilla-studios.com (Chris Peak)</author>
      <guid>http://www.gorilla-studios.com/2013/03/02/photo-of-the-month</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Two months down, still going strong. This month I spent a lot of time out hiking through various forest preserves in the area so my favorite photo this month came from Waterfall Glen Forest Preserve in Darien, IL. I found these waterfalls along a small creek that winds its way through the southern section of the park. A graduated ND filter kept a balanced exposure between the sky and foreground, and a circular polarizer filter cut back reflections from the water to reveal all the rocks and little details underneath. Using both of these also allowed me to extend my exposures up to 2 seconds. I plan on going back in the summer to get one from in the water, but for now its just a bit too cold.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/images/pom_february.jpg&quot; /&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Photo 365 FAQ</title>
      <link>http://www.gorilla-studios.com/2013/02/22/photo-365-faq</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Feb 2013 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
      <author>chris@gorilla-studios.com (Chris Peak)</author>
      <guid>http://www.gorilla-studios.com/2013/02/22/photo-365-faq</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I am 52 days into my Photo365 challenge and have already gotten a few people asking me almost the same questions about the project, so I thought I would explain a little bit more about why I am doing this exercise and what my guidelines are.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Why?&lt;/strong&gt; - A number of reasons, some of which are: Staying sharp by taking at least one photo every day, keeping my camera on me at almost all times (I &lt;i&gt;hate&lt;/i&gt; that feeling when I wish I had it), to push myself to try different styles I normally wouldn&#39;t shoot, and also it acts as a photo diary for the year.  Im looking forward to having all 365 in a gallery, I have kicked around ideas about what to do with the final set, but more on that later in the year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Do you really take and post one photo a day?&lt;/strong&gt; - I try to take at the very least one photo per day, but also limit myself to no more than 36 if its not a photo walk or specific shoot. The main point of the limit is so I don&#39;t keep second guessing or trying the same shot over again. I want to see the bad shots as well as the good.  I try to post the photo on the same day, but if I have to wait until morning I am okay with that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How much time per day?&lt;/strong&gt; - Like I said I usually limit myself to a handful of shots, the average seems to be about 5-10 per day. I also limit myself to three minutes of photoshop touchup for any given photo.  I have a timer set and when beeps, thats it. I try to get the best photo I can straight from the camera - however I have been playing around with some alternate edits I usually don&#39;t try like half-saturation and stylized filters.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What have you learned so far?&lt;/strong&gt; - I have noticed that I am looking around for photo opportunities a lot more than I used to. It was difficult getting into the habit of bringing my SLR everywhere, but my Black Rapid strap really helps with that - I just sling it over my shoulder and head out. I like to see the progress I have made, and I also like seeing the good shots contrasted with some of the bad. I can see days where I just wasn&#39;t feeling very creative, and then others where I wish I could have posted a lot more.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/images/pod/53_full.jpg&quot; /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here is the photo from today, February 22nd.  I simply walked a few blocks out of my way after work and took a handful of shots as I went. I was quite surprised at how this one came out. Allowing myself three minutes for editing I spent most of the time adjusting the highlights &amp;amp; color temp, and staying true to the limit I didn&#39;t get a chance to straighten the composition.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Remember to keep shooting and have fun.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>From The Archives</title>
      <link>http://www.gorilla-studios.com/2013/02/05/from-the-archives</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Feb 2013 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
      <author>chris@gorilla-studios.com (Chris Peak)</author>
      <guid>http://www.gorilla-studios.com/2013/02/05/from-the-archives</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I spent the weekend going over my backups and consolidating over ten years worth of photos into one complete archive. I made the decision when I got my first camera to keep everything so when I am back at home after a shoot I can go over what worked and what didn&#39;t, just like film. This strategy is starting to pay dividends in full, because now I have a ten year archive to sort through and see how far I have come in my craft. I wanted to share one of a handful of shots I took with my original Canon Powershot S200 that re-ignited my passion for photography.&lt;/p&gt;  
&lt;img src=&quot;/images/archer.jpg&quot; /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Taken on August 3rd, 2003 in downtown Chicago on one of my first photo walks. I vaguely recall trying very hard to capture some long night-time exposures with a point and shoot, and looking back on the roll I didn&#39;t do too bad considering the limitations of the camera. This was from the tail end of the walk - &lt;i&gt;The Spearman&lt;/i&gt; is a large bronze statue from 1928, one of two guardians (the other being &lt;i&gt;The Bowman&lt;/i&gt;) standing watch at Congress &amp;amp; Michigan Ave in the loop.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Photo Of The Month</title>
      <link>http://www.gorilla-studios.com/2013/02/01/photo-of-the-month</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Feb 2013 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
      <author>chris@gorilla-studios.com (Chris Peak)</author>
      <guid>http://www.gorilla-studios.com/2013/02/01/photo-of-the-month</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;One month into the Photo365 challenge and I feel it has been going very well so far. The goal when I started wasn&#39;t to produce portfolio-worthy images every day - it was mainly to keep practicing my craft while pushing myself to step outside my comfort zone and shoot things I normally wouldn&#39;t. Some days were harder than others, but overall it has been thoroughly enjoyable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A few shots stand out more than others, but the one that caught the most attention was actually completely random.  On January 24th I had to walk from one client to another in the middle of a rather blustery Chicago snowstorm.  I had a vague idea of how to get from A to B, but didn&#39;t have a specific route in mind. I just started walking and snapping pictures as I went. A few turns in the general direction I found myself in front of a row of very interesting looking townhomes in the River North neighborhood. Thankfully nobody was parked in front so I took a quick photo and kept walking. &lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;img src=&quot;/images/pom_january.jpg&quot; /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The image was captured at f9.5 at 1/90, ISO 100. I intentionally kept my shutter speed down to catch the snow swirling in front of the lens. I was not sure of exactly how it would show up after processing, but I love how it turned out. I&#39;m undecided if this one will make it to print or portfolio, but it looks beautiful as a desktop image on my Cinema Display. One month down, eleven to go!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Flight</title>
      <link>http://www.gorilla-studios.com/2013/01/20/flight</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Jan 2013 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
      <author>chris@gorilla-studios.com (Chris Peak)</author>
      <guid>http://www.gorilla-studios.com/2013/01/20/flight</guid>
      <description>&lt;img src=&quot;/images/flight.jpg&quot; /&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Experiment</title>
      <link>http://www.gorilla-studios.com/2013/01/14/experiment</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Jan 2013 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
      <author>chris@gorilla-studios.com (Chris Peak)</author>
      <guid>http://www.gorilla-studios.com/2013/01/14/experiment</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I hear a lot of less-experienced photographers bemoaning the fact that they don&#39;t have a particular lens, or their camera &#39;isn&#39;t good enough&#39;, and it always frustrates me. You don&#39;t need the latest 20+ Megapixel camera to produce great images. Keep practicing with the gear you have, and more importantly push yourself and try something you&#39;ve never done before. For my Photo 365 project I decided to try to catch a droplet splashing out of water but I don&#39;t have a ring flash or enclosed soft-box - heck my tripod was in the trunk of my car with my wife at work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Necessity is the mother of invention so I grabbed some things in the kitchen and setup a mini-studio. I used a glass of water, an eye dropper, a lamp as a secondary light, my flash &amp;amp; sync cable, and ...a chopstick?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/images/experiment.jpg&quot; /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I set the camera up on a plastic tupperware container as a makeshift tripod and switched over to manual focus mode since nothing would be moving. Looking through the camera I couldn&#39;t tell if I was in focus on the center of the water&#39;s surface, so I dipped the chopstick in dead center and focus locked on that.  I grabbed my cable release in one hand and the eye dropper in the other and tried to sync the drop to the shutter.  At first I tried the built-in timer but couldn&#39;t get the droplet to hit at the right time, so I resorted to dropping multiple drops not too far apart and releasing the shutter during.  It only took me a few shots to get the timing down. About 10 minutes of setup and a few minutes of shooting and I captured this one:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/images/droplet.jpg&quot; /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Its not going to appear in any magazines thats for sure, but then again it was about 15 minutes with no additional equipment. No high-speed camera, no special lighting, just what I had in my camera bag and kitchen. &lt;i&gt;f&lt;/i&gt;/19, 1/200th, ISO 100. This was just an experiment, I like to tinker around. Next time I will probably distill the water first so its free of impurities, and I may try a larger container so I can get more of a horizontal shot. I only spent a few minutes tinkering around in the kitchen, but I already have a better understanding of macro-photography setups, and how I can improve next time.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Photo 365</title>
      <link>http://www.gorilla-studios.com/2013/01/13/photo-365</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Jan 2013 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
      <author>chris@gorilla-studios.com (Chris Peak)</author>
      <guid>http://www.gorilla-studios.com/2013/01/13/photo-365</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As previously mentioned, I have decided to participate in a Photo 365 Challenge.  I will be taking one photo a day for the entire 2013 calendar year, and posting them &lt;a href=&quot;/photo365.html&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; as well as my &lt;a href=&quot;http://gorilla-studios.tumblr.com&quot;&gt;Tumblr feed&lt;/a&gt;. I wanted to take this challenge so I would have my camera on me at all times, push myself as a photographer, and try some things I haven&#39;t done before. So far I am only 13 days in and already I am finding myself seeing things differently, looking for photos everywhere I go.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To make things a bit more challenging, I will limit myself to only a handfull of shots per day.  I have also turned off the automatic preview after each shot as a throwback to the old film days where you don&#39;t know your results until your in the dark-room. I&#39;ll make monthly posts about my progress, positive notes, frustrations,  etc..&lt;/p&gt; 
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Happy New Year</title>
      <link>http://www.gorilla-studios.com/2013/01/01/happy-new-year</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2013 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
      <author>chris@gorilla-studios.com (Chris Peak)</author>
      <guid>http://www.gorilla-studios.com/2013/01/01/happy-new-year</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Happy New Year from Gorilla-Studios!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since its January 1st and everyone under the sun is making resolutions, I&#39;ve decided to jump on the bandwagon. This year I am going to try to complete a Photo 365 Challenge (tip o&#39; the hat to &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.kandirich.com&quot;&gt;Kandi Rich&lt;/a&gt; for the inspiration).  If you want a project to push you all year be sure to checkout &lt;a href=&quot;http://content.photojojo.com/tips/7-new-year-projects/#more-32021&quot;&gt;Photojojo&#39;s 7 New Year Projects&lt;/a&gt; for some great inspiration if you&#39;re not quite up to a 365 day photo challenge. My other resolution is to post more often and keep working on the site. Last year was spent focusing on getting married and my new full-time job, so this year I am going to set aside time to grow my site and skills the best I can.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Heres to 2013!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Practice Swapping Lenses</title>
      <link>http://www.gorilla-studios.com/2012/12/30/practice-swapping-lenses</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Dec 2012 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
      <author>chris@gorilla-studios.com (Chris Peak)</author>
      <guid>http://www.gorilla-studios.com/2012/12/30/practice-swapping-lenses</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Any craftsman will practice his skills, working on them over and over. Any photographer worth their salt will practice not only taking photos, but working with their equipment as well. I have seen on many blogs posts talking about swapping lenses quickly, but they always say practice in favorable conditions in good light. Lets take practicing lens swapping a bit further.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was out yesterday walking through the snow,  getting used to my new Black Rapid Double Strap, keeping sharp with handling gear in windy cold conditions, and just enjoying the scenery when I decided to swap from my wide angle to a telephoto. Problem was I couldnt set my bag down because I was in the middle of a field in deep snow. &lt;i&gt;Here&#39;s the challenge:&lt;/i&gt; swap out your lens with out setting down any gear, then try to do it with gloves on. Try it in the dark with minmal light. Could you do it by feel alone? Whats it like handling your lenses and caps with your gloves on? Practice working in adverse conditions before you find yourself in them not knowing what to do.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Remember to keep practicing not only taking and composing photos, but working with your gear. The better you know it the faster you will be in the field when it counts.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Celestron Dry Run</title>
      <link>http://www.gorilla-studios.com/2012/12/22/celestron-dry-run</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Dec 2012 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
      <author>chris@gorilla-studios.com (Chris Peak)</author>
      <guid>http://www.gorilla-studios.com/2012/12/22/celestron-dry-run</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I finally took my recently acquired Celestron Ultima 11 Schmidt-Cass telescope out for a test run to get a feel for using it in the field. Everything setup easily and I got the moon in sight quickly, but I had some initial focusing problems. About a half hour of tinkering around and I finally got it in focus and was thoroughly impressed with the clarity. The Celestron has an 11&quot; mirror with a rough focal length of 2800mm. Using a 26mm Plossl eyepiece puts us at roughly 108x magnification (2800mm / 26mm). I couldn&#39;t help just gazing through the eyepiece for some time, getting used to tracking the moon manually (I still need to learn how to properly polar align the scope and use the auto tracking). Finally I pulled out my trusty EOS 10D and mounted it to the scope. I refocused and started shooting, right around 1/90th at ISO 200. I locked the mirror up and used a remote as to avoid shake, but the first round of photos were all soft. Im not sure if it was a mirror shake problem or the images were just plain out of focus. I had a hard time getting locked in with the telescopes focus knob, clearly its going to take some practice. Heres the &#39;best&#39; of the out of focus images from tonight:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/celestron_test.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That was shot at ISO 200 for 1/90th of a second with the mirror lock enabled. If I understand correctly it has a focal length of f/16. This image was also completely un-cropped - the telescope has so much power I cannot fit the moon into the frame all at once. To get full lunar images I either need to stitch multiple images together or purchase a telecompressor. It was a relatively clear night, but I did shoot with a lot of ambient light from the subdivision. I may take it out tomorrow for another shoot, stay tuned!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gorilla-Studios Looks To The Skies</title>
      <link>http://www.gorilla-studios.com/2012/12/02/gorilla-studios-looks-to-the-skies</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Dec 2012 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
      <author>chris@gorilla-studios.com (Chris Peak)</author>
      <guid>http://www.gorilla-studios.com/2012/12/02/gorilla-studios-looks-to-the-skies</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/celestron.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today I liberated my fathers Celestron Ultima 11&quot; Schmidt-Cass telescope which had been collecting dust for some time. I picked up an adapter for my Canon, so over the next few months I will be seriously exploring astrophotography.  I have previously used a low-grade Quantaray 600-1000mm scope for lunar photography, needless to say this is quite an upgrade - the Celestron has a focal distance of 2800mm (if I understand the specs correctly). I will keep posting my experiences and results soon.  Stay tuned.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Insure Your Gear</title>
      <link>http://www.gorilla-studios.com/2012/11/27/insure-your-gear</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Nov 2012 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
      <author>chris@gorilla-studios.com (Chris Peak)</author>
      <guid>http://www.gorilla-studios.com/2012/11/27/insure-your-gear</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Here&#39;s a great reason why to insure your gear before something bad happens. Ed Hetherington shared a story via &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.facebook.com/media/set/?set=a.10152269804305542.929748.117291240541&quot;&gt;his facebook page&lt;/a&gt; about how a lioness decided to get up close and personal with his EOS 5D MkII. While the camera did not survive, thankfully it looks like the lioness didn&#39;t suffer any injuries from her curiosity.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>5D MkII Price Drop</title>
      <link>http://www.gorilla-studios.com/2012/09/30/5D-MkII-Price-Drop</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Sep 2012 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <author>chris@gorilla-studios.com (Chris Peak)</author>
      <guid>http://www.gorilla-studios.com/2012/09/30/5D-MkII-Price-Drop</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.canonrumors.com/2012/09/big-canon-eos-5d-mark-ii-price-drop-coming/&quot;&gt;Canon Rumors&lt;/a&gt; reports that there is a big price drop coming on the Canon EOS 5D MkII. This is a great deal for someone looking into upgrade to a more capable body but cannot justify spending $3500 on the MkIII.  Just remember - the MkII is still a great camera, and a terrific bargain now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt; UPDATE &lt;/strong&gt; - &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.bhphotovideo.com/c/product/583953-REG/Canon_2764B003_EOS_5D_Mark_II.html&quot;&gt;B&amp;amp;H Photo&lt;/a&gt; has the body only on sale for $1799. This really makes me think long and hard about my next major purchase.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Quick Tip - Shooting The Moon</title>
      <link>http://www.gorilla-studios.com/2012/07/27/quick-tip-shooting-the-moon</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Jul 2012 21:41:26 -0500</pubDate>
      <author>chris@gorilla-studios.com (Chris Peak)</author>
      <guid>http://www.gorilla-studios.com/2012/07/27/quick-tip-shooting-the-moon</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;img_center&quot; src=&quot;/images/half_moon.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Half Moon shot on July 27th, 2012 with a Canon EOS 10D + Quantaray 600-1000mm&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here are two things you can do to give your astro and night photography a little boost.  First is to pair your cable release with the camera&#39;s &#39;Mirror Lock&#39; function. Simply go into your DSLR&#39;s custom functions and select Mirror Lock. By enabling this, when you press the shutter release the mirror swings up and out of the way locking into position and holding in place. You then have to press the button again to open the shutter and make the exposure. After the photo is taken the mirror swings back into place as normal. What this does is eliminate any shaking or movement involved when the mirror flips up.  Normally during the day time and during normal photos this movement does not matter, but when you are trying to keep the camera as steady as possible during a long exposure at night it makes a large difference.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Second is to use a UV/Haze filter. These filters cut down on UV light and haze that can impact image quality. Sometimes the difference isn&#39;t that great, but when I shot a before and after tonight I was impressed with what a cheap $20 UV filter did.  The moon was low in the sky when the shot was taken, increasing the amount of atmospheric haze to shoot through.  Both images were taken within a minute of each other, on my Canon 10D paired with a Quantaray 600-1000mm super telephoto, extended to 1000mm, &lt;i&gt;f&lt;/i&gt;/16 at 1/30th of a second, ISO 100. On the left the mirror was not locked and the filter was not on the lens. On the right the mirror-lock function is enabled and the filter is on. Without the mirror-lock the first image was shaken enough to impact the sharpness, and you can also see the clarity difference as well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/moon_example.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Unfiltered with no mirror lock vs. UV/Haze filter with Mirror Lock&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Photographers best tool - improvisation</title>
      <link>http://www.gorilla-studios.com/2012/07/24/a-photographers-best-tool-improvisation</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Jul 2012 19:23:21 -0500</pubDate>
      <author>chris@gorilla-studios.com (Chris Peak)</author>
      <guid>http://www.gorilla-studios.com/2012/07/24/a-photographers-best-tool-improvisation</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;One lesson I have learned in my years of shooting is that you should always be ready to improvise. It&#39;s a good idea to plan your shoots to get a good idea of what you want to accomplish but you always have to be ready to throw it out the window and get what you can.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I went out after work last Friday and decided to go down to Navy Pier and take some dusk shots of the Ferris Wheel and spinning swings. I wanted to catch them as the sun was going down and use a slower shutter speed to capture some motion. After taking a few test shots I was approached by a security guard and he told me firmly that they did not allow tripods during high traffic periods &#39;due to safety concerns&#39;. I was frustrated and voiced my displeasure since I was actually using it as a monopod, but rather than having a chat with the Chicago Police I decided to move along. Needless to say I was in a bad mood, but instead of just packing up and heading home I started walking up the lakefront. I knew there was a great park just north of Navy Pier with a beautiful view of the skyline and lots of boat activity, so I decided to try to see what I could get up there. Again I setup and started composing my shots, taking some test exposures and watching the sun sink farther and farther. Just as I started to feel good about everything a Chicago Police officer reported that the park was closing and ran everyone out. This was yet another opportunity to throw my hands up and pack it in. Thankfully I stayed cool and left the park and went down to the beach around the corner. After double-checking with the officer I found that it was open until 10 so I wouldn&#39;t have any problems. As the golden hour set in I started getting some great shots and all my frustrations just drifted away.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/chicago_skyline.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Chicago skyline at dusk&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This was the last shot before the sun finally went down, taken at 19mm &lt;i&gt;f&lt;/i&gt;/8 for 30 seconds. I would have missed this opportunity had I gotten angry and just headed home.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/flower_bug.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here is another great example. This photo was taken when I went out last summer looking for more Great Blue Herons that were nested near my house. I was walking along the Fox River looking at the tree line when the color of these flowers really caught my eye. I switched over to my 50mm macro lens and started photographing these bold flowers. I was just about to pack up when I noticed this bug on one flower, climbing the stamen. I would have totally missed this had I not had my eyes open.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Always be sure to have an idea of what you want to get before you even leave the house but keep your eyes and mind open to something completely different. Looking through my portfolio there are quite a few shots that were a complete surprise to me at the time. Whether its a scenery or lighting change, location change, equipment malfunction or whatever, one of the best tools you can have is being able to stay calm and get the shot that presents itself to you.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wolf Camera Blowout Sale</title>
      <link>http://www.gorilla-studios.com/2012/07/18/wolf-camera-blowout-sale</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Jul 2012 19:23:21 -0500</pubDate>
      <author>chris@gorilla-studios.com (Chris Peak)</author>
      <guid>http://www.gorilla-studios.com/2012/07/18/wolf-camera-blowout-sale</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It looks like Wolf Camera is filing for bankruptcy - again.  I stopped by my local store and found out they are closing &#39;probably half&#39; of their stores.  While they were never able to compete against online retailers in terms of cost, the customer service was always top notch.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&#39;m not sure exactly which and how many stores are closing, but the one in Batavia, IL is shutting down &#39;within the month&#39; and is currently having a huge blowout sale.  I picked up about $200 worth of filters for about $40 bucks today.  Most of their inventory is picked clean already, but if you know what you&#39;re looking for be sure to stop by.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Don't Worry</title>
      <link>http://www.gorilla-studios.com/2012/06/15/dont-worry</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Jun 2012 09:34:58 -0500</pubDate>
      <author>chris@gorilla-studios.com (Chris Peak)</author>
      <guid>http://www.gorilla-studios.com/2012/06/15/dont-worry</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I have had lots of conversations over the years with friends and younger photographers about upgrading gear, and they always ask about what camera is &#39;better&#39; or which does X better. As a beginner or amateur photographer guess what? The specs don&#39;t really matter. If you listen closely you&#39;ll hear the sound of thousands of Internet Trolls crying out &lt;em&gt;&#39;Blasphemy!&#39;&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The other day a friend and I were discussing about what she should get as her first serious DSLR. She told me that the guy at Wolf Camera was going on about how Nikon has better low-light performance, but the Canon optics are better, blah blah blah. She got worried and wanted to know the real-world differences between a few entry to mid-level cameras. These clerks never seem to realize that they are splitting hairs and to a beginner it doesn&#39;t matter (and most of the time they don&#39;t understand). Do you really think to a beginner (or anyone really) it matters that camera X shoots .5fps faster than camera Y, or its sensor is 3MP more? No. Nobody can tell the difference between a 16MP photo and a 18.5MP photo when they are all uploaded onto Flickr.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I always laugh when car guys are comparing a BMW that can do 180MPh and a Mercedes that can do 182MPh. Yes that Merc is technically faster, but they are both high-performance machines that are really never going to be pushed to their limits. It&#39;s the same with cameras - the difference between a Canon EOS 60D and a Nikon D90 is going to be marginal to most beginner and amateur photographers. This Nikon may have 1MP more, or that Canon may be a hair better in low-light sensitivity, but guess what? They are both fantastic cameras that produce great images.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yes it is an investment and you want to purchase the right camera to fit your needs since you will have it for years (I am *still* shooting with my 10D I purchased in 2003), but don&#39;t go overboard wringing your hands about the spec differences between a Rebel T2i and a D5000. Figure out what you want to use the camera for, buy it, and start having fun. Remember: its not the sensor, the lens, or the ultra-high ISO, or some whiz-bang feature that make the photograph - it&#39;s your eye, your gut, and your heart.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Stop worrying about all the new cameras coming out and forget about how this camera magazine said brand X was so much better. Instead of sitting in front of a computer reading spec sheets, review after review, and endless forum posts, take that time and go outside with &lt;em&gt;your camera&lt;/em&gt;. Take some awesome shots with what you have - share it, talk about your art, and most of all, have fun with it.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Summer Is Almost Here</title>
      <link>http://www.gorilla-studios.com/2012/05/18/summer-is-almost-here</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 May 2012 14:29:05 -0500</pubDate>
      <author>chris@gorilla-studios.com (Chris Peak)</author>
      <guid>http://www.gorilla-studios.com/2012/05/18/summer-is-almost-here</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/portfolio/flower_bug.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Bug on a flower Strobist Macro Photography&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Coolest/Dumbest Photographer In The World</title>
      <link>http://www.gorilla-studios.com/2012/04/20/the-coolestdumbest-photographer-in-the-world</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Apr 2012 15:12:18 -0500</pubDate>
      <author>chris@gorilla-studios.com (Chris Peak)</author>
      <guid>http://www.gorilla-studios.com/2012/04/20/the-coolestdumbest-photographer-in-the-world</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/stay-cool.gif&quot; alt=&quot;Don&#39;t Panic&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Found this on &lt;a href=&quot;http://memebase.com/2012/04/20/internet-memes-just-escaped-death-still-taking-pictures/&quot;&gt;Memebase&lt;/a&gt;.  This guy is both 1) Incredibly calm given the circumstances, and 2) Incredibly stupid for being that close to the action.  I think 99% of the time that would have ended the other way. Had a car almost clipped me I don&#39;t think I would calmly take pictures as it went by, id be changing my pants.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Don&#39;t try this at home kids.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Web Design Blog</title>
      <link>http://www.gorilla-studios.com/2012/04/04/web-design-blog</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Apr 2012 16:18:12 -0500</pubDate>
      <author>chris@gorilla-studios.com (Chris Peak)</author>
      <guid>http://www.gorilla-studios.com/2012/04/04/web-design-blog</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In February I accepted a design residency at &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.8thlight.com&quot;&gt;8th Light&lt;/a&gt; in Chicago, so needless to say that has been my primary focus lately.  One of my residency requirements is to write weekly blog posts about my experience and what I am learning. I wrote an entirely new &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/mojombo/jekyll&quot;&gt;Jekyll&lt;/a&gt; powered blog hosted on github to share my experiences. You can check it out at &lt;a href=&quot;http://cpeak.github.com&quot;&gt;cpeak.github.com&lt;/a&gt;. It also has a lot of design &amp;amp; development resources. Enjoy!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Canon 50mm f/1.8</title>
      <link>http://www.gorilla-studios.com/2012/03/31/canon-50mm-f1-8</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 31 Mar 2012 09:32:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <author>chris@gorilla-studios.com (Chris Peak)</author>
      <guid>http://www.gorilla-studios.com/2012/03/31/canon-50mm-f1-8</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I got a chance earlier this week to test out my Canon 50mm f/1.8 in the field for a quick headshot session downtown with our friend Allie. Overall it&#39;s a great lens at an absolute bargain that should be in any photographers bag. Amazon has the lens on sale for $117 as of right now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/50mm.gif&quot; alt=&quot;Canon 50mm f/1.8 Prime Lens&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We had planned to meet up and shoot around 5:30, about an hour before sunset. However Allie got delayed at work which put us back a bit so we were fighting the sun going down. Despite losing daylight rapidly the little 50mm performed very well - I even grabbed some frames at 1/20th all the way open at f/1.8 handheld. Since it is not packing a USM (Ultra Sonic Motor) low-light focusing did become an issue, however it wasn&#39;t a deal-breaker though I felt it could perform better. I only mis-focused one or two shots due to the low-light (and that was shooting 1.8 with a very limited depth of field). The lens is super light and some reviews complain that it is built cheaply but I couldn&#39;t find any issues with the quality.  The manual focus ring is smaller than most lenses so I can see that being a complaint to someone who likes to use manual control often, but I don&#39;t mind it that much.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/allie.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Canon 50mm f/1.8 at 1/20th&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here is an un-edited shot taken on my 10D with the 50mm, f/1.8 at 1/20th, hand-held.  As you can see even with an extremely shallow depth-of-field it is very sharp where it needs to be. The bokeh is very smooth so shooting in downtown Chicago at dusk made for some beautiful backgrounds.  We did a basic one-light strobist shoot. I set my Speedlite paired with a wireless trigger on a lightstand with an umbrella which my wife kept from blowing away. Walking around Millennium Park we found some overhead lights in the amphitheater that acted as beauty lights really highlighting her hair, so technically its a two-light setup in this shot.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hands down this is almost a must buy for anyone who shoots portraits or wants more performance in low-light situations.  It&#39;s a well built lens thats &lt;em&gt;very&lt;/em&gt; fast, a great bang for the buck. &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Don't Rush Out And Buy The Latest And Greatest</title>
      <link>http://www.gorilla-studios.com/2012/03/23/dont-rush-out-and-buy-latest-and-greatest</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Mar 2012 10:52:21 -0500</pubDate>
      <author>chris@gorilla-studios.com (Chris Peak)</author>
      <guid>http://www.gorilla-studios.com/2012/03/23/dont-rush-out-and-buy-latest-and-greatest</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A lot of younger and more inexperienced photographers I&#39;ve met over the years have a bad case of gadget envy.  I always hear them saying &#39;...if I only had this lens&#39; or &#39;if I had this new DSLR body then I would really be so much better&#39;.  Repeat with me: &lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Buying new gear does not make you a better photographer&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;. Trust me, I&#39;ve been there - I still get the bug every now and then, but thankfully my experience wins out in the end. I started writing this post because the new Canon EOS 5D MkIII was just announced and is poised to hit the market very soon (update: &lt;em&gt;today&lt;/em&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Just because the 5D MkIII is now on the market that does not make your DSLR any less of a camera. If you have a Rebel T2i or an EOS 60D, the jump to the 5D MkIII is not going to instantly make your photos better. The difference between an 18.1MP photograph from an entry level T2i and a 22.3MP photograph from the new MkIII are going to be negligible at best. Unless you are doing glamour shots for Vogue or full spreads for National Geographic your current camera is up to the task. The new Digic 5+ processor is not going to compose better photographs for you and having a 63-Zone Dual Layer Metering system is not going to magically fix that lighting problem you&#39;ve been having in the photos you&#39;ve taken so far.  Practice and experience make the photographer, not the camera.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;But, but, but I want that shiny new camera that was just released, its soooo much better!&lt;/em&gt; Guess what - I still shoot to this day with an 6.1MP EOS 10D, which is now almost 10 years old. Technology wise most people categorize this as a &#39;dinosaur&#39;, heck, most cell phones have higher megapixel counts. Every photo in &lt;a href=&quot;/?page_id=133&quot;&gt;my gallery&lt;/a&gt; was shot with the 10D. When I first got it I experienced a lot of growing pains - I was exploring night photography, taking long exposures of the city and I found myself constantly looking at the pro level EOS SLRs thinking they would take me to the next level. I was frustrated about the quality of photographs I was taking. Would a pro level camera back then make my photos any better? Nope. I would have made the same mistakes in composition and lighting and been just as frustrated and my wallet would have been a lot lighter. I took my time to learn my craft, discussing my work with other photographers, learning as much as I could.  Now shooting with that same camera I am getting photos that I am truly proud of, and the only thing I upgraded was my experience.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>37signals - Give It 5 Minutes</title>
      <link>http://www.gorilla-studios.com/2012/03/01/37-signals-give-it-5-minutes</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Mar 2012 13:19:52 -0600</pubDate>
      <author>chris@gorilla-studios.com (Chris Peak)</author>
      <guid>http://www.gorilla-studios.com/2012/03/01/37-signals-give-it-5-minutes</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://37signals.com/svn/posts/3124-give-it-five-minutes&quot;&gt;My favorite blog post&lt;/a&gt; from them in a long time, which is saying something because SVN is one of my favorite feeds.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;So next time you hear something, or someone, talk about an idea, pitch an idea, or suggest an idea, give it five minutes. Think about it a little bit before pushing back, before saying its too hard or its too much work. Those things may be true, but there may be another truth in there too: It may be worth it.&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am the exact opposite of how Jason was - I take a lot of time when people pitch ideas and express opinions.  I deliberately wait and think about it, working out my thoughts clearly first.  I let the first round of counter-arguments and crap fly before I open my mouth, that way I can tell who is worth discussing the issue with.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DSLR Shutter Release In Super Slow-Motion</title>
      <link>http://www.gorilla-studios.com/2012/02/11/dslr-shutter-release-in-super-slow-motion</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Feb 2012 19:15:13 -0600</pubDate>
      <author>chris@gorilla-studios.com (Chris Peak)</author>
      <guid>http://www.gorilla-studios.com/2012/02/11/dslr-shutter-release-in-super-slow-motion</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.petapixel.com/2012/01/24/a-dslr-camera-shutter-in-slow-motion/&quot;&gt;Via PetaPixel&lt;/a&gt; - watch straight down the inside of a Canon 60D as the shutter button is pressed. For beginners this is a great way to understand the whole process of how your DSLR actually takes a photo. When you press the shutter release the mirror flips up and the shutter blades then open to expose the sensor to the light coming in from the lens.  After a set time - &lt;em&gt;your shutter speed&lt;/em&gt; - the blades snap back into place and the mirror drops down again.  What is really amazing is how fast this process happens - a typical exposure during the day may be around 1/250th to 1/500th of a second.  My old camera can go all the way up to 1/4000th!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is also a great example why why for long exposures I like to use my &lt;strong&gt;Mirror Lockup&lt;/strong&gt; function built into my camera.  As you can see there is an awful lot of vibration as the mirror slams up into place before the shutter opens.  To avoid any of this shake you can &#39;lock the mirror&#39; in place before the actual exposure. Using my cable release I press the button once to lock the mirror up into place, then press it again to take the actual exposure and release the mirror, avoiding any vibrations that may compromise my photograph. More on that later.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Productivity Quick-Tip - SynergyKM For Mac</title>
      <link>http://www.gorilla-studios.com/2012/02/04/productivity-quick-tip-synergykm-for-mac</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Feb 2012 10:04:49 -0600</pubDate>
      <author>chris@gorilla-studios.com (Chris Peak)</author>
      <guid>http://www.gorilla-studios.com/2012/02/04/productivity-quick-tip-synergykm-for-mac</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;One tool I use quite a bit but never think about is &lt;a href=&quot;http://sourceforge.net/projects/synergykm/&quot;&gt;SynergyKM&lt;/a&gt;, an open-source app that lets you control multiple computers with one keyboard and mouse without a physical KVM switch.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My primary setup is a PowerMac G5 workstation which I do all my photography editing on, but for coding and work I have a PowerBook that travels with me.  When I am home I enjoy being able to use both but I don&#39;t want the hassle of switching back and forth between the two. Synergy solves the problem very simply.  The application installs as a preference pane on both machines and setup is easy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/synergykm.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;SynergyKM for Mac&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here I have my PowerMac G5 &#39;Ogden&#39; setup as the server, and my PowerBook &#39;Asana-2&#39; (why did I name it -2?) setup to the left of my displays.  On the PowerBook I just tell it to look for Ogden and since they are on the same network they connect to each other.  Now I can just swing my mouse over to the left and just like with multiple displays it transfers mouse and keyboard control over to the PowerBook.  When you leave the current computer it takes the mouse cursor and just drops it dead center on the primary screen indicating that its in a kind of &#39;idle&#39; state.  Mac&#39;s and PC&#39;s work seamlessly, and you can setup multiple locations as well - I have profiles setup for home and work so when I&#39;m at the office I just switch profiles and it connects to my work PC.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Its open-source so its free, and it removes the clutter of a second keyboard and mouse from the desk which is huge for me since I enjoy a clean work area.  The biggest benefit is that it removes the confusion or mental jump between machines - when you&#39;re in a workflow you don&#39;t even think about it, it&#39;s seamless. Be sure to head over to the &lt;a href=&quot;http://sourceforge.net/projects/synergykm/&quot;&gt;Source-Forge project page&lt;/a&gt; and check it out.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>First Of The Month - What's Your Backup Situation?</title>
      <link>http://www.gorilla-studios.com/2012/02/01/first-of-the-month-whats-your-backup-situation</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Feb 2012 21:42:04 -0600</pubDate>
      <author>chris@gorilla-studios.com (Chris Peak)</author>
      <guid>http://www.gorilla-studios.com/2012/02/01/first-of-the-month-whats-your-backup-situation</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It&#39;s the first of the month - a great time to double check how your backups are doing.  My full time job is doing IT support so I see first-hand the dangers of either not backing up data or not checking your backups. Remember: just backing up your data is not good enough! &lt;strong&gt;CHECK IT&lt;/strong&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How do you know your backup set is good? Most people don&#39;t check until they are already in hot water. Don&#39;t gamble with your data - run a &#39;fire-drill&#39; every few months.  Pretend your main computer just crashed - shut it down and walk through what it&#39;s going to take to get you back on your feet.  Do you have a spare machine incase your motherboard fails? Do you have a spare hard drive to swap in if its a drive crash? Do you have your software installers and more importantly the license keys?  What applications do you need to get your workflow going? Planning this out before something crashes, that way when it does you know what to do.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Remember&lt;/em&gt; - backup drives are just as fallible as internal drives.  Don&#39;t put all your eggs in one basket by storing all your documents in one external &#39;backup drive&#39;.  You are not protected until your data is on two separate devices. In my experience you can usually expect hard drives to last between 3 and 5 years, however if it is a mission critical drive I would replace them every 1 or 2 years.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Backup solutions are very affordable these days so there is no excuse for not having at least something in place.  Check your backups on the first of the month and run your fire drill once every few months, that way if something ever happens you&#39;ll be in great shape.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Back!</title>
      <link>http://www.gorilla-studios.com/2012/01/23/back</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Jan 2012 19:06:03 -0600</pubDate>
      <author>chris@gorilla-studios.com (Chris Peak)</author>
      <guid>http://www.gorilla-studios.com/2012/01/23/back</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/beach.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Beachfront in the Bahamas&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Back from my honeymoon with my amazing wife, refreshed and ready to take on the new year.  Looking forward to a great year for myself and the website, lots of new things are cooking so be sure to come back often!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>28 Resolutions From 28 Seasoned Photographers</title>
      <link>http://www.gorilla-studios.com/2012/01/10/28-resolutions-from-28-seasoned-photographers</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Jan 2012 19:23:06 -0600</pubDate>
      <author>chris@gorilla-studios.com (Chris Peak)</author>
      <guid>http://www.gorilla-studios.com/2012/01/10/28-resolutions-from-28-seasoned-photographers</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I set myself a number of goals for the upcoming year that I am committed to fulfilling, so I was happy to find a great list of 2012 resolutions from professional photographers (a few of which I really look up to and love their work).  &lt;a href=&quot;http://blog.photoshelter.com/2012/01/28-resolutions-from-28-seasoned-photographers/&quot;&gt;Read the full article over at Photoshelter&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Jam Session</title>
      <link>http://www.gorilla-studios.com/2012/01/09/jam-session</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Jan 2012 19:28:13 -0600</pubDate>
      <author>chris@gorilla-studios.com (Chris Peak)</author>
      <guid>http://www.gorilla-studios.com/2012/01/09/jam-session</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/CRW_3885.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sunset - January 6th, 2012</title>
      <link>http://www.gorilla-studios.com/2012/01/06/sunset-january-6th-2012</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Jan 2012 18:55:37 -0600</pubDate>
      <author>chris@gorilla-studios.com (Chris Peak)</author>
      <guid>http://www.gorilla-studios.com/2012/01/06/sunset-january-6th-2012</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/CRW_3718.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Sunset&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was stuck at work but managed to sneak out back and take a quick snap.  Remember, the best camera is the one you have on you!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gorilla-Studios Now On 500px</title>
      <link>http://www.gorilla-studios.com/2012/01/02/gorilla-studios-now-on-500px</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Jan 2012 23:59:21 -0600</pubDate>
      <author>chris@gorilla-studios.com (Chris Peak)</author>
      <guid>http://www.gorilla-studios.com/2012/01/02/gorilla-studios-now-on-500px</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://500px.com/gorilla-studios&quot;&gt;Gorilla-Studios is now on 500px.com&lt;/a&gt;, a new photographic community for discovering and sharing great photographs.  I&#39;m still setting up my profile and getting my work uploaded, but if you want to share your work be sure to join soon.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New Years Resolution - Investing In Myself</title>
      <link>http://www.gorilla-studios.com/2012/01/01/new-years-resolution-investing-in-myself</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2012 17:33:31 -0600</pubDate>
      <author>chris@gorilla-studios.com (Chris Peak)</author>
      <guid>http://www.gorilla-studios.com/2012/01/01/new-years-resolution-investing-in-myself</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Happy New Year everyone!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here&#39;s to making 2012 a great year. I usually don&#39;t make resolutions but this year I will be investing in my photography - dedicating more time and hopefully upgrading equipment as the year goes on. In 2011 I was focused on getting married and working my full time job, so now this year I am going to spend more time learning, shooting and expanding my portfolio. My immediate goal is to at least go out shooting once a week and try to get a portfolio image every month. I want to learn more and hone my skills, I will be really pushing myself and sharing my knowledge and experience here. I have quite a bit planned for the site this year, more post ideas, reviews, critiques and more!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So happy shooting and happy 2012 everyone!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Chris&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>From The Archives</title>
      <link>http://www.gorilla-studios.com/2011/12/31/from-the-archives-2</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 31 Dec 2011 11:33:44 -0600</pubDate>
      <author>chris@gorilla-studios.com (Chris Peak)</author>
      <guid>http://www.gorilla-studios.com/2011/12/31/from-the-archives-2</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/IMG_1811.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Lighthouse and Sailboat on Lake Michigan, Chicago, Illinois&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Whats In The Bag? Black Rapid RS 7</title>
      <link>http://www.gorilla-studios.com/2011/12/30/whats-in-the-bag-black-rapid-rs-7</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Dec 2011 07:18:30 -0600</pubDate>
      <author>chris@gorilla-studios.com (Chris Peak)</author>
      <guid>http://www.gorilla-studios.com/2011/12/30/whats-in-the-bag-black-rapid-rs-7</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The newest addition to my setup is a brand new Black Rapid RS-7 sling camera strap.  Prior to finding this one under the Christmas tree this year I was using a homemade setup that consisted of a guitar strap secured to a post from an extra tripod mount - not the most professional setup in the world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Black Rapid RS-7 is simply the best camera strap I have come across in years.  It allows me to go hands free when setting up a shoot, moving lighting around or directing my subjects while keeping my camera at my side right where I need it ready to go. It comes with the main strap and a fastener that attaches to your SLR body tripod mount (or long lens if need be).  The strap clips into the fastener with a locking carabiner that sits well on the underside of your camera. I have a battery grip with vertical controls and the while the RS-7 attached I don&#39;t find it uncomfortable shooting vertically.  The fastener sits right in the center of my palm without any discomfort.  The carabiner swings out of the way and freely spins on the strap without un-screwing the fastener from the SLR body.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/fastener.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Black Rapid RS-7 Fastener on Canon EOS DSLR Camera&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The whole setup feels great to use - I am usually paranoid about straps and hanging on to my camera, but I have no doubts when using it.  As with any strap I always have a hand on the lens while walking in crowds or around anything that I can bang into, but I have no worries about it unclipping or detaching and dropping. Sliding the strap up to shooting position is very quick with little resistance, same with sliding it back in place at your side.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/carabiner.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Black Rapid RS-7 Caribeaner clip for digital SLR camera&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another great feature is the locking &#39;bumpers&#39; on the strap that keep the shoulder padding in the right place.  There is a back bumper that you lock in right where you want the camera to hang - this way if the padded portion of the strap moves when you pull your camera up to shoot, as you slide your camera back down it catches the bumper and moves the strap back into the proper location.  There is another front bumper that you can move down to lock the camera down by your hip which really reduces how much it swings around when you are hands free.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The RS-7 is also compatible with Black Rapid&#39;s Mods - like the BRAD strap or storage for memory cards or a cell phone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Overall the Black Rapid RS-7 is a beautifully made camera strap that any photographer worth their salt should have in their bag. I only had the chance to shoot with it a few times, but I am in love with it and highly recommend it. Check out the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.blackrapid.com/product/camera-strap/rs-7/&quot;&gt;RS-7 at Black Rapid&#39;s website&lt;/a&gt;.  Don&#39;t believe me? Check out &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=hWJKrqP40Nw&quot;&gt;Jared Polin&#39;s (aka FroKnowsFoto......DOT COM) video review.&lt;/a&gt;  All images courtesy of Black Rapid.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Quote - Ira Glass</title>
      <link>http://www.gorilla-studios.com/2011/12/27/quote-ira-glass</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Dec 2011 22:26:40 -0600</pubDate>
      <author>chris@gorilla-studios.com (Chris Peak)</author>
      <guid>http://www.gorilla-studios.com/2011/12/27/quote-ira-glass</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I am reading &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.amazon.com/The-Passionate-Photographer-Toward-Becoming/dp/0321719891/ref=sr_1_1&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Passionate Photographer: Ten Steps Toward Becoming Great&lt;/em&gt; by Steve Simon&lt;/a&gt; and came across a quote from Ira Glass about honing your skills that I had heard a few years ago which hit me like a truck...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;quote&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You&#39;ve got to get rid of a lot of crap before you&#39;re going to get anything that&#39;s special.  You don&#39;t want to be making mediocre stuff.  There&#39;s a gap for the first couple years that you&#39;re making stuff. What you&#39;re making isn&#39;t so good. But your taste, the thing that got you into the game, is good enough that you can tell what you&#39;re making is kind of a disappointment to you. A lot of people at that point, they quit. The thing I would say to you with all my heart is that most everybody I know who does interesting, creative work, went through a phase of years where they had really good taste, they could tell what they were making wasn&#39;t as good as they wanted it to be. They knew it fell short. Everybody goes through that. If you&#39;re going through it right now, or if you&#39;re just starting off and you&#39;re entering into that phase, you&#39;ve got to know its totally normal and the most important thing you could do is a lot of work. Do a huge volume of work because it&#39;s only by actually going through a volume of work that you&#39;re actually going to catch up and close that gap.&lt;br /&gt;
- Ira Glass&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Such an amazing quote.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Photoshop Quick Tip - Lens Correction</title>
      <link>http://www.gorilla-studios.com/2011/12/14/photoshop-quick-tip-lens-correction</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Dec 2011 09:36:53 -0600</pubDate>
      <author>chris@gorilla-studios.com (Chris Peak)</author>
      <guid>http://www.gorilla-studios.com/2011/12/14/photoshop-quick-tip-lens-correction</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I love shooting in downtown Chicago, but one of the hazards you run into is something called the Keystone Effect - a distortion of taller buildings and structures.  A few days after our wedding, the wife and I took a day trip into the city with our cameras in tow. After a fun afternoon at the Shedd Aquarium we walked back up along the lake and I took a quick shot of the skyline. Here you can see the shot before editing.  I added quick lines to show how the buildings are leaning in towards the center of frame and you will notice this effect getting worse the farther from center they are.  This is a great example of the Keystone Effect.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/before_wlines.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Distorted image correction&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To take care of this we are going to use a Photoshop filter called &lt;strong&gt;Filter &amp;gt; Distort &amp;gt; Lens Correction&lt;/strong&gt;.   Here is the control panel for this particular filter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/lens-correction.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Photoshop Lens Correction Filter&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Leave the grid on and take a look over at the Transform section towards the bottom right.  There you will find a slider for &#39;Vertical Perspective&#39;.  Here you can adjust your photo and make sure everything lines up the way it should, taking care of that Keystone Effect.  For this particular example I adjusted it to -15, this got most of the buildings in the shot back to vertical, especially Aon Center and Trump Tower.  Once you make your adjustment you will notice that the bottom of your photo has been compressed in a bit leaving some bare canvas on either bottom corner. This is due to the fact Photoshop has basically tilted the entire plane of the photo towards you, hinging on the center line - therefore the bottom of the image is smaller and the top is larger.  Just crop the photo to ensure you don&#39;t have any blank areas on either corner. Here we can see the before and after:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/before_after.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Keystone effect before after&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is details like this that can sometimes make or break a photograph so keep an eye out for this effect when shooting large buildings or have a lot of vertical lines in your photo.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Have fun and keep shooting!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Happy 8th Birthday Gorilla-Studios</title>
      <link>http://www.gorilla-studios.com/2011/12/12/happy-8th-birthday-gorilla-studios</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Dec 2011 11:46:19 -0600</pubDate>
      <author>chris@gorilla-studios.com (Chris Peak)</author>
      <guid>http://www.gorilla-studios.com/2011/12/12/happy-8th-birthday-gorilla-studios</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It&#39;s been 8 years since the first version of Gorilla-Studios went live! A few tear-downs and re-designs later, many trivial &amp;amp; random posts later and here we are! I meant this post to be a bit more grand but I am laid up this week one appendix lighter so the celebration will have to wait a little bit. I&#39;ll be back later with some more, but for now, its time for another nap...&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Chris&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Whats In The Bag?</title>
      <link>http://www.gorilla-studios.com/2011/12/03/whats-in-the-bag</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Dec 2011 14:35:05 -0600</pubDate>
      <author>chris@gorilla-studios.com (Chris Peak)</author>
      <guid>http://www.gorilla-studios.com/2011/12/03/whats-in-the-bag</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I get a lot of questions about what camera and lenses I shoot with and what gear I like to carry, so I am going to write a few posts covering what&#39;s in my bag and what I lug around on a typical shoot.  Here&#39;s my usual gear bag for general shoots:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/bag.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Lowepro Camera Bag&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And my primary DSLR....&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/10D.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Canon EOS 10D DSLR&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I shoot everything with my trusty EOS 10D.  Its pretty antiquated these days, but I still get great results.  It has a 6.1MP CMOS which still holds it&#39;s own in most situations but is severely lacking in low-light situations. It has an ISO range from 100 to 1600, however I rarely get shots above ISO 800 that I really like. All the photos in the gallery were shot with the 10D paired with various lenses (which I will go over individually later).  Originally purchased in 2003, the camera is still solid as a rock after taking (and this is an estimate) somewhere in the neighborhood of at least 50,000 photos.  The primary shutter button is just starting to flake out, it takes a firm press and there is a bit of a delay but thankfully I have it paired to a dual-battery grip with vertical controls.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once my checkbook has recovered from the wedding I am planning on investing in a 5D MkII.  Remember the phrase &lt;em&gt;&#39;Buy once, buy right&#39;&lt;/em&gt;.  Don&#39;t buy something thats good enough for now that you may outgrow later just because you can afford it. Save up and invest in good equipment - it will last and you&#39;ll be much happier.  I made the mistake as a young photographer by purchasing a number of really slow lenses not knowing exactly what I should have gotten.  I saw the Canon 70-200mm f2.8 but didn&#39;t understand why that was so much more than an off brand f4 telephoto.  There is a huge difference in quality and without experience I couldn&#39;t see that.  Remember, you don&#39;t need a bunch of fancy lenses and the latest greatest equipment to be a great photographer.  Invest in a solid DSLR, and one or two fast lenses, and shoot, shoot, SHOOT.  Practice and experience make the photographer, not the gear.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&#39;ll be writing some more posts about the rest of the gear in my bag, so check back later or subscribe to my RSS Feed.  Feel free to contact me with any gear questions, and have fun shooting!&lt;br /&gt;

- Chris&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mini-Review - Opteka MP100 67" Monopod</title>
      <link>http://www.gorilla-studios.com/2011/10/25/mini-review-opteka-mp100-67-monopod</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Oct 2011 12:03:11 -0500</pubDate>
      <author>chris@gorilla-studios.com (Chris Peak)</author>
      <guid>http://www.gorilla-studios.com/2011/10/25/mini-review-opteka-mp100-67-monopod</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In preparation for an upcoming photo trip to see migrating Sandhill Cranes I wanted to get a monopod so I didn&#39;t have to lug my full tripod out into the field.  After some browsing online, I decided to go with the Opteka MP100 67&quot; Monopod.  I couldn&#39;t bring myself to spending over a hundred dollars on some high-end brand name kit.  For &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.amazon.com/Opteka-MP100-Professional-Heavy-Monopod/dp/B0002RBQO0/&quot;&gt;13.50 from Amazon&lt;/a&gt; I figured why not try it and see if its a good deal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/opteka_m100.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Opteka M100 Monopod and carrying case&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The monopod itself is rather sturdy, not completely solid, but well built.  It compacts down very well, with 3 quick release levers for fairly easy adjustments.  I paired it up with an Opteka Ball Head and got amazing results.  I assumed for 13$ it was going to be flimsy and not well constructed, but I was surprised. It held my EOS with battery grip, the ball head, and a large lens very well.  The main advantage of this monopod is that it extends out to 67&quot; which is a must for me considering I stand at 6&#39;6&quot;.  With the ballhead I found myself actually lowering the top section a bit to get the camera eye level, which is astounding.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Overall its a well built monopod for an absolute steal.  Its not the most solid constructed unit I have ever seen, but it is a fantastic bargain.  We will see how it holds up to day to day usage in the field.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ever have one of those days?</title>
      <link>http://www.gorilla-studios.com/2011/10/07/ever-have-one-of-those-days</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Oct 2011 15:17:55 -0500</pubDate>
      <author>chris@gorilla-studios.com (Chris Peak)</author>
      <guid>http://www.gorilla-studios.com/2011/10/07/ever-have-one-of-those-days</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;where everything was perfect and way beyond expectation? I did, and it happened to be my wedding day...&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/c_n_k.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Chris and wife&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Huge thanks to &lt;a href=&quot;http://riversidereceptions.com/&quot;&gt;Riverside Receptions&lt;/a&gt; in Geneva, IL for taking care of everything, having everything setup, ready to go and handling anything that came up.  The service was fantastic, the food was wonderful and the whole day was amazing thanks to them.  Many thanks to &lt;a href=&quot;http://aclassactdjservice.com/aclassactdjservice.com/Welcome.html&quot;&gt;Andy Fuzak with A Class Act DJ Service&lt;/a&gt; for DJ&#39;ing the night and making sure everything flowed well and everyone kept dancing all night!  Also many thanks to &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.bellapictures.com/&quot;&gt;Bella Pictures&lt;/a&gt; and their photographer who captured the special day for us.  I am extremely picky when it comes to photography and they paired us with a true professional - I cannot wait to see the results.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thank you to all my family and friends who supported us throughout the years and came out to celebrate with us.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And above all, thanks to my blushing bride, I love you so much.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Thank You Steve</title>
      <link>http://www.gorilla-studios.com/2011/10/06/thank-you-steve</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Oct 2011 08:57:37 -0500</pubDate>
      <author>chris@gorilla-studios.com (Chris Peak)</author>
      <guid>http://www.gorilla-studios.com/2011/10/06/thank-you-steve</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Thank you for years of dedication and passion.  When I was tall enough to reach the keyboard I started playing around with my Dads Apple II, getting lost in the adventure of Oddessy, trekking the Oregon Trail, and discovering a passion that lives on to this day.  My jaw hit the floor when we got our Apple IIGS, color graphics!  A mouse!  Dad and I started learning basic programming together, exploring what we could get that amazing machine to do.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was the happiest kid in the world when I got my very own Centris 650, all 30Mhz of its power, all mine!  I was an expert by the time I got a PowerMac 7200.  An iMac, PowerMac G4, and an iBook all followed.  My trusty PowerBook and PowerMac are still my reliable workhorses I use every day.  My wife got me an iPad for my birthday and I was as giddy as I was when I was a kid playing with our Apple II.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As my passion for photography grew and grew, so did my love of Apple.  Their products allowed me to focus on my work and express my creativity, as Steve said, a true bicycle for the mind.  I would not be able to do what I do if not for Steve Jobs.  I am in awe of all the tributes popping up all over the web today, it truly shows us the world lost a visionary.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He did make a dent in the universe.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is with great sadness in my heart that I say Thanks Steve&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Stop to smell the roses</title>
      <link>http://www.gorilla-studios.com/2011/08/10/stop-to-smell-the-roses</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Aug 2011 10:52:27 -0500</pubDate>
      <author>chris@gorilla-studios.com (Chris Peak)</author>
      <guid>http://www.gorilla-studios.com/2011/08/10/stop-to-smell-the-roses</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;You&#39;ll never know what you might find.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/flower_bug.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Bug in Flower&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Good Morning</title>
      <link>http://www.gorilla-studios.com/2011/07/30/good-morning</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Jul 2011 10:58:42 -0500</pubDate>
      <author>chris@gorilla-studios.com (Chris Peak)</author>
      <guid>http://www.gorilla-studios.com/2011/07/30/good-morning</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/CRW_8206.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Butterfly Mt St Mary Park&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Photojojo - Gifts &amp; Gear For The Photographer</title>
      <link>http://www.gorilla-studios.com/2011/07/07/photojojo-gifts-gear-for-photographers</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Jul 2011 13:28:03 -0500</pubDate>
      <author>chris@gorilla-studios.com (Chris Peak)</author>
      <guid>http://www.gorilla-studios.com/2011/07/07/photojojo-gifts-gear-for-photographers</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Stumbled across this today - &lt;a href=&quot;http://photojojo.com/store/&quot;&gt;gifts and gear for photographers from Photojojo&lt;/a&gt;.  Fun looking site with lots of fun stuff that I would love to order (or &lt;a href=&quot;http://photojojo.com/store/awesomeness/camera-lens-mug/&quot;&gt;hope to find&lt;/a&gt; under the Christmas tree *cough cough*).    Full disclosure - I have no affiliation with Photojojo, but would easily be bought with freebies.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cuddle Up With Your Favorite Lens</title>
      <link>http://www.gorilla-studios.com/2011/07/07/cuddle-up-with-your-favorite-lens</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Jul 2011 09:05:13 -0500</pubDate>
      <author>chris@gorilla-studios.com (Chris Peak)</author>
      <guid>http://www.gorilla-studios.com/2011/07/07/cuddle-up-with-your-favorite-lens</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.plushtography.com/shop.html&quot;&gt;Plushtography.com&lt;/a&gt; hand makes lens pillows that are absolutely awesome.  Two of the three they have are now sold-out and I would assume the last one is going to sell out fast too.  Tip of the hat to &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.engadget.com/2011/07/07/plush-camera-lens-pillows-get-you-through-the-night-koala-hug-a/&quot;&gt;Engadget&lt;/a&gt; for the find.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Start Basic</title>
      <link>http://www.gorilla-studios.com/2011/06/25/start-basic</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Jun 2011 17:10:03 -0500</pubDate>
      <author>chris@gorilla-studios.com (Chris Peak)</author>
      <guid>http://www.gorilla-studios.com/2011/06/25/start-basic</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/start_basic_logo.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Start Basic band logo&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/images/start-basic1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Start Basic band&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I got the chance to shoot some promo shots over the weekend for Start Basic - a great local band from Batavia.  They are prepping their first album so we are working on rolling out their new logo, identity, t-shirt and poster designs - the works. I&#39;ll be posting about my experience with shooting a band, working with your subjects and getting the results you want.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Absolutely Breathtaking</title>
      <link>http://www.gorilla-studios.com/2011/06/15/absolutely-breathtaking</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jun 2011 20:22:50 -0500</pubDate>
      <author>chris@gorilla-studios.com (Chris Peak)</author>
      <guid>http://www.gorilla-studios.com/2011/06/15/absolutely-breathtaking</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Via Gizmodo - Randy Halverson shot these &lt;a href=&quot;http://gizmodo.com/5812198/watch-the-milky-way-wheel-overhead-in-all-its-glory&quot;&gt;absolutely breathtaking time-lapse shots&lt;/a&gt; of the Milky Way passing over the South Dakota landscape. Simply amazing.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Oatmeal v. FunnyJunk - Copyright &amp; Creativity</title>
      <link>http://www.gorilla-studios.com/2011/06/02/the-oatmeal-vs-funnyjunk-copyright-creativity</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jun 2011 09:12:43 -0500</pubDate>
      <author>chris@gorilla-studios.com (Chris Peak)</author>
      <guid>http://www.gorilla-studios.com/2011/06/02/the-oatmeal-vs-funnyjunk-copyright-creativity</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.theoatmeal.com&quot;&gt;The Oatmeal&lt;/a&gt; is possibly one of the most creative laugh-out-loud funny (and &lt;a href=&quot;http://theoatmeal.com/comics/semicolon&quot;&gt;educational&lt;/a&gt;) web-comics I have come across in recent years and it breaks my heart to see Matthew Inman getting ripped off by FunnyJunk.  Arstechnica has &lt;a href=&quot;http://arstechnica.com/tech-policy/news/2011/06/funnyjunk-vs-the-oatmeal.ars&quot;&gt;a great article&lt;/a&gt; about FunnyJunk lifting Inman&#39;s work with little to no attribution.  Be sure to read Matthew&#39;s thoughtful and insightful &lt;a href=&quot;http://theoatmeal.com/blog/funnyjunk2&quot;&gt;response&lt;/a&gt; to the whole ordeal.  As a footnote - if you want to see the downfall of human culture in action just look at any internet forum or youtube comment thread.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As an artist I am extremely nervous about my own work being ripped off, but thankfully (or not) I am not well-known enough to have that happen.  I have struggled with how to handle copyrighting and watermarking my images to protect my work, however I don&#39;t want to treat my tens of readers/viewers like criminals.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Broken Lens Horror Stories</title>
      <link>http://www.gorilla-studios.com/2011/06/01/broken-lens-horror-stories</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jun 2011 11:51:43 -0500</pubDate>
      <author>chris@gorilla-studios.com (Chris Peak)</author>
      <guid>http://www.gorilla-studios.com/2011/06/01/broken-lens-horror-stories</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Fun little article over on Gizmodo listing some &lt;a href=&quot;http://gizmodo.com/5804720/broken-lens-horror-stories&quot;&gt;horrifying stories&lt;/a&gt; about equipment damage.  It brought to my attention &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.borrowlenses.com/&quot;&gt;www.borrow-lenses.com&lt;/a&gt;, which I have every intention of using sometime in near future.  Remember - always take care of your camera equipment!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fly Me To The Moon</title>
      <link>http://www.gorilla-studios.com/2011/03/18/fly-me-to-the-moon</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Mar 2011 22:41:27 -0500</pubDate>
      <author>chris@gorilla-studios.com (Chris Peak)</author>
      <guid>http://www.gorilla-studios.com/2011/03/18/fly-me-to-the-moon</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/fly_me_to_the_moon.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Super Moon shot&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>100 Days In Glacier National Park</title>
      <link>http://www.gorilla-studios.com/2009/12/02/100-days-in-glacier-national-park</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Dec 2009 14:25:25 -0600</pubDate>
      <author>chris@gorilla-studios.com (Chris Peak)</author>
      <guid>http://www.gorilla-studios.com/2009/12/02/100-days-in-glacier-national-park</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.glacierparkmagazine.com/100_days_in_Glacier_National_Park/100daysinGlacierNationalPark.html&quot;&gt;A beautiful photo set from a photographer who spent 100 days in Glacier National Park.&lt;/a&gt;  This is definitely is kindling my long lost love of photography.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pixar's Brad Bird On Fostering Innovation</title>
      <link>http://www.gorilla-studios.com/2009/09/29/pixars-brad-bird-on-fostering-innovation</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Sep 2009 12:49:26 -0500</pubDate>
      <author>chris@gorilla-studios.com (Chris Peak)</author>
      <guid>http://www.gorilla-studios.com/2009/09/29/pixars-brad-bird-on-fostering-innovation</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://gigaom.com/2008/04/17/pixars-brad-bird-on-fostering-innovation/&quot;&gt;An article from 2008 with Brad Bird&lt;/a&gt;, director of &lt;em&gt;The Incredibles&lt;/em&gt; on fostering innovation and Pixar&#39;s company culture.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have read and re-read this article many many times and I hope I am privileged enough to work with people like him.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Adam Savage On The Value Of Failing</title>
      <link>http://www.gorilla-studios.com/2009/07/06/adam-savage-on-the-value-of-failing</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jul 2009 20:27:22 -0500</pubDate>
      <author>chris@gorilla-studios.com (Chris Peak)</author>
      <guid>http://www.gorilla-studios.com/2009/07/06/adam-savage-on-the-value-of-failing</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://fora.tv/2009/05/30/MythBuster_Adam_Savages_Colossal_Failures&quot;&gt;GREAT talk at this years Makers Faire&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    

  </channel> 
</rss>
